<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General Education on Kevin&#39;s corner of the web</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/categories/general-education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General Education on Kevin&#39;s corner of the web</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 - Kevin Sauls</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/categories/general-education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How We Encourage Cheating in Education</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/how-we-encourage-cheating-in-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/how-we-encourage-cheating-in-education/</guid>
      <description>How We Encourage Cheating in Education I was watching a news report this morning about students using ChatGPT that asked whether this was considered cheating. That got me to thinking about how we encourage cheating in education..&#xA;Think about it: The purpose for education is to provide the student with the foundational knowledge they need to be successful in work and life. We all want to be successful, so cheating to get there doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to me to be a very profitable endeavor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Thoughts on Competency Based Education</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/my-thoughts-on-competency-based-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/my-thoughts-on-competency-based-education/</guid>
      <description>My Thoughts on Competency Based Education Competency based education has gathered quite a lot of steam over the last few years. Many universities now assert that they are competency based and promote this as somehow better than traditional education. In general, it seems that competency based education is a way of expediting the educational process whereby the student can move forward more quickly so long as the student can demonstrate competence in a subject.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Returning to Basics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/returning-to-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/returning-to-basics/</guid>
      <description>Returning to Basics The title of this blog is iamcuri.us. That title was chosen to reflect the many and sundry interests that I have and the drive I have to explore new ideas and to learn new things. While I think some of my posts here have reflected that, others seems to skew in specific directions that seem to narrow the focus on the blog. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m wrong. Maybe the posts that outline my tinkering in websites and self-hosting do reflect my questioning and exploring and learning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of an Academic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/he-evolution-of-an-academic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/he-evolution-of-an-academic/</guid>
      <description>The Evolution of an Academic Had someone told me on the day of my high school graduation in 1977 that I would one day be an academic, in possession of a doctoral degree and teaching at the university level, I&amp;rsquo;d have warned them that whatever they were smoking was muddling their brain. Yet, here I am, forty years later, in possession of not one, but two master&amp;rsquo;s degrees, and a doctorate, teaching at a university.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Progress ... Slowly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/making-progress-slowly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/making-progress-slowly/</guid>
      <description>Making Progress &amp;hellip; Slowly There has been a lot going on the last few months. I have been struggling to get my dissertation done. The biggest obstacle has been locating participants for a qualitative study. I finally got responses to my recruiting efforts and have been able to interview 7 people. That&amp;rsquo;s not a great response, but is better than nothing (which is what I had in the past!)&#xA;and allows me to move forward.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Education Relevant?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/is-education-relevant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/is-education-relevant/</guid>
      <description>Is Education Relevant One of the questions with which I have wrestled for a while now is the question of what it means to be ‘educated’. The problem, of course, is that there is no one definition and that, I think, creates much of the problem in evaluating educational programs. The state of Georgia recently put on the ballot a bill that would create an “Opportunity School District”. In an effort to address “failing” schools, the state proposed taking them over and doing whatever is necessary to ‘improve’ outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life Long Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/life-long-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/life-long-learning/</guid>
      <description>Life Long Learning One of the &amp;lsquo;goals&amp;rsquo; of the nursing department is that we develop &amp;rsquo;life long learners&amp;rsquo;. What this means, I suppose is up for some debate but I think, generally, that what is meant is that we prepare our students to learn how to identify their professional learning needs and help them develop the skills needed to meet those on-going needs. After all, health care is an ever-evolving field and constant learning is required.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing your Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/designing-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/designing-your-life/</guid>
      <description>Designing Your Life I &amp;lsquo;attended&amp;rsquo; a presentation by Story Musgrave, the astronaut, on &amp;ldquo;Designing your life&amp;rdquo; or some such similar topic. While I wasn&amp;rsquo;t overly impressed with his general rambling presentation style, I was very impressed with the message that threaded throughout his story. I took several keys away from the presentation.&#xA;The value of curiosity The first takeaway was the importance of curiosity in achieving an effective life. From high school drop out, he went on to earn a BS in math and statistics, MBA in operations analysis and computer programming, BA in chemistry, MD, and MS in physiology and biophysics within an 8 year period.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Social Filters Impact an Educated Response</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/how-social-filters-impact-an-educated-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/how-social-filters-impact-an-educated-response/</guid>
      <description>How Social Filters Impact an Educated Response One of the hallmarks of the well-educated person is, I think, the ability and willingness to explore all sides of an issue before making a decision. Unfortunately, it seems that few people, even those who are, in fact, well-educated, truly take the time to explore an issue before taking a stance on it. And, to a large extent, I get it. It’s hard to do.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The First Thing Every College Should Do For Its Students</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/the-first-thing-every-college-should-do-for-its-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/the-first-thing-every-college-should-do-for-its-students/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-first-thing-every-college-should-do-for-its-students&#34;&gt;The First Thing Every College Should Do For Its Students&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For some time now I’ve argued that colleges and universities have dropped the ball on one of the most important preparatory steps in attending college: Defining what a college education is all about.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Students often go to college without a clear conception of what they’re supposed to be getting from the experience.  They go because college has become the “thing you do” after high school.  Like their secondary education, they never really stop to think about why they’re going, or what the benefits are. More importantly, many students see college as simply an extension of their secondary education. That is, learning without an express purpose other than “I’ll need to know this someday.” &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of a Degree</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/the-meaning-of-a-degree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/the-meaning-of-a-degree/</guid>
      <description>The Meaning of a Degree The reasons why they may choose to do this are myriad. For some students, the BSN has long been a personal goal. For others, though, the decision isn’t internally motivated. Rather, they’re faced with either obtaining their BSN, or finding other employment. Now, for anyone outside of nursing, that latter reason might seem a bit harsh. But for those of us in the profession, it makes sense – at least to a degree.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technology For Its Own Sake</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/technology-for-its-own-sake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/technology-for-its-own-sake/</guid>
      <description>Technology For It&amp;rsquo;s Own Sake About eight years ago I spent a couple of years teaching high school. Being a nurse, and coming into the experience with no real educational background it was quite an interesting, and eye-opening experience. Needless to say, I probably learned more than my students did. One of the things that left me scratching my head was the approach the school system took toward education. Tons of money was spent on technology and teachers were required to have at least one “technology lesson” each week.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is it for Education or Business?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/is-it-for-education-or-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/is-it-for-education-or-business/</guid>
      <description>Is it for Education or Business? In the early 1990’s as I was preparing to wrap up my MBA I was informed by my advisor that I still needed to take a basic statistics course. Now, that would seem a reasonable expectation were it not for the fact that I had already completed two advanced statistics courses. Being a bit obstinate, I asked why it was necessary for me to take a course designed to prepare me for courses that I had already taken and passed (quite well, I might add.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Education &#34;All That&#34;?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/is-education-all-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/is-education-all-that/</guid>
      <description>Is Education &amp;ldquo;All That&amp;rdquo; I had a wonderful opportunity to talk with a woman(we’ll call her Jane) who has accomplished several things that I have only dreamed of. She has developed a new approach to an old and vexing problem many nurses face, she contributed to the development of a new medical device, she has been published in peer-reviewed journals, and has spoken around the world before thousands of people to introduce other professionals to both her new technique and to the medical device.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The State of the MOOC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/the-state-of-the-mooc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/the-state-of-the-mooc/</guid>
      <description>The State of the MOOC Two recent articles about Massive Open Online Courses (MOOC) got my attention this week.&#xA;Fail? The first article brings to the fore the reality that only about 7% of those who start a MOOC course complete it. This is, of course, a major concern for educators, given that completion rates are the major metric for colleges. It is completely understandable that many would see that number and conclude that MOOCs are failing.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
