<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General Education on Kevin&#39;s Corner of the Web</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/general-education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General Education on Kevin&#39;s Corner of the Web</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/general-education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How We Encourage Cheating in Education</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-we-encourage-cheating-in-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-we-encourage-cheating-in-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-we-encourage-cheating-in-education&#34;&gt;How We Encourage Cheating in Education&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was watching a news report this morning about students using ChatGPT that asked whether this was considered cheating.  That got me to thinking about how we encourage cheating in education..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about it:  The purpose for education is to provide the student with the foundational knowledge they &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;need to be successful in work and life.  We all want to be successful, so cheating to get there doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to me to be a very profitable endeavor.  After all, at the end of the day you still have to know how to do things in order to be successful.  I used to remind my nursing students of this all the time: If you want to be a good nurse you&amp;rsquo;re going to need to actually &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; what you&amp;rsquo;re doing.  Cheating might get you through the class, it might even allow you to pass the licensing exam but the real test is whether you can function in the real world.  It&amp;rsquo;s a hell of a lot less stressful to actually know what you&amp;rsquo;re doing when in an emergency than to try to wing it because you lack the knowledge to actually perform correctly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-we-encourage-cheating-in-education&#34;&gt;How We Encourage Cheating in Education&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was watching a news report this morning about students using ChatGPT that asked whether this was considered cheating.  That got me to thinking about how we encourage cheating in education..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about it:  The purpose for education is to provide the student with the foundational knowledge they &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;need to be successful in work and life.  We all want to be successful, so cheating to get there doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to me to be a very profitable endeavor.  After all, at the end of the day you still have to know how to do things in order to be successful.  I used to remind my nursing students of this all the time: If you want to be a good nurse you&amp;rsquo;re going to need to actually &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; what you&amp;rsquo;re doing.  Cheating might get you through the class, it might even allow you to pass the licensing exam but the real test is whether you can function in the real world.  It&amp;rsquo;s a hell of a lot less stressful to actually know what you&amp;rsquo;re doing when in an emergency than to try to wing it because you lack the knowledge to actually perform correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-we-cheat&#34;&gt;Why We Cheat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My experience, after twenty years of teaching, is that the reason  we cheat is that we want to get a good grade and pass the class, but we don&amp;rsquo;t want to do the actual work needed to earn that good grade.  Student&amp;rsquo;s rarely understand the purpose of education.  For them going to class, reading, studying and so on are simply obstacles to becoming an adult or, if they&amp;rsquo;re in college, obstacles to becoming a teacher, engineer, doctor, or whatever it is they want to be when they graduate.  We look for shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why do we cheat to get good grades?  The simple reason is that schools (and parents) focus on grades rather than learning.  There is an assumption that grades reflect the level of learning the student has achieved and, in an ideal world, this is at least partly true&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Unfortunately, we put so much emphasis on grades that the relationship between what the student learns and what the grade reflects has been lost.  (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gocomics.com/fminus/2024/04/20?ct=v&amp;amp;cti=1968939&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; a great comic strip that sums this all up quite well!) Some students are quite adept at test-taking and can pass an exam even with little or no knowledge of the content.  Add a bit of cheating into the mix and students can complete a course while taking nothing from it.  That&amp;rsquo;s pretty damn sad in my view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, grades are often used as measures of the quality of instruction.  That is, the teacher is rated based on the number of students who pass the course.  Some years ago I had an anatomy and physiology teacher who tended to give students the test questions or answers prior to the test so that the students would be successful on the exams.  The problem, of course, is that when they got to my class where they needed to apply the knowledge they were expected to have brought from that class they struggled.  Rather than realize that the A&amp;amp;P teacher failed them, the students blamed me for demanding that they know the information.  Sorry &amp;ndash; if you&amp;rsquo;re going to take care of cardiac patients, you need to know how the heart works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, because students didn&amp;rsquo;t do well in my class I was reviewed as an ineffective instructor rather than the victim of an incompetent prior instructor.  It never seemed to occur to my higher-ups that my class depended on knowledge provided by a prerequisite course.  If that course failed the student, that negatively affected me.  (We won&amp;rsquo;t get into how that whole process reeks of a lack of critical thinking on the part of the manager.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-how-do-we-fix-this&#34;&gt;So, How Do We Fix This?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an ideal world, we would, first, do away with grading.  Rather, we would work to determine whether or not the student understands the concepts that are being taught, identify the areas where they are still struggling then work to ensure that those areas are properly addressed so that the student does, in fact, master the concepts.  Grading really accomplishes nothing except to demoralize the student who is struggling. It reinforces the notion that the student cannot achieve success.  It also establishes a &amp;ldquo;pecking order&amp;rdquo; both for the teacher and for students.  With grades, the goals becomes the grade rather than mastery of the material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the reality is that this approach is not practical when working with large numbers of students.  It also would not be accepted by legislators because they would no longer have something to complain about. After all, if all students actually achieved their goals, that would show that the educational system is working, which is anathema to politicians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another issue is how to go about determining if the student understands the concepts.  In fact, there are multiple ways to accomplish this though designing and implementing those approaches may prove daunting in a larger classroom.  Some schools use peer grading where students evaluate each other&amp;rsquo;s work for quality, etc.  Evaluating the same content using multiple approaches helps to tease out those areas where the student has on-going weaknesses so that they can be addressed.  Oral exams, rather than written tests, may allow the student to more fully express their understanding of the content.  Allowing the student to describe or apply &amp;rsquo;every thing they know about&amp;rsquo; a topic may help identify what is important to the student and what their actual level of understanding is.  Remember that when teachers write a test they are identifying what &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; believe is important, not what the student feels is most important.  This approach, in particular, allows the student to apply their understanding to their specific situation and may actually provide the teacher new insights into the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other approaches, such as standards based testing, equity grading, and so on that have the potential to improve education and achieve the true goal of education &amp;ndash; learning.  Unfortunately, too many people cling to the old ways because &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rsquo;s the way it&amp;rsquo;s always been done.&amp;rdquo;  Then complain because it isn&amp;rsquo;t working. And until &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; problem is resolved nothing will change and cheating will continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No test or paper can truly reflect what a student knows and understands about a topic.  Testing and papers and other means of &amp;lsquo;grading&amp;rsquo; give approximations of that knowledge.  Tests are often written to reflect what the teacher believes to be most important.  The student, meanwhile, may have learned something entirely different but which is more important to them than what the teacher believes to be important.  Education is ultimately, I believe, about what meets the student&amp;rsquo;s needs rather than what an arbitrary external resources believes is important.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thoughts on Competency Based Education</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-thoughts-on-competency-based-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-thoughts-on-competency-based-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-thoughts-on-competency-based-education&#34;&gt;My Thoughts on Competency Based Education&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competency based education has gathered quite a lot of steam over the last few years.  Many universities now assert that they are competency based and promote this as somehow better than traditional education.  In general, it seems that competency based education is a way of expediting the educational process whereby the student can move forward more quickly so long as the student can demonstrate competence in a subject.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-thoughts-on-competency-based-education&#34;&gt;My Thoughts on Competency Based Education&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competency based education has gathered quite a lot of steam over the last few years.  Many universities now assert that they are competency based and promote this as somehow better than traditional education.  In general, it seems that competency based education is a way of expediting the educational process whereby the student can move forward more quickly so long as the student can demonstrate competence in a subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, education was concerned with &amp;lsquo;seat time&amp;rsquo;. A correlation was assumed (though I don&amp;rsquo;t think ever validated) &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; between the amount of time the student spent studying and sitting in classes and their success in learning.  Success, of course, was determined by taking multiple-guess tests, writing papers, etc.  What this approach did not take into account, particularly for older students, is what the student brings to the table.  The classic example of this is the IT student who, through years of personal study and hobby practice, has become proficient in coding programs.  Requiring this student to sit through basic programming courses which teach skills the student mastered long ago is clearly unnecessary. The &amp;ldquo;system&amp;rdquo;, however, did not take these students into account and there was rarely a means for the student to test out of the course by demonstrating that they had already mastered the material. (From my own experience, while completing my MBA I was required to take an introductory statistics course despite having already passed advanced statistics and quantitative methods!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competency based education is designed to allow the student to &amp;rsquo;test out&amp;rsquo; of a course by demonstrating that they already possess the skills and knowledge the course was designed to teach. The ideal situation is that the student who lacks the skills or knowledge taught in a particular course is able to go through the course and develop those skills or obtain that knowledge. Meanwhile, the student who already possesses the skills and knowledge is able to move on to the next course which may teach content with which they are unfamiliar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sounds-great-so-whats-the-issue&#34;&gt;Sounds great! So, What&amp;rsquo;s the Issue?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several concerns I have with competency based education and, specifically, how it is promoted and administered by many schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, what do we mean by &amp;ldquo;competent&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years ago I undertook an intensive program that crammed two years of IT into six months. By and large there were few tests.  Our progress was determined by our ability to accomplish the tasks we were assigned to complete. For example, in a one month course we learned to program in C and Perl.  The instructor determined whether we passed based on whether: a) the program ran; and, b) the program did what it was expected to do. Whether the code was written cleanly or was efficient didn&amp;rsquo;t matter; if it ran and did what it was intended to do, we were considered competent in programming in that language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, a pilot is considered competent if she can consistently get the plane aloft, fly to the intended destination, and land the plane in one piece.  A doctor may be considered competent if he can consistently arrive at a valid diagnosis, prescribe relevant treatment, and obtain a positive patient outcome. A surgeon might be considered competent if she can consistently perform the procedure without causing undue harm to the patient and, again, obtain an overall positive outcome.  Whether any of these professionals follow appropriate practices, achieve their outcomes efficiently and effectively, or not is not really a consideration. They are competent if they achieved the intended outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning to the classroom, if you ask the faculty of most schools to define &amp;ldquo;competence&amp;rdquo; they will most likely struggle to do so or provide various different definitions. Students bring their own definitions and understanding to the table, often situating their definition in a way that lightens their burden of study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therein lies the first concern:  What do we mean by competent and how do we determine it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the first issue is simply clearly defining what one means by &amp;ldquo;competent&amp;rdquo; and ensuring that everyone &amp;ndash; all faculty and students &amp;ndash; share that one clear meaning.  It may be different for different schools, but everyone within the same institution should have the same understanding of its meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dictionary.com&lt;/em&gt; defines competence as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;having suitable or sufficient skill, knowledge, experience, etc., for some purpose; properly qualified: He is perfectly competent to manage the bank branch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adequate but not exceptional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we determine whether a student has sufficient skill, knowledge, experience, etc?  Would you consider a surgeon who has demonstrated one successful heart surgery competent?  Would you allow them to operate on you (without a more highly experienced doctor in attendance)?  I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t.  I would want to know that the the surgeon has successfully performed multiple heart surgeries before I&amp;rsquo;d allow them to operate on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skills and knowledge are not interchangeable. I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;ve worked alongside people who had great &amp;ldquo;book knowledge&amp;rdquo; but couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out which end of the screwdriver to hold. Being able to pass a multiple choice test (which basically means they can identify the correct answer when they see it) demonstrates neither sufficient skill nor knowledge of the subject.  At the very least, the student should be required to pass multiple tests, preferably of different forms (written, oral, etc). Yet some schools rely on a single exam to determine that a student is competent in a subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the examples provided earlier really describe what I would consider to be a minimal level of competence. Yes, each of those examples may have achieved an intended outcome, but they may also have skipped important steps, kludged fixes for errors that popped up, and so on.  They may not follow best practices and, as a result, may actually produce an inferior product. Yes, it works but does it work well and efficiently?  Well-written computer programs, for example, have very few, if any, unnecessary lines of code, contains clear documentation of what each line of code or block of code is intended to accomplish, and compile into efficient programs.  In the examples above, the best you might hope for is &amp;ldquo;adequate&amp;rdquo;.  Again, do you want someone who does an adequate job, or one that does an exceptional job.  If I&amp;rsquo;m a hiring agency, I&amp;rsquo;ll generally choose the second option because it will end up costing me less in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second issue is ensuring that students are actually demonstrating competence through multiple assessments using different modalities.  It&amp;rsquo;s simply too easy for a student to &amp;lsquo;get lucky&amp;rsquo; in passing a single exam. And, particularly with online schools the test questions and answers, other students&amp;rsquo; papers, and so on are available online so students may actually pass a course but take away absolutely no knowledge of the course content. (That&amp;rsquo;s actually a travesty because the student is not getting what they&amp;rsquo;re paying for, but it is their decisions to short-change them.). Multiple assessments, using multiple modalities &amp;ndash; including hands-on demonstrations &amp;ndash; helps to ensure that the student actually is competent in the content and didn&amp;rsquo;t just get lucky on their assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third issue, in my view, is that while some students truly are competent in the content and are able to demonstrate their competence satisfactorily, many are not.  However, because of the marketing schools do for their programs, many students believe that competency based education and the potential for accelerating their progress means that they don&amp;rsquo;t need to take the time actually learn the content. They just want to take the test and move on.  They fail to understand that it is important to focus on the areas where they are not competent so that they become competent in those areas and, therefore, are fully prepared for the professional role they are pursuing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-is-competency-based-education-a-bad-idea&#34;&gt;So is Competency-Based Education a Bad Idea?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me be clear: I believe in competency based learning because I believe, when properly administered, competency-based learning ensures that the student possesses all of the skills and knowledge needed to be successful in their chosen field. In fact, properly administered, I believe competency based education may be superior to our traditional educational model because the student has the opportunity to identify areas of weakness, work to strengthen those areas, then prove their competence.  In other words, competency based education, again properly administered, can be expected to provide more graduates who each possess a greater set of skills and knowledge than a traditional classroom because the student must demonstrate competence before continuing on, unlike tradtional schools where, even if the student fails a test, they continue on to the next topic or class. (I have a post planned that explores the grading system.) I believe it also allows the student who brings appropriate knowledge, skills, and experience to the table to bypass courses which are redundant for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To achieve that goal, though, requires that schools be clear in their definitions, consistent in their application of those definitions, and rigorous in their determination of competence to ensure that the students are truly prepared for their professional roles. Competency-based assessment is hard.  It requires the development of specific, demanding assessments of varied types (oral, written, hands-on, etc) in order to ensure that the student is truly competent. It also requires that schools routinely, and frequently, update their assessments to prevent students from accessing other students&amp;rsquo; work and suggestions which might allow the student to pass the course without actually engaging the course materials and without any real knowledge of the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, I think too few schools are willing to invest that much effort into the process and, as a result, turn out students who are only marginally competent (if at all).  These student may, at best, meet that second definition of competence: adequate, but not exceptional.  I don&amp;rsquo;t understand why anyone who wants to be successful in their career would settle for being adequate when they have the potential be be exceptional.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Returning to Basics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/returning-to-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/returning-to-basics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;returning-to-basics&#34;&gt;Returning to Basics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title of this blog is iamcuri.us.  That title was chosen to reflect the many and sundry interests that I have and the drive I have to explore new ideas and to learn new things.  While I think some of my posts here have reflected that, others seems to skew in specific directions that seem to narrow the focus on the blog.  Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m wrong.  Maybe the posts that outline my tinkering in websites and self-hosting do reflect my questioning and exploring and learning. Still, I think that it&amp;rsquo;s time I pushed into some new areas a&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;nd revisit in more detail some old areas, too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;returning-to-basics&#34;&gt;Returning to Basics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title of this blog is iamcuri.us.  That title was chosen to reflect the many and sundry interests that I have and the drive I have to explore new ideas and to learn new things.  While I think some of my posts here have reflected that, others seems to skew in specific directions that seem to narrow the focus on the blog.  Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m wrong.  Maybe the posts that outline my tinkering in websites and self-hosting do reflect my questioning and exploring and learning. Still, I think that it&amp;rsquo;s time I pushed into some new areas a&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;nd revisit in more detail some old areas, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;philosopy&#34;&gt;Philosopy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first real introduction to philosophy was through my doctoral program.  In fact, the introduction to the topic was a bit abrupt and jarring.  The very first class in my doctoral program was in the philosophy of science course. To say it was bewildering was an understatement.  The lectures were interesting, though I can&amp;rsquo;t say that I understood a great deal of them.  The readings, likewise, were challenging. Still, I persisted and managed to do fairly well in the course, even while feeling I had no idea what it was all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a couple of years and I became interested in the concepts of critical thinking.  Now, thinking is a core aspect of philosophy so if I was to gain any understanding of critical thinking I realized I would need to get a better handle on philosophy.  In fits and starts I&amp;rsquo;ve been adding to my understanding by reading, somewhat haphazardly, the writings of various philosophers, notably the ancient ones such as Plato, Aristotle, and the like but also some more recent ones such as Kuhn, Popper, and Watts.  But my approach was disjointed and I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like I was building the proper foundation.  What I needed was a structured approach to learning more about philosophy.  But, where to start? What are the best first readings?  How do I layer my learning so that I build on prior learning without jumping into the deep end of the pool and feeling totally lost?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;ve found a way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;physics&#34;&gt;Physics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve expanded my reading on a variety of topics over the last several years, one topic that keeps coming up in various ways is that of physics.  I know nothing of physics, though I do find the articles I&amp;rsquo;ve read on topics related to physics interesting and I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself wanting to know more.  As with philosophy, though, the question was where to begin.  Physics is a huge and confusing field.  Would a &amp;ldquo;dummies&amp;rdquo; book benefit me?  I didn&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, while reading &lt;em&gt;The Structure of Science&lt;/em&gt; by Thomas Kuhn.  Kuhn was a physicist by training who stumbled into the history of science and later into the philosphy of science. That transition actually made sense to me.  But, in reading that essay I was struck by the broad range of topics in which Kuhn seemed to be conversant. Ponder this, of course, I realized that his background in the history of science required him to understand the basics of the broad range of concepts that constitute &amp;ldquo;science&amp;rdquo;. I also realized that his background in physics seemed to provide him a particularly sound starting point for mastering these other topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve set my cap to learning a bit more about physics (In fact, I did this about four years ago but never acted on it.)  How to begin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-path-forward&#34;&gt;A Path Forward&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While searching for some hints on how to begin teaching myself physics, quite by accident I ran across an article by Susan Fleming entitled, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.susanjfowler.com/blog/2016/8/26/from-the-fledgling-physicist-archives-if-susan-can-learn-physics-so-can-you%22&#34;&gt;If Susan Can Learn Physics, So Can You&lt;/a&gt;.  This blog post laid out, step-by-step, a course of study that reflected a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in physics.  Now, I really don&amp;rsquo;t care to get &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; deep into it (or maybe I do), but at least she gave me a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, as they say on TV, &amp;ldquo;But Wait!  There&amp;rsquo;s More!&amp;rdquo;  Ms. Fleming is now Mrs. Rigetti and she has changed her website, but provided follow up post for a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in philosopy entitled, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.susanrigetti.com/philosophy&#34;&gt;So You Want to Learn Philosopy &amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;.  She was the answer to my dreams!  How did it come to be that she was able to do this?  I briefly read her bio and it seems she was a philosphy major who, with no prior experience in physics and little mathematical background, was cajoled by college advisor to take physics as an elective.  I&amp;rsquo;ll let you follow the two links to her sites to get the lowdown on her path to two majors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-road-map&#34;&gt;The Road Map&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, now I have two paths to follow.  How to proceed.  My plan, perhaps foolish as it might be, is to begin with philosophy. I intend to follow, as closely as possible the curriculum she has laid out for that domain.  I figure two years to get through it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, because I&amp;rsquo;m really a glutton for punishment, I&amp;rsquo;ll tackle the physics curriculum.  That&amp;rsquo;s at least another two years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let&amp;rsquo;s be honest about something: I have no intentions of ever using the knowledge gained for anything other than self edification.  I do not aspire to by a &amp;lsquo;Philosopher&amp;rsquo; (though I suspect most everyone becomes one at some point in time) and I certainly do not expect to make a career or even get a job in physics.  But, having the knowledge, being able to understand just a little better some of the topics that seem so esoteric to me, at the moment seems worth the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of an Academic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/he-evolution-of-an-academic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/he-evolution-of-an-academic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-evolution-of-an-academic&#34;&gt;The Evolution of an Academic&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had someone told me on the day of my high school graduation in 1977 that I would one day be an academic, in possession of a doctoral degree and teaching at the university level, I&amp;rsquo;d have warned them that whatever&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; they were smoking was muddling their brain. Yet, here I am, forty years later, in possession of not one, but two master&amp;rsquo;s degrees, and a doctorate, teaching at a university.  How did that happen?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-evolution-of-an-academic&#34;&gt;The Evolution of an Academic&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had someone told me on the day of my high school graduation in 1977 that I would one day be an academic, in possession of a doctoral degree and teaching at the university level, I&amp;rsquo;d have warned them that whatever&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; they were smoking was muddling their brain. Yet, here I am, forty years later, in possession of not one, but two master&amp;rsquo;s degrees, and a doctorate, teaching at a university.  How did that happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-wasnt-planned&#34;&gt;It Wasn&amp;rsquo;t Planned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never planned to go to college.  As a high school student, I hated school.  It wasn&amp;rsquo;t so much that I disliked learning. Rather, it was that I disliked the structure and rigidity of the scholastic environment.  I was, and am, curious (hence the title of this blog). I loved learning about things that caught my interest.  As a teen I became interested in solar power and, to this day, I can tell you that the proper angle for a solar panel is latitude plus or minus 15 degrees, depending on the season. I learned that tidbit of information somewhere around age 17 and it has never left me. And, I&amp;rsquo;ve always read on a variety of topics.  Even as a elementary school student I was interested in topics such as psychology and anthropology, pondering on why cultures were different, for example, and read on those topics&amp;ndash; at least as well as a fifth grader could!  But I hated the imposed structure of learning that schooling provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time I was graduating from high school I was done. No more school for me!  So, I went to work.  Now, it&amp;rsquo;s important to recognize that in the mid-1970&amp;rsquo;s a college education was nice to have but wasn&amp;rsquo;t necessary for most jobs.  Someone could easily get a wide variety of jobs that paid a decent wage, allowing a relatively good middle-class living, without having attended college.  But things were changing.  After a year of working, I realized that the really well-paying jobs required an associate degree.  So, off to the community college I went. I had no idea what I wanted to do. So, like so many others, I chose a business admin major.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After blundering through a few business courses, however, I realized that the topic didn&amp;rsquo;t hold much interest to me so I started digging around.  I learned about this intriguing career called a Physician&amp;rsquo;s Assistant (PA).  I shifted my focus a bit and found a job as an orderly in the local hospital to help me decide if healthcare was appealing to me. I talked to a couple of PAs who, to my dismay, presented a less than rosey picture of the future of the PA. They were wrong, by the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the PA picture was looking rather bleak, I also met and worked with a number of men who were nurses. When I had been working in a small local grocer, the owner&amp;rsquo;s wife was working on her degree in nursing and suggested that I consider that.  I thought she was nuts; nursing was for women.  But, having met and worked with several men in nursing, and having gotten their whole-hearted endorsements of the field as appropriate for men, I thought, &amp;ldquo;why not?&amp;rdquo;  I changed my major and off I went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to say here that in making that choice I found that my grades improved.  Having a clearly defined goal certainly helped me to focus my energies toward my studies.  I took, and passed with good grades, all of the biological studies the community college offered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having already earned the hours for an associates degree, it made little sense to spend another two years getting an AD in nursing, so I chose, instead, to pursue a BSN.  I applied to, and was accepted, into a BSN program.  I can&amp;rsquo;t say it was always a pleasant two years, but at least I had a focus and was successful in my studies.  And by 1983 I was a full-fledged licensed, RN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-next-stagse&#34;&gt;The Next Stagse&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing my degree and passing the licensing exam I went to work in a Coronary Care Unit.  I generally like the work and soon found that I wanted more.  In this case, I thought that I wanted to move into administration.  To that end, I began work on a Masters in Business Administration and by 1992, and two schools later, I had acheived that goal. I went to work as an administrator in home health.  And hated it.  It didn&amp;rsquo;t take me long to realize that my personality didn&amp;rsquo;t suit the world of management well.  Still, I persisted in working in healthcare, returning to my roots as an RN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the realization that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t great management material, there were still areas within management that intrigued me and I found myself drawn to reading and studying those topics. I had begun my studies in the mid-1980s &amp;ndash; just when computers were really beginning to show up in the workplace. They definitely piqued my curiosity and soon I was off playing with computers, learning how to program and how the darn things worked.  This fit into my general curiosity of all things technical.  I loved computers and exploring all the things you could do with them.  I still do, by the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the 1990s I returned to school again, first for a masters in nursing (with the notion of becoming a nurse practitioner) and later as a masters in information systems (to answer my interest in computers). Both of those pursuits were derailed by social and family issues that got in the way of my studies and prevented me from completing.  For the MSN, in particular, a fading interest in becoming an NP was also a factor.  It always saddened me that I never completed the MIS degree (even though I possess now much of the knowledge and skills that the degree would have provided me.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through out this time, I continued to read and study in a variety of topic areas.  I remained an avid reader of both fiction and non-fiction.  It was rare that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have some book at hand, and visits to bookstores were a weekly occurrence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;transition-to-teaching&#34;&gt;Transition to Teaching&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While working at a small hospital, I had the opportunity to take on the role of nurse educator for the facilty. I found not only that I enjoyed the work but that I apparently had a penchant for communicating concepts in a clear and concise manner.  I was a good teacher.  That experience, and the realization that it engendered, led me to explore the possiblity of teaching in an academic setting.  I applied for, and was accepted, as an instructor in an LPN program.  This I did for for nearly 10 years, with a two year interlude in which I taught health science in a high school (that experienced confirmed for me that secondary education was NOT a viable option for me!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed teaching LPN students.  As I continued in that role, I found that my perspective on teaching and learning about nursing was changing.  I also found that I was more introspective. I gave thought to how I taught. I sought out information on how to teach more effectively and efficiently.  My approaches evolved from the &amp;ldquo;sage on the stagse&amp;rdquo; approach that I had grown up with, to a more interactive approach.  And, I became more aware of the value of education beyond simple career training.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t just want to teach students how to do the job, I wanted to teach them how to think.  I had begun to realize that the more knowledge you have, the better able you are to make sense of your life, to make better and more informed decisions.  Limiting yourself to knowledge only within the work domain limits your ability to grow and find value as a person.  I came to realize that I wanted to teach at a higher level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To teach beyond the LPN level, however, requires a masters degree or higher.  So, back to school I went.  Nearing completion of my MSN, I decided that a doctorate would open more doors. Not only did it open more doors for me, the doctorate also opened my eyes and mind to new ways of thinking.  The experience profoundly affected my sense of self and how I view my world.  Through my doctoral work I began to realize just how limited my own worldview had been.  I began to read even more widely and more deeply on a range of subjects.  I began to think about how critical the skills of thinking and reading were to success not only in nursing, but in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common complaint of my students, most of whom are practicing RNs who are being forced back to school for their BSN by their employers, is that they don&amp;rsquo;t see how the BSN helps them to become a better nurse.  I can answer that now.  How can adding more knowledge, regardless of the type of knowledge, not help you be more effective in working with others?  How can knowledge not help you to see connections between ideas and experiences?  How can knowledge of disparate concepts not help you to develop your own ideas more fully?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here I am. A teacher &amp;ndash; an academic. Even, perhaps, a bit of a scholar. This is not where I expected life to take me, but here is where I have found a sense of fulfillment. Mihaly Csikcszentmihaly, in his book &lt;em&gt;Flow: The Psychology of Optimal Experience&lt;/em&gt; describes the sense of oneness one feels when things are as they should be in life.  I think, in becoming an academic, I have found my flow.  I have found my purpose in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boy, am I surprised!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Progress ... Slowly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/making-progress-slowly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/making-progress-slowly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;making-progress--slowly&#34;&gt;Making Progress &amp;hellip; Slowly&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been a lot going on the last few months.  I have been struggling to
get my dissertation done. The biggest obstacle has been locating participants
for a qualitative study.  I &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; got responses to my recruiting efforts and
have been able to interview 7 people.  That&amp;rsquo;s not a great response, but is
better than nothing (which is what I had in the past!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and allows me to move
forward.  Did I say I was excited?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;making-progress--slowly&#34;&gt;Making Progress &amp;hellip; Slowly&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been a lot going on the last few months.  I have been struggling to
get my dissertation done. The biggest obstacle has been locating participants
for a qualitative study.  I &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; got responses to my recruiting efforts and
have been able to interview 7 people.  That&amp;rsquo;s not a great response, but is
better than nothing (which is what I had in the past!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and allows me to move
forward.  Did I say I was excited?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having finally gotten the data collected, themed, coded, and all the other
things you do to qualitative data, I finally sat down to write.  For the past
four and a half
days that&amp;rsquo;s pretty much all I&amp;rsquo;ve done: write.  yes, I have literally been
writing 8 - 10 hours a day for the past nearly 5 days.  And I&amp;rsquo;m not done.  I&amp;rsquo;m
getting close, mind you, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t crossed the finish line.  I hope to do
that soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Education Relevant?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/is-education-relevant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/is-education-relevant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;is-education-relevant&#34;&gt;Is Education Relevant&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the questions with which I have wrestled for a while now is the question of what it means to be ‘educated’.  The problem, of course, is that there is no one definition and that, I think, creates much of the problem in evaluating educational programs.  The state of Georgia recently put on the ballot a bill that would create an “Opportunity School District”. In an effort to address “failing” schools, the state proposed taking them over and doing whatever is necessary to ‘improve’ outcomes.  As I pondered the proposal, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; one of the questions that I continually confronted was what does it mean for school to “fail”? Who determines this? And, on what is it based?  Advertisements for the plan suggested that “only 12% of third graders in our failings schools are reading on grade-level.” That, of course, raised other questions for me.  For example, how does this compare to third graders in those schools that are not considered to be failing? What does it mean to read on grade level?  Recognizing that people learn at different rates and that skills such as reading are commonly dependent on external factors such as how much reading goes on in the home, is the standard even appropriate? These and several other questions brought me back around to the question of what it means to be educated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;is-education-relevant&#34;&gt;Is Education Relevant&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the questions with which I have wrestled for a while now is the question of what it means to be ‘educated’.  The problem, of course, is that there is no one definition and that, I think, creates much of the problem in evaluating educational programs.  The state of Georgia recently put on the ballot a bill that would create an “Opportunity School District”. In an effort to address “failing” schools, the state proposed taking them over and doing whatever is necessary to ‘improve’ outcomes.  As I pondered the proposal, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; one of the questions that I continually confronted was what does it mean for school to “fail”? Who determines this? And, on what is it based?  Advertisements for the plan suggested that “only 12% of third graders in our failings schools are reading on grade-level.” That, of course, raised other questions for me.  For example, how does this compare to third graders in those schools that are not considered to be failing? What does it mean to read on grade level?  Recognizing that people learn at different rates and that skills such as reading are commonly dependent on external factors such as how much reading goes on in the home, is the standard even appropriate? These and several other questions brought me back around to the question of what it means to be educated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know that schools are generally managed at the local level in order to meet the needs of the particular community.  We know, for example, that students in predominantly rural areas have different experiences, values, needs, and interests than students living in urban areas. Those different values, experiences, needs, and interests necessarily create a different set of learning needs.  I currently live in a predominantly rural area where many, if not most, students will grow up to work in agriculture. Their parents are not highly educated and their likely career path does not require a high level of education. Consequently, once the student has mastered the basic of reading, writing, and math they’re probably pretty much ready for their world.  In contrast, the urban child’s parents may be more highly educated and their environment offers more in terms of potential career choices.  Basic skills of reading, writing, and math may not be sufficient to meet their future needs.  Relevance of what is being taught to the career paths most open to them are vastly different. Shouldn’t their educational expectations be different also?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, is the Georgia’s proposal reasonable? Or, are we trying to fit everyone into the same box, ignoring differences in community values and needs in order to meet some nebulous (and dare I say suspect) ‘standard’ that has no foundation in fact?  Does it matter whether the child at age 8 can read at a specific level? Or, does it matter more that he is continuing to develop reading skills?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, this post doesn’t really get to the topic of being “educated” as the first sentence suggests, but it lays a foundation for future conversations that will address this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you’re reading, bear in mind that I do not put my thoughts here as definitive, but as exploratory.  I am still learning, thinking, and trying to understand. I write here to share that journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Long Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/life-long-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/life-long-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;life-long-learning&#34;&gt;Life Long Learning&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the &amp;lsquo;goals&amp;rsquo; of the nursing department is that we develop &amp;rsquo;life long
learners&amp;rsquo;.  What this means, I suppose is up for some debate but I think,
generally, that what is meant is that we prepare our students to learn how to
identify their professional learning needs and help them develop the skills
needed to meet those on-going needs.  After all, health care is an ever-evolving
field and constant learning is required. As I have pointed out to my students
for many years, many of the diseases that we deal with today were not identified&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;life-long-learning&#34;&gt;Life Long Learning&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the &amp;lsquo;goals&amp;rsquo; of the nursing department is that we develop &amp;rsquo;life long
learners&amp;rsquo;.  What this means, I suppose is up for some debate but I think,
generally, that what is meant is that we prepare our students to learn how to
identify their professional learning needs and help them develop the skills
needed to meet those on-going needs.  After all, health care is an ever-evolving
field and constant learning is required. As I have pointed out to my students
for many years, many of the diseases that we deal with today were not identified&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;when I was in school. Nor were many of the procedures that are routinely
conducted today.  So, if the professional is to remain a professional he or she
is required to constantly learn new information about those diseases,
procedures, and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To aim to prepare our students to continue to learn is, clearly, an important
goal.  But, as I think about it, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that it&amp;rsquo;s the right goal.  I was
watching a TED talk by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/ben_dunlap_talks_about_a_passionate_life&#34;&gt;Dr. Bernie Dunlap&lt;/a&gt;
the president of Wofford College in South Carolina, a few days ago and after a 20 minute talk on the influence of
various Hungarians on his life, he got to the real point of his talk.  He was
chronicling the interaction over dinner at his home between Dr. Francis
Robicsek, a cardiovascular surgeon and collector of french art and Mayan art and
Roger Milliken, CEO of Milliken &amp;amp; Company about, of all things, a Harry Potter
movie.  The crux of the story was that the two were arguing over whether the
second Harry Potter movie was as good as the first.  That these two titans
should be discussing, much less arguing, over such a mundane thing seems
unfathomable.  In his winning stroke, Dr. Robiscek said, &amp;ldquo;I bet you went to the
movie with a child&amp;rdquo; to which Milliken replied that he did.  Robiscek closes in
for the kill: &amp;ldquo;Ah-hah!  I went all by myself!&amp;rdquo;  In that moment, says Dunlap he
realized the essence of life-long learning.  It was, he says, that &amp;ldquo;insatiable
curiosity, that irrepressible desire to know, no matter what the subject, no
matter what the cost&amp;rdquo; that represents life long learning.  It isn&amp;rsquo;t simply
learning that which one needs to know to remain current in one&amp;rsquo;s field but the
desire to know more about more things.  To understand in greater depth the
totality of human knowing and experience that defines life-long learning. And
this, I fear, we do not do well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sirkenrobinson.com/&#34;&gt;Sir Ken Robinson&lt;/a&gt; speaks and writes often of the
negative impact that our
educational system has on creativity.  I see his point, even if I don&amp;rsquo;t fully
agree with it.  But I think, just as importantly &amp;ndash; and perhaps more importantly
&amp;ndash; our educational system negatively impacts our desire to learn.  By insisting
on specific performance standards, grading work against some (nominally)
objective standard, and a host of other oppressive measures, education has
worked against itself by inadvertently discouraging curiosity and exploration in
favor of
conformity and blind acceptance.  Students are provided little incentive and
virtually no support in thinking outside the box or of exploring things that are
of interest to them but, at least in the minds of others, of little direct
value.  But value is in the eye of the beholder.  Many see a liberal arts
education as having little value because such an education does not lead
directly to a job.  But, the liberal arts graduate has a broader, and deeper,
overall skill set than the &amp;lsquo;vocationally&amp;rsquo; trained student.  That broad education
equips them with the skills to adapt to a constantly changing environment in
ways that the B-school trained student may not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning requires challenging one&amp;rsquo;s self.  It requires stretching beyond what is
known and comfortable. It requires exploring ideas, even the bad ones, to find
out what makes them bad and to ferret out any good that might lie hidden within
them. Learning requires taking risks to define our limits and to know what lies
beyond what we believe we know.  It requires considering things that are not
within our ken or belief system to understand how others believe as they do and
how the two can be reconciled.  Learning requires freedom not restrictions.&lt;br&gt;
Yet, my wife was telling me last night that a local elementary school limits
students to reading books only with their tested Lexile range.  How ridiculous!&lt;br&gt;
Yes, they will find the reading perhaps easier, but how do they extend their
reading range, expand their vocabularies, and extend their understanding of the
world if they&amp;rsquo;re not allowed to stretch themselves?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing your Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/designing-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/designing-your-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;designing-your-life&#34;&gt;Designing Your Life&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &amp;lsquo;attended&amp;rsquo; a presentation by Story Musgrave, the astronaut, on &amp;ldquo;Designing your
life&amp;rdquo; or some such similar topic.  While I wasn&amp;rsquo;t overly impressed with his
general rambling presentation style, I was very impressed with the message that
threaded throughout his story. I took several keys away from the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-value-of-curiosity&#34;&gt;The value of curiosity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first takeaway was the importance of curiosity in achieving an effective
life. From high school drop out, he went on to earn a BS in math and statistics,
MBA in operations analysis and computer programming, BA in chemistry, MD, and MS
in physiology and biophysics within an 8 year period.  He would later earn an MA
in literature.  To me, the broad range of areas, as much as the time frame for
these accomplishments, says a great deal. He explored the areas that interested
him. He committed himself to those areas. Most students today would be
counseled to choose a singular path and follow it. Yet, the life he built for
himself was one based on the intersections of his interests.  Each area of
interest exposed him to ideas that he wanted to explore further and so he did.&lt;br&gt;
By not limiting himself to a given field, he opened up new avenues for self
expression and provided himself the skills to create new opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;designing-your-life&#34;&gt;Designing Your Life&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &amp;lsquo;attended&amp;rsquo; a presentation by Story Musgrave, the astronaut, on &amp;ldquo;Designing your
life&amp;rdquo; or some such similar topic.  While I wasn&amp;rsquo;t overly impressed with his
general rambling presentation style, I was very impressed with the message that
threaded throughout his story. I took several keys away from the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-value-of-curiosity&#34;&gt;The value of curiosity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first takeaway was the importance of curiosity in achieving an effective
life. From high school drop out, he went on to earn a BS in math and statistics,
MBA in operations analysis and computer programming, BA in chemistry, MD, and MS
in physiology and biophysics within an 8 year period.  He would later earn an MA
in literature.  To me, the broad range of areas, as much as the time frame for
these accomplishments, says a great deal. He explored the areas that interested
him. He committed himself to those areas. Most students today would be
counseled to choose a singular path and follow it. Yet, the life he built for
himself was one based on the intersections of his interests.  Each area of
interest exposed him to ideas that he wanted to explore further and so he did.&lt;br&gt;
By not limiting himself to a given field, he opened up new avenues for self
expression and provided himself the skills to create new opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;seizing-opportunity&#34;&gt;Seizing opportunity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The second takeaway&lt;/strong&gt; was the importance of seizing opportunity.  When
opportunities presented themselves he took advantagse of them.  He leveraged
those opportunities into even more opportunities.  He also, and this is
important, created opportunity by highlighting the skills and knowledge that he
brought to the table.  He didn&amp;rsquo;t play the game.  He was forthright in what he
had accomplished and what he could do.  He recognized that opportunities may
have long-term payoffs when, for example, he chose to work for free in a
neuroscience lab in order to gain the experience and knowledge he wanted from
that field.  His earlier skills played a vital role in his success in that
field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;take-risks&#34;&gt;Take risks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third takeaway, I think, was his willingness to take risks.  He did this in
many ways, but the one that stood out to me was his use of a one page resume
that played up his accomplishments and his skills rather than his
&amp;lsquo;qualifications&amp;rsquo;.  That is he highlighted what he had accomplished and his
qualities rather than his pedigree.  This is a truly important concept for the
liberal arts major.  Highlighting what you&amp;rsquo;re capable of, rather than simply
listing academic credentials makes the difference. His one page resume showed
his academic credentials, but also highlighted what he had done with those
credentials, as well as the non-academic accomplishments he had that further
attested to his capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;everything-is-connected&#34;&gt;Everything is connected&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth takeaway was the importance of recognizing how the fields intersect.&lt;br&gt;
No field operates in isolation.  By intersecting his various degrees and
experiences he was able to build a remarkable life of accomplishment and was
able to create new knowledge, new science.  I would not particularly care to
suffer through his presentation again, but would love to see the major points he
wanted to make so that I could consider them further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder if he has a book &amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Social Filters Impact an Educated Response</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-social-filters-impact-an-educated-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-social-filters-impact-an-educated-response/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-social-filters-impact-an-educated-response&#34;&gt;How Social Filters Impact an Educated Response&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the hallmarks of the well-educated person is, I think, the ability and willingness to explore all sides of an issue before making a decision. Unfortunately, it seems that few people, even those who are, in fact, well-educated, truly take the time to explore an issue before taking a stance on it. And, to a large extent, I get it. It’s hard to do.  It’s hard, not only because it takes time and effort, but because we are bombarded by so much information from so many different sources and on so many different topics that it is difficult to winnow out the wheat from the chaff.  What is important? What should I be concerned with?  What issues can I reasonably relegate to secondary or tertiary concern and on which should I focus my attention? &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-social-filters-impact-an-educated-response&#34;&gt;How Social Filters Impact an Educated Response&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the hallmarks of the well-educated person is, I think, the ability and willingness to explore all sides of an issue before making a decision. Unfortunately, it seems that few people, even those who are, in fact, well-educated, truly take the time to explore an issue before taking a stance on it. And, to a large extent, I get it. It’s hard to do.  It’s hard, not only because it takes time and effort, but because we are bombarded by so much information from so many different sources and on so many different topics that it is difficult to winnow out the wheat from the chaff.  What is important? What should I be concerned with?  What issues can I reasonably relegate to secondary or tertiary concern and on which should I focus my attention? &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two truly modern factors make it even more difficult to view the world through an educated lens.  First, there is a great deal of fake news out there.  Recent news articles have focused on this phenomenon 1,2.  Some sites, such as Onion.com are deliberately fake in an effort to satirize current events.  This is to be expected and is, in its own way, a means for highlighting problems in news reporting, as well as in the systems (such as the political system) it targets.  More concerning, however, are those sites that pose as legitimate news sources while promulgating false information as “news”.  Both Facebook and Google have fallen prey to this type of ‘reporting’ and it doesn’t help that sites like Yahoo.com intersperse advertisements disguised as news articles within the listings of legitimate news.  Figuring out whether news is truly valid is becoming harder and harder to do.  And, as the difficulty rises, the willingness to expend the energy to figure out what is valid declines.  The result? People make decisions based on questionable information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second factor is equally concerning.  As people rely increasingly on the internet and social media for their news, the algorithms used on those sites provides a lopsided view of the world 3. We all know that Amazon, Google, and a host of other sites tailor ads to meet your interests.  Those same algorithms are used to to tailor the news you see.  As El-Bermawy notes in his &lt;em&gt;wired&lt;/em&gt; opinion piece, the result of this tailored news is that you are only reading news that conforms to your interests.  Thus, if you’re against some issue (abortion, for example) you’ll only see news that reflects that perspective.  On the one hand, that seems reasonable.  Certainly, if I am interested in solar power having my news filtered to show me articles on that topic is quite useful. On the other hand, if I’m interested in some controversial topic the filters help to ensure that I only see articles that support my view.  That’s not so good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a democratic society in which the people have a substantial say in the shaping of policy it is important that the people have a good understanding of the issues.  This means that they need to understand both the pros and the cons.  Filtered news, as El-Barmawy notes, creates a situation in which the reader isn’t given the opportunity to learn about the varying perspectives; they only get their own perspective reinforced.  In effect, there is a confirmation bias in the news they receive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps most concerning of all is that most people will not realize that they’re not being given the whole news.  It isn’t obvious that their news has been filtered to fit their perspectives. It wasn’t a choice they made consciously but is the result of algorithms reacting to their prior activities.  The result is that their store of knowledge — and their understanding of the issues — is trapped in a silo that protects them from alternative views.  And exactly those alternative views are essential to a complete understanding of an issue and an appropriate decision regarding those issues in a democratic society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Log In – New York Times. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/11/15/technology/google-will-ban-websites-that-host-fake-news-from-using-its-ad-service.html&#34;&gt;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/11/15/technology/google-will-ban-websites-that-host-fake-news-from-using-its-ad-service.html&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed November 18, 2016.
2.
Stelter B. The plague of fake news is getting worse — here’s how to protect yourself. CNNMoney. &lt;a href=&#34;http://money.cnn.com/2016/10/30/media/facebook-fake-news-plague/index.html&#34;&gt;http://money.cnn.com/2016/10/30/media/facebook-fake-news-plague/index.html&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed November 18, 2016.
3.
M. El-Bermawy      Mostafa. Your Filter Bubble is Destroying Democracy. WIRED. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/2016/11/filter-bubble-destroying-democracy/&#34;&gt;https://www.wired.com/2016/11/filter-bubble-destroying-democracy/&lt;/a&gt;. Published November 18, 2016. Accessed November 18, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Thing Every College Should Do For Its Students</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-first-thing-every-college-should-do-for-its-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-first-thing-every-college-should-do-for-its-students/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-first-thing-every-college-should-do-for-its-students&#34;&gt;The First Thing Every College Should Do For Its Students&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some time now I’ve argued that colleges and universities have dropped the ball on one of the most important preparatory steps in attending college: Defining what a college education is all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students often go to college without a clear conception of what they’re supposed to be getting from the experience.  They go because college has become the “thing you do” after high school.  Like their secondary education, they never really stop to think about why they’re going, or what the benefits are. More importantly, many students see college as simply an extension of their secondary education. That is, learning without an express purpose other than “I’ll need to know this someday.” &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-first-thing-every-college-should-do-for-its-students&#34;&gt;The First Thing Every College Should Do For Its Students&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some time now I’ve argued that colleges and universities have dropped the ball on one of the most important preparatory steps in attending college: Defining what a college education is all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students often go to college without a clear conception of what they’re supposed to be getting from the experience.  They go because college has become the “thing you do” after high school.  Like their secondary education, they never really stop to think about why they’re going, or what the benefits are. More importantly, many students see college as simply an extension of their secondary education. That is, learning without an express purpose other than “I’ll need to know this someday.” &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The costs of a college education continue to rise and students, rightfully, should be informed of their options for an education, for educational financing, and even for their careers.  Yet, most colleges don’t do anything to provide the incoming student with an overview of what a college education can do for them and what they should expect from their experience. No one clearly differentiates the college experience from earlier educational experiences, so the student never gets an opportunity to make a fully informed decision. Consequently, they flounder, become frustrated and may even drop out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that one of the most important things that a college can do for its incoming students is to provide them with clear guidance on what a college education entails and what it provides (or doesn’t provide) in preparing them for their future.  Call it a ‘truth-in-education’ approach not unlike the truth-in-lending that you get when taking out a loan. It should be the first thing the student hears. And, perhaps, should even be what they hear &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; they enroll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students should be helped to understand that college provides two types of education: technical and human.  Now, I’ll probably go into these in more detail in later posts, but for now I’ll define them thusly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical education is education that is designed to provide the student with specific skills and knowledge that meets the requirements of specific career fields.  Think nursing, engineering, IT, business, and the like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Human” education or, if you prefer, “classic” education is designed to develop the intellectual capacity of the student.  I prefer the use of “human” simply because the focus is not on developing a specific skillset, but on developing the student’s human potential.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite what many may say, one is not better than the other.  They are simply different. And which route the student takes is a reflection of her own values, personality, and interests.  Perhaps the biggest difference is that the student who chooses a “technical” route is choosing a clear, but limited career path while the student who chooses the “human” route has a less clear but, ultimately, more wide-open path.  Thus, while the IT graduate knows what her job options are and can encapsulate her skill set neatly by saying “I have a degree in programming”, the History graduate needs to take the time to inventory the skill set he has developed through his college experience and consider how that particular set of skills can be of benefit to an organization. It is of note that the skills that many organizations say they want in their employees are precisely the skills that the humanities graduates have developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing up front that the two types of education are different and what that difference means is essential to how a student understands their collegiate experience and its impact on their future.  Certainly there is not a huge demand for people who majored in English Literature. But there &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a demand for employees who can read and interpret complex documents, who can write clearly and succinctly, and who can think creatively to solve problems.  And the English Lit student may be better positioned to do that than your average business major.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colleges are spending millions of dollars on advertising to draw students to their campuses and tens of thousands more on developing new and exciting programs.  Perhaps, in stead, they should invest in helping students see how the current programs can help them get ahead.  Simply explain what the college experience is all about.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of a Degree</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-meaning-of-a-degree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-meaning-of-a-degree/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-meaning-of-a-degree&#34;&gt;The Meaning of a Degree&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasons why they may choose to do this are myriad. For some students, the BSN has long been a personal goal. For others, though, the decision isn’t internally motivated. Rather, they’re faced with either obtaining their BSN, or finding other employment. Now, for anyone outside of nursing, that latter reason might seem a bit harsh. But for those of us in the profession, it makes sense – at least to a degree. While I don’t disagree with the need for higher levels of education in nursing, I’m not so sure that the approach employers are using to encourage nurses to seek the BSN is the best approach. Let’s begin with a bit of background. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-meaning-of-a-degree&#34;&gt;The Meaning of a Degree&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasons why they may choose to do this are myriad. For some students, the BSN has long been a personal goal. For others, though, the decision isn’t internally motivated. Rather, they’re faced with either obtaining their BSN, or finding other employment. Now, for anyone outside of nursing, that latter reason might seem a bit harsh. But for those of us in the profession, it makes sense – at least to a degree. While I don’t disagree with the need for higher levels of education in nursing, I’m not so sure that the approach employers are using to encourage nurses to seek the BSN is the best approach. Let’s begin with a bit of background. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research has shown a correlation between the level of nursing education and positive outcomes. That is, where the percentagse of baccalaureate prepared nurses is relatively high, there are fewer complications, slightly fewer deaths per 1000, and other benefits to the organization and to the patient. In addition, the Robert Wood Johnson/IOM has generated several reports over the years that also document the benefits of higher levels of nursing education and have consequently called on nursing schools, and employers to increase the numbers of practicing BSN level nurses.  the RWJ/IOM report has recommended that 80% of nurses be prepared at the BSN level by 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a more generic front, while all other healthcare disciplines have raised their educational requirements for entry to practice, nursing maintains the same educational requirements for entry to practice that have existed for more than 50 years. Times have changed, technologies have changed, knowledge has changed, and nursing needs to change in response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A third factor driving the push for nurses to get their BSN is something called “Magnet Status.” Magnet status is a designation made by the American Nurse Credentialing Center (ANCC) that recognizes hospitals for nursing excellence, quality patient care, and innovative nursing practices. Many organizations that either have achieved Magnet Status, or are working towards it, have established goals to increase the percentagse of BSN prepared nurses on staff. There are essentially three ways to achieve that goal: Hire only BSN nurses, encourage your current staff to go back to school, or decrease the number of non-BSN nurses on staff. The last two tend to work in concert and are often either transmitted, or interpreted, as “get your degree or lose you job.” Thus, many students are going back to school to keep their jobs, not because they are motivated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;just-give-me-the-degree&#34;&gt;Just give me the degree&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that most educators would agree that external motivators, particularly negative motivators don’t lead to particularly good learning outcomes. And this is what I see. I can almost always immediately identify the student who comes to school “because I have to.” They are the ones who don’t want to do the work. They are the ones who complain about everything. They are the ones who become frustrated because they “don’t understand” what is expected of them because they are so busy just trying to rush through that they didn’t bother to read the syllabus – or the assigned materials. There is very much of a “Just give me the degree” mentality.  And that is, to me, very sad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things that I try to communicate to students is that it isn’t just a piece of paper. That degree &lt;em&gt;means something&lt;/em&gt;. When you tell someone you possess a degree, you are telling that you possess certain knowledge and skills that aren’t as easily found in those without the degree.  It’s not just about technical skills and knowledge. The BSN level nurse has a greater understanding of how things work together, how they interact. She is better prepared to see relationships, and to understand those relationships. She is better able to identify and anticipate the sequelae of patient situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also about being able to read, understand, and implement the findings of nursing and medical research to benefit the patient and/or the organization – or themselves. It’s about being able to talk cogently with other medical professionals about patient situations to work collaboratively to improve outcomes. It’s about improving the position of nursing within the healthcare structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is, I think, indicative of the level of understanding that many ADN nurses see no difference between themselves and the BSN nurse. It is true that many BSN nurses, particularly straight out of school, work along side the ADN nurse, doing the same job. And, it is likely true that many don’t have the technical skills that the ADN nurse has on graduation. But what the ADN nurse doesn’t see is that the BSN nurse brings a different skillset to the table. The physical skills can be quickly and easily learned. What is more difficult to learn, and what the BSN prepared nurse generally does bring to the table, are the intellectual skills needed to see and anticipate problems before they occur, the awareness and understanding of research that impacts practice, and the importance of that research on patient outcomes. The ADN nurse, of course, can certainly develop those skills over time, but it is the orderly development of those skills through education that hastens the process for the baccalaureate nurse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-the-value-of-the-degree&#34;&gt;What is the value of the degree?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in the long run,  I believe that it is vital that we increase the number of BSN level (and higher) nurses. The value of the higher degree has been demonstrated through multiples studies. And, as nurses, we should be committed to doing anything that we can to improve the quality of care that we provide to benefit the patient. What is the value of the degree? To me it is the value of the we improved through our own improved knowledge and skill.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology For Its Own Sake</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/technology-for-its-own-sake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/technology-for-its-own-sake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;technology-for-its-own-sake&#34;&gt;Technology For It&amp;rsquo;s Own Sake&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About eight years ago I spent a couple of years teaching high school. Being a nurse, and coming into the experience with no real educational background it was quite an interesting, and eye-opening experience. Needless to say, I probably learned more than my students did. One of the things that left me scratching my head was the approach the school system took toward education. Tons of money was spent on technology and teachers were required to have at least one “technology lesson” each week. That lesson had to be so designated on your weekly lesson plan. Talk about misguided! As I write this I still see a lot of the same things happening in education — at all levels. And it’s just plain dumb. Let’s explore this a bit. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;technology-for-its-own-sake&#34;&gt;Technology For It&amp;rsquo;s Own Sake&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About eight years ago I spent a couple of years teaching high school. Being a nurse, and coming into the experience with no real educational background it was quite an interesting, and eye-opening experience. Needless to say, I probably learned more than my students did. One of the things that left me scratching my head was the approach the school system took toward education. Tons of money was spent on technology and teachers were required to have at least one “technology lesson” each week. That lesson had to be so designated on your weekly lesson plan. Talk about misguided! As I write this I still see a lot of the same things happening in education — at all levels. And it’s just plain dumb. Let’s explore this a bit. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;build-it-and-they-will-come&#34;&gt;Build It and They Will Come&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s suppose, for a moment, that I’m running a for profit business. Where and when I spend money is determined by the needs that spending that money will meet. Outside of research and development it is unlikely that I would spend large sums of money on equipment and software for which I don’t already have a defined purpose. Stating that a bit differently, purchases are driven by the need the purchase will meet. A businessman would be foolish to spend large sums of money on a piece of equipment then turn to his staff and say, “well, here it is. Figure out how we can use it!” But that’s what schools do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the metrics used to judge school systems, apparently, is the technology available within the system.  Thus, IT leaders in education become focused on procuring equipment and software that they can then point to as evidence of their “forward thinking” and/or their technologic support of the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, often that technology sits in the classroom unused. Why? Three reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.    The technology is purchased without a clear purpose in mind. No one asks the question: What instructional need is this purchase fulfilling? With no clear instructional purpose, the equipment is simply not used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.    While money was spent to buy the equipment and software, little or no money is spent to train teachers to use it.  Shown how to use the technology, and how it can be beneficial in the classroom, I think many teachers would be accepting of new technologies. However, this is seldom done. They’re left to their own motivation. That leads us to the third problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.    Teachers already have a lot on their plates. They have no motivation to learn new technologies that may not have value in their classrooms. That is, with so many competing priorities in teaching today, teachers don’t want to spend time trying to learn a technology that may not be of benefit in moving them toward the goal of educating their students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IT directors in schools should be educators and they should be capable of evaluating the utility of the technologies in the classroom setting. Purchases should be driven not by a desire to “look good” on some report, or by a desire to “try out” new technologies, but by the need in the classroom. Interestingly, it seems that often the decisions are made without input from teachers and when teachers do make recommendations, or requests for specific technologies, their input is ignored or minimized. Heaven forbid that a faculty member should request software, or access to an online technology that they have determined would be beneficial to their classroom. Their request may well be denied. After all, who are they to evaluate software? And, there’s likely to be no money in the budget for such requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;technology-for-technologys-sake&#34;&gt;Technology for Technology’s Sake&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I note above, the idea of having at least one “technology lesson plan” each week is equally ludicrous.  Technology should always be the tool to achieving an outcome. Unless you’re teaching a technology course, the technology should not be the focus. Like buying equipment without a purpose, using technology (or requiring its use) when it contributes little to the outcomes is ridiculous for several reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.    Not all topics benefit from the use of technology. As adjunctive activities technology-based activities might have a place in some classrooms. For example, using storyboarding software to create a storyboard of a reading in a literature class might be beneficial in reinforcing what is learned. On the other hand, simply having the student prepare a PowerPoint on the topic likely does no more for learning than having them take notes. Why not just have them take notes, instead of introducing the complexity of the software into the equation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.    Teachers seldom have the level of skill needed to teach students how to use the technology— I”m an English teacher, not a computer teacher, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.    A corollary to  #2 is that students are often significantly more sophisticated in their ability to use current technologies than are their teachers. So, the teacher assigns the creation of a PowerPoint (which students have now done hundreds of times) and the student is bored. Why not allow the student to select a technology to use to present an idea? I’m betting theirs would be much more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sure there are other reasons, but I’ll let you add them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point in all of this is that technology is, and should be seen as, a tool in the teacher’s toolbox. You would never hand someone a wrench and tell them to figure out how to build a house with it. Neither should you demand that teachers use a specific technology in their classrooms. Teachers should always be free to choose the tools that best meet the needs of the classroom. But, to help them understand the tools available to them, they should be properly trained in the use of all their tools, not just a few. Finally, teachers should feel free to request  and be allowed to use whatever resources they feel best meet the needs of their classroom. It should never be the IT director’s decision on what is appropriate for the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is it for Education or Business?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/is-it-for-education-or-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/is-it-for-education-or-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;is-it-for-education-or-business&#34;&gt;Is it for Education or Business?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early 1990’s as I was preparing to wrap up my MBA I was informed by my advisor that I still needed to take a basic statistics course. Now, that would seem a reasonable expectation were it not for the fact that I had already completed two advanced statistics courses. Being a bit obstinate, I asked why it was necessary for me to take a course designed to prepare me for courses that I had already taken and passed (quite well, I might add.) The response – not surprisingly – was that it was a necessary part of the degree and, therefore, could not be waived. That introductory statistics course, the one designed to prepare me for higher level courses, was the last course I took before graduating. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;is-it-for-education-or-business&#34;&gt;Is it for Education or Business?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early 1990’s as I was preparing to wrap up my MBA I was informed by my advisor that I still needed to take a basic statistics course. Now, that would seem a reasonable expectation were it not for the fact that I had already completed two advanced statistics courses. Being a bit obstinate, I asked why it was necessary for me to take a course designed to prepare me for courses that I had already taken and passed (quite well, I might add.) The response – not surprisingly – was that it was a necessary part of the degree and, therefore, could not be waived. That introductory statistics course, the one designed to prepare me for higher level courses, was the last course I took before graduating. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems reasonable to me that educated, rational people would recognize how ludicrous it is to demand strict adherence to a course of study designed to teach me something, that I have clearly already mastered. It seems reasonable to me that highly educated, rational people would recognize that the purpose of education is not to check off boxes on a list to provide an educational experience. It seems reasonable to me that highly educated, rational people would recognize that the purpose of a class has been fulfilled when a student has succeeded in a higher level course. Alas, what seems reasonable to me is, apparently, not reasonable to those highly educated, rational people called University Administrators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;and-it-continues-&#34;&gt;And it Continues …&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had hoped that with the passage of twenty years, the continuous evolution of the educational environment, and pressure from various sources to look carefully at the products of today’s higher educational systems, changes would have come. I had hoped that blind adherence to a “course of study” would have given way to a more rational view of the learning experience. With an increasing number of “non-traditional” student (meaning, among other things, second career students) I would have expected a bit more acknowledgement of prior experience in the educational sphere. Certainly a twenty year career in management provides knowledge and experience that exceeds anything likely to be presented in a classroom! But, alas, it appears I am wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I move into my spring term, I am preparing to begin a “practicum” experience designed to introduce me to the faculty role. For a young student, for a student who lacks experience in the field, these practica can be immensely instructive. But, how will the 240 hours of practicum contribute to the more than 18,000 hours of experience I have in the role? To be frank, I’m doubtful I’ll get much out of it. Like the introductory statistics course from twenty years ago, this course is designed to provide with the foundational skills necessary for success in subsequent experiences. The problem is – as it was twenty years ago – I have already mastered the role that the course is designed to prepare me for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;and-the-alternative&#34;&gt;And the Alternative?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I taught secondary ed for a couple of years. For students who quickly mastered the basic content of the course we had enrichment activities that built on their basic knowledge. These activities allowed the brighter student to extend and deepen their knowledge about the topic while allowing their classmates time to master material with which they may be struggling. This makes sense. Repeating material already learned is wasted effort.  Building on that material is not only good time utilization, but good use of effort. And, in the end the student is all the more successful. This concept apparently hasn’t made it to the collegiate level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, those of us who share significant experience as faculty at the undergraduate level sought to pursue that practicum at the graduate level. We wanted to gain experience in a role that was different from our histories. But, no. That is not possible, for it is not the goal of the course. So, I’ll be working 64+ hours a week between my full-time job and the practicum experience (not to mention the study time for the two other courses I’ll be taking) and will get to pay $1000 more for the privilege of being “introduced” into a role I’ve held for nine years. So, Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obvious answer to this question is rooted in the very same issues that have grabbed so many headlines in recent years. Money. By allowing a student to bypass a course that they clearly do not need, the university is missing out on the revenue that course would generate. And this simply will not do!  Yet, it seems to me that helping students to manage costs should be part of the university’s mission. I wonder how this may change as MOOCs make inroads in the educational landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I can only hope that as I continue to add to my academic resume that I won’t lose the common sense that tells me something is decidedly wrong with this picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*\&lt;/em&gt;* End of Rant ***&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Education &#34;All That&#34;?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/is-education-all-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/is-education-all-that/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;is-education-all-that&#34;&gt;Is Education &amp;ldquo;All That&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a wonderful opportunity to talk with a woman(we’ll call her Jane) who has accomplished several things that I have only dreamed of. She has developed a new approach to an old and vexing problem many nurses face, she contributed to the development of a new medical device, she has been published in peer-reviewed journals, and has spoken around the world before thousands of people to introduce other professionals to both her new technique and to the medical device. She can confidently say that the approach she developed is being used in health care settings around the world. And she has an associate’s degree — the minimum level of education required to become a nurse.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;is-education-all-that&#34;&gt;Is Education &amp;ldquo;All That&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a wonderful opportunity to talk with a woman(we’ll call her Jane) who has accomplished several things that I have only dreamed of. She has developed a new approach to an old and vexing problem many nurses face, she contributed to the development of a new medical device, she has been published in peer-reviewed journals, and has spoken around the world before thousands of people to introduce other professionals to both her new technique and to the medical device. She can confidently say that the approach she developed is being used in health care settings around the world. And she has an associate’s degree — the minimum level of education required to become a nurse.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without that last sentence I have no doubt that you would have expected that I would have introduced her as Doctor Jane, indicating her PhD in nursing or some allied field. But she is not; she is minimally educated for her profession. And there’s the rub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have become so trained that more education is always the way to wealth, fame, and fortune that we have really, I think, overlooked the real drivers of accomplishing things like Jane has done: Curiosity, creativity, and drive. The simple fact is I know quite a number of highly educated people who have not, and will not, accomplish what Jane has done.  Or anything close to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I get bashed for bashing higher education, don’t misunderstand my meaning. higher education has a place (I”m banking heavily on it!) The lead author of Jane’s article is a PhD educated nurse researcher. There’s little doubt that it was with her colleague’s guidance that Jane wrote and published what she did. But he didn’t develop the technique; she did. His role was to help her evangelize it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we also need to remember that without creativity, curiosity, and drive no amount of education will lead to new ideas, or new products. What scares me sometimes, though, is that it seems that we are “educating” these traits out of our students. Peter Gray, a research psychologist at Boston College penned &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;this article&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; about the creativity killing effects of traditional education with its focus on high-stakes testing. For years before, I have questioned education’s role in developing or squelching a child’s innate creativity. You can teach techniques in art, for example, or the mechanics of playing a musical instrument. One wonders what Pablo Picasso’s art would have been had he remained at the Royal Academy of San Fernando, Spain’s foremost art school of the time. How different would the Apple computer be if Steve Jobs had remained in college? Would there even &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; and Apple computer? Jobs, for example, famously dropped out of Reed College only to later audit courses that “interested” him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, to be sure, not everyone who charts their own path will be as successful as Jobs, or Picasso, and others who have made their mark in the world despite lacking higher education credentials. My point isn’t to argue that education isn’t necessary. On the contrary, it is highly necessary. None of the things that have been accomplished — even by people like Steve Jobs — would have been possible had they not been educated. But their educational path was one of their choosing. They eschewed the traditional structured process of formal education in favor of an educational path that was driven by their interests. Consequently they learned more and achieved more because they were curious about a topic, driven to learn more, and creative in how they apply that knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of the MOOC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-state-of-the-mooc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-state-of-the-mooc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-state-of-the-mooc&#34;&gt;The State of the MOOC&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two recent articles about &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Massive Open Online Courses&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; (MOOC) got my attention this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;fail&#34;&gt;Fail?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.insidehighered.com/news/2013/05/10/new-study-low-mooc-completion-rates&#34;&gt;first article&lt;/a&gt; brings to the fore the reality that only about 7% of those who start a MOOC course complete it. This is, of course, a major concern for educators, given that completion rates are the major metric for colleges. It is completely understandable that many would see that number and conclude that MOOCs are failing. I’m not sure I agree with that assessment for several reasons.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-state-of-the-mooc&#34;&gt;The State of the MOOC&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two recent articles about &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Massive Open Online Courses&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; (MOOC) got my attention this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;fail&#34;&gt;Fail?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.insidehighered.com/news/2013/05/10/new-study-low-mooc-completion-rates&#34;&gt;first article&lt;/a&gt; brings to the fore the reality that only about 7% of those who start a MOOC course complete it. This is, of course, a major concern for educators, given that completion rates are the major metric for colleges. It is completely understandable that many would see that number and conclude that MOOCs are failing. I’m not sure I agree with that assessment for several reasons.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, it’s important to remember that MOOCs are a new and novel concept that has received a tremendous amount of public press. Many people are curious to know what the hype is all about and may well have signed up to take a course simply to see what the hype was all about. Once their curiosity was satisfied they dropped out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other students may have signed up with specific learning needs on the topic. Once their learning needs were satisfied they, too, dropped out. This is one of the benefits of the ‘open’ aspect of the MOOC; students are free to come and go as they please, according to their needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A third factor is the low, or no cost, aspect of the MOOC. One of the basic concepts of the MOOC is that the courses are available at little or no cost. This has, I think, two implications. The first is that the low, or no, cost of the course means the student has nothing to lose by signing up. This could lead to many students signing up for courses. The second implication is that with no “skin in the game” the student has no real incentive to work hard to achieve. Fowler (2013) points out a Coursera study that finds that students who pay $30 – $60 for an Identify Verification service associated with the course are “significantly” more likely to complete the course.  Surely cost, and having skin in the game, makes a difference on completion rates. At the same, time, I’m not sure which comes first. Are they more likely to complete &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; they paid the fee, or are they more likely to pay the fee because they want to complete the course?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A final reason, at least in my mind, is that many MOOCs are simply poorly designed and, as a consequence, students found the format unpalatable. MOOCs are based on some very specific concepts. One of those concepts is that students contribute to the learning process with the faculty serving as guide.  In other words, students are actively involved in their education. Many courses, however, appear to be highly structured courses with an over-reliance on video lectures and assigned reading. Students simply don’t want to sit passively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;who-are-moocs-for&#34;&gt;Who are MOOCs for?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there is no question that completion is an issue, it turns out that the one who are completing already have some &lt;a href=&#34;http://chronicle.com/blogs/wiredcampus/moocs-are-reaching-only-privileged-learners-survey-finds/48567&#34;&gt;college-level education&lt;/a&gt; — usually at least a baccalaureate degree. This comes as a bit of surprise, apparently, to some of the folk who felt that MOOCs would be the salvation for underprivileged students. Frankly, I’m not surprised. The design of MOOCs require the student to bring the ability to study independently to the table. Moreover, the concepts that underly the MOOC rely on student interest and motivation. The undergraduate student often lacks both the skills needed for independent study and the motivation and interest to seek out the knowledge the course is intended to provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, the MOOC has a couple of  very specific niche markets. I think that MOOCs are great resources for the individual who wants to know more about some topic without necessarily wanting a degree. These individuals are motivated to learn, not because they need the degree but because they want to know more. These folk, not surprisingly, are often already well educated. Their motivation might be to gain the knowledge to move into a new position or to deepen their knowledge for a position they’ve recently been promoted into. Or, it may simply be to fulfill a curiosity. Many well-educated people tend to expand their interests into new areas. The MOOC is a perfect vehicle for meeting that interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These well-educated people also bring a history of study skills to the table, making the MOOC not only more appealing to them, but making them more likely to be successful in that environment. This is one of the major issues, in my view, for those considering offering MOOCs to undergraduate students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;wrapping-it-up&#34;&gt;Wrapping it Up…&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that MOOCs are a potentially valuable way for people to learn new skills that they need to improve their work situations, or to expand their interests. On the other hand, I don’t think that they are the best option for teaching students who are not already well versed in studying. Stay tuned, though, because things are always subject to change!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
