<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book Reviews on Kevin&#39;s Corner of the Web</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/book-reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book Reviews on Kevin&#39;s Corner of the Web</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/book-reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Confusing Fiction with Fact</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/confusing-fiction-with-fact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/confusing-fiction-with-fact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;confusing-fiction-with-fact&#34;&gt;Confusing Fiction with Fact&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I swear some people can&amp;rsquo;t keep track of reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While browsing Amazon for something to read in the vein of philosophy I ran across a book entitled &lt;em&gt;The da Vinci Fraud: Why the Truth is Stranger than Fiction&lt;/em&gt; by Robert M. Price.  The book purports to debunk the &amp;ldquo;many misleading claims found in Dan Brown&amp;rsquo;s Da Vinci Code&amp;rdquo; according to one reviewer.  That statement and several others made by various &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;reviewers suggest that somehow Brown was intending to provide accurate historical information regarding the Christian Church.  Funny, having read &lt;em&gt;The Da Vinci Code&lt;/em&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t recall Brown ever claiming that the book was historically accurate.  For someone to take the time to write a book to refute claims that were never made seems, well, stupid. Apparently, Mr. Price (or I should say Doctor Price, given his PhD) has difficulty comprehending that fiction is by definition not fact.  Fiction writers often base their works on some variation of an idea or concept and follow the &amp;ldquo;what if&amp;rdquo; process. That is, &amp;ldquo;what if&amp;rdquo; there really is an Opus Dei &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; with sinister underpinnings?  &amp;ldquo;What if&amp;rdquo; Jesus and Mary Magdalene really did have a child together? and so on.  Fiction writers take some fact and embroider it with the lace needed to paint an enticing picture that tells an entertaining story.  Few set out to present history (or any other topic) factually.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;confusing-fiction-with-fact&#34;&gt;Confusing Fiction with Fact&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I swear some people can&amp;rsquo;t keep track of reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While browsing Amazon for something to read in the vein of philosophy I ran across a book entitled &lt;em&gt;The da Vinci Fraud: Why the Truth is Stranger than Fiction&lt;/em&gt; by Robert M. Price.  The book purports to debunk the &amp;ldquo;many misleading claims found in Dan Brown&amp;rsquo;s Da Vinci Code&amp;rdquo; according to one reviewer.  That statement and several others made by various &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;reviewers suggest that somehow Brown was intending to provide accurate historical information regarding the Christian Church.  Funny, having read &lt;em&gt;The Da Vinci Code&lt;/em&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t recall Brown ever claiming that the book was historically accurate.  For someone to take the time to write a book to refute claims that were never made seems, well, stupid. Apparently, Mr. Price (or I should say Doctor Price, given his PhD) has difficulty comprehending that fiction is by definition not fact.  Fiction writers often base their works on some variation of an idea or concept and follow the &amp;ldquo;what if&amp;rdquo; process. That is, &amp;ldquo;what if&amp;rdquo; there really is an Opus Dei &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; with sinister underpinnings?  &amp;ldquo;What if&amp;rdquo; Jesus and Mary Magdalene really did have a child together? and so on.  Fiction writers take some fact and embroider it with the lace needed to paint an enticing picture that tells an entertaining story.  Few set out to present history (or any other topic) factually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love James Michener&amp;rsquo;s work. He has generated dozens of books that provide insight into the history of various regions (Alaska, Hawaii, the Caribbean, Spain, Poland, and on and on) but I would be fool to believe that his works are 100% historically accurate.  And, again, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that Michener ever set out for accuracy.  Having read almost all of his books, including his autobiography, I suspect that he simply found the process of researching and learning about these different regions interesting and consequently used that research to provide a foundation for his stories. His histories are painted in broad brush strokes that do give the flavor of that region&amp;rsquo;s history but are likely not completely accurate.  Does the lack of absolute historical accuracy diminish his work?  Not in my view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every writer writes through a particular lens and it&amp;rsquo;s especially important, I think, to remember that history is researched, interpreted, and written through the specific lens of that writer. Dr. Price may claim to present facts to refute Brown&amp;rsquo;s storyline (I can&amp;rsquo;t say for certain that he does since I&amp;rsquo;ve not read the book) but the reader must remember that Price&amp;rsquo;s account was interpreted and written through his own lens and may, therefore, be just as historically inaccurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m left scratching my head on why someone with a PhD would even consider Brown&amp;rsquo;s stories to be intended to be historically accurate.  They are simply works of fiction with some references to reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opus Dei is an organization officially recognized by the Catholic Church.  Brown&amp;rsquo;s depiction of the organization as somehow sinister is based, from what I can understand, on controversies surrounding the organization and its cult-like activities (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opus_Dei&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;)&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review - A Curious Mind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/book_reviews/book-review-a-curious-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/book_reviews/book-review-a-curious-mind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/b14798115985144bc798024764ad1773_MD5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-curious-mind&#34;&gt;A Curious Mind&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am, and have always been, a curious person so when I saw this book at the book store I had no choice but to select it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curiosity is a driving force that pushes us to learn more, understand more, and to find or create new things.  Curiosity is also the foundation for creativity, which is the premise for Brian Grazer&amp;rsquo;s book, &amp;ldquo;A Curious Mind&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the name sound familiar, but you &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; can&amp;rsquo;t quite nail down his name, Brian is the producer of many hit movies, including &lt;em&gt;Splash, Apollo 13, Friday Night Lights, and A Beautiful Life&lt;/em&gt; among many others.  Brian credits his curiosity for both getting him into the movie industry and with his success within that industry.  He points to how his curiosity, and what he calls &amp;ldquo;curiosity conversations&amp;rdquo;, has expanded his understanding of people and phenomena,  allowed him to explore new ideas in unique ways, for developing a deeper understanding of others, and for providing him the foundation for identifying good ideas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/b14798115985144bc798024764ad1773_MD5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-curious-mind&#34;&gt;A Curious Mind&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am, and have always been, a curious person so when I saw this book at the book store I had no choice but to select it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curiosity is a driving force that pushes us to learn more, understand more, and to find or create new things.  Curiosity is also the foundation for creativity, which is the premise for Brian Grazer&amp;rsquo;s book, &amp;ldquo;A Curious Mind&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the name sound familiar, but you &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; can&amp;rsquo;t quite nail down his name, Brian is the producer of many hit movies, including &lt;em&gt;Splash, Apollo 13, Friday Night Lights, and A Beautiful Life&lt;/em&gt; among many others.  Brian credits his curiosity for both getting him into the movie industry and with his success within that industry.  He points to how his curiosity, and what he calls &amp;ldquo;curiosity conversations&amp;rdquo;, has expanded his understanding of people and phenomena,  allowed him to explore new ideas in unique ways, for developing a deeper understanding of others, and for providing him the foundation for identifying good ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book spends a good bit of time talking about the role curiosity has played in Brian&amp;rsquo;s success but it also gives good advice on how to harness your curiosity to open your life to greater opportunity.  To be successfully curious, you need to do two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be willing to listen to the answers you receive when you ask questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bw willing to act on what you learn.  He used the example of our curiosity about whether we could go to the moon was one thing; marshaling the resources to make that happen was another.  Only through being willing to act on our curiosity &amp;ndash; to answer the question and to explore the possibilities of making it happen &amp;ndash; can curiosity really open up our lives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A unique aspect of the book is his focus on &amp;ldquo;Curiosity Conversations&amp;rdquo;.  Throughout his adult professional life Brian has tried to meet regularly with people he was curious about &amp;ndash; everyone from Isaac Asimov to Sheldon Glashow, a Nobel Prize winning physicist &amp;ndash; to gain insight into their thoughts and what drives them to do the things they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book points out that curiosity is often looked upon with derision.  Curious people are not often well received and asking questions can be considered rude. And yet is it curiosity that has driven almost all of the innovation we have experienced.  Though not in the book, curiosity, the question of &amp;lsquo;can this be done?&amp;rsquo;, has even led to the relatively rapid development of Artificial Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-i-liked-about-the-book&#34;&gt;What I Liked About the Book&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curiosity is a big motivator in my life so the whole notion of a book that explores how curiosity impacted someone else is always enlightening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He provides examples  of how curiosity led to some of his decisions in life and in his career.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The book provides suggestions on how to ramp up your curiosity and how to then use that curiosity to ramp up your life. (Note that these are not &amp;lsquo;formulas&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;how tos&amp;rsquo;, but simple suggestions that you might implement in your life.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-i-didnt-like-about-the-book&#34;&gt;What I Didn&amp;rsquo;t Like About the Book&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall, I think the book is pretty good as it is.  The book provides a great many examples, which does become somewhat redundant at times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While the examples help the reader to understand what curiosity can lead to and how it can affect your life, they can come across as a bit of name-dropping at times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;do-i-recommend-the-book&#34;&gt;Do I Recommend the Book?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes.  Even if you&amp;rsquo;re not a terribly curious person, the book is an interesting read that provide a look inside how a movie producer came to that profession and was able to leverage their curiosity into a (very) successful career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a curious person, the book provides further evidence that curiosity is a great tool for personal and professional growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a book that, in fact, I will likely re-read at some point in the future to refresh and revitalize my own curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-quotes&#34;&gt;Some Quotes:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to ask any question embodies two things: the freedom to go chase the answer, and the ability to challenge authority, to ask, &amp;ldquo;How come you&amp;rsquo;re in charge?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curiosity is a form of power, and also a form of courage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Referring to the film executive and producer John Calley of Warner Brothers)  &amp;hellip; watching Calley work, I realized something: Creative thoughts didn&amp;rsquo;t have to follow a straight narrative line. You could pursue your interests, your passions, you could chase any quirky idea that came from som odd corner of your experience or your brain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip; Storytelling and curiosity are natural allies.  &amp;hellip; The story is a repot from the front lines of curiosity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are all trapped in our own way of thinking, trapped in our own way of relating to people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
