<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kevin&#39;s corner of the web</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kevin&#39;s corner of the web</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 - Kevin Sauls</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Re-envisining Retirement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/re-envisioning-retirement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/re-envisioning-retirement/</guid>
      <description>Re-envisioning Retirement Somewhere around noon on December 29, 2023 I logged out and powered down my work computer for the last time. After 40 years and 6 months of professional practice in nursing – 20 in the clinical setting and another almost 21 in teaching – I was retiring. Officially, I was to work until 4 PM that day but all of my students had been transferred to other instructors, much of my access to school resources had been rescinded, and there was nothing for me to do so, with my boss’s blessings, I called it a career.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting WordStar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/revisiting-wordstar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/revisiting-wordstar/</guid>
      <description>Revisiting WordStar A day or so ago I ran across an article where science fiction writer Robert J. Sawyer had released his version of WordStar 7.0 for DOS, noting that it is now abandonware and, thus, he felt comfortable releasing it into the wild. What was interesting was that, as he noted, not only he, but several other quite successful writers had developed quite an affinity for the ancient software that ran on a long outdated operating system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Am I on &#34;The Spectrum&#34;?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/am-i-on-the-spectrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/am-i-on-the-spectrum/</guid>
      <description>For the past ten years I have worked from home. Although I interacted regularly with students and other faculty, those interactions generally took place by email (my preferred method) or, when interactivity was required, by phone, Teams, or Zoom. Actual face-to-face interaction was very limited. I liked it that way for, as odd as it may seem, I don&amp;rsquo;t actually like dealing with people directly. I say that&amp;rsquo;s odd because I have spent my entire career in a field that required not only face-to-face interaction but, as a nurse, often that interaction required intimate contact with others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putting My Second Act Into Perspective</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/putting-my-second-act-into-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/putting-my-second-act-into-perspective/</guid>
      <description>Putting My Second Act into Perspective Six months ago I retired after forty years of nursing practice. One of the things I was told when I retired was that I would get bored within three months.&#xA;Uh.&#xA;No.&#xA;As I told a former co-worker, I&amp;rsquo;m busier now than when I was working. The difference is that I&amp;rsquo;m doing what interests me, what I want to do, rather than what I&amp;rsquo;m required to do by someone else.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using the Right Tool for the Job</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/using-the-right-tool-for-the-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 18:13:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/using-the-right-tool-for-the-job/</guid>
      <description>Back in the late 1980&amp;rsquo;s, when I first began working with computers, there were a fairly wide variety of devices and OSes from which to choose. TRS-80, Commodore (I had the C-128), MS-Dos based PCs, Apple, Amiga, and so on. The challenge was to determine which device worked best for your intended use. DOS based PCs were best for office type work, Apple was the choice if you were doing multimedia, Amiga for gaming, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using the Right Tool for the Job</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/2024-07-01-using-the-right-tool-for-the-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/2024-07-01-using-the-right-tool-for-the-job/</guid>
      <description>Using the Right Tool for the Job Back in the late 1980&amp;rsquo;s, when I first began working with computers, there were a fairly wide variety of devices and OSes from which to choose. TRS-80, Commodore (I had the C-128), MS-Dos based PCs, Apple, Amiga, and so on. The challenge was to determine which device worked best for your intended use. DOS based PCs were best for office type work, Apple was the choice if you were doing multimedia, Amiga for gaming, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Driving a Hybrid Pickup Truck</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/driving-a-hybrid-pickup-truck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/driving-a-hybrid-pickup-truck/</guid>
      <description>Driving a Hybrid Pickup Truck I drove a 2000 Ford Ranger for over 20 years. I loved that truck and basically just wore it out. I think when I finally sold it in 2021 I had put over 250K miles on it. But, alas, all good things come to an end and as it got longer in the tooth it began to have more problems, with their associated costs, than I was willing to deal with.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doing Unix-y Things</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/doing-unix-y-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/doing-unix-y-things/</guid>
      <description>Doing Unix-y Things In an earlier post I noted that my foray into Linux began when I started an intensive program in network administration, etc back in 2000. That&amp;rsquo;s not precisely true. That course did not teach me anything about Linux. I don&amp;rsquo;t even recall it being mentioned. What it did teach me was Unix. Sun Solaris Unix, to be precise, running on a Sun Sparc server (rest their souls). Linux came along a bit later.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Do People Use Chromeos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/why-do-people-use-chromeos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/why-do-people-use-chromeos/</guid>
      <description>Why Do People Use ChromeOS? It seems like people have jumping on the ChromeOS bandwagon in droves since the first Chromebooks debuted in 2011. The draw, as I understand it, was that the laptops were small and inexpensive and required little knowledge of computing. Boot it up, create a Google account (if you didn&amp;rsquo;t already have one), and go. Schools and even businesses bought into the ecosystem quickly. Today many schools are almost entirely connected using Chromebooks and often students are given a Chromebook for them to take home and use.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving from Exchange to Zoho Mail</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/moving-from-exchange-to-zoho-mail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/moving-from-exchange-to-zoho-mail/</guid>
      <description>Moving from Exchange to Zoho Mail Somewhere back around 2011 or 2012 I moved from my ISP&amp;rsquo;s email service to Microsoft Office 365 Business plan that offered access to MS Exchange server. I had previously toyed with using Gmail&amp;rsquo;s services with my own domain name but didn&amp;rsquo;t find that it met my specific needs. Too, I really didn&amp;rsquo;t have a great love for Gmail.&#xA;My motivation for moving, as I recall now more than a dozen years later, is that I was starting my doctoral studies and needed to be able to coordinate more easily with classmates, access calendars and documents across multiple platforms, and generally have better control over my workflows.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My History with Self Hosting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/my-history-with-self-hosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/my-history-with-self-hosting/</guid>
      <description>My History with Self-Hosting My journey with Linux started in the summer of 2020 when I enrolled in an intensive course in IT designed for a specific ISP (which no longer exists). The course was provide through a state university in cooperation with that company and in conjunction with a state level push to encourage tech companies to settle in Georgia. I ended up not taking a job with that company.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PlainText Preferences</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/plaintext-preference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/plaintext-preference/</guid>
      <description>PlainText Preferences Over the last ten years there have been a couple of preferences that have driven many of my technology decisions. One is a preference for using plain text rather than proprietary software. The other is a preference for flat files over databases.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s Talk about Plain Text My move toward plain text came about for several reasons.&#xA;First, I just wanted to take notes that I could quickly create and reference as needed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Naked by Brian Hoffman</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/book-review-naked/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/book-review-naked/</guid>
      <description>Naked by Brian Hoffman Overview In the acknowledgements, author and scholar Brian Hoffman notes that the idea for this book grew out of his own early experiences in a clothing optional home/community. He noted that as he grew older he became increasingly aware that what was normal in his own life was not nearly so normal for most others, at least in the US. It was, he suggests, that dichotomy between his experiences and the broader social order that led him to explore the history and influences on nudist life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confusing Fiction with Fact</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/confusing-fiction-with-fact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/confusing-fiction-with-fact/</guid>
      <description>Confusing Fiction with Fact I swear some people can&amp;rsquo;t keep track of reality.&#xA;While browsing Amazon for something to read in the vein of philosophy I ran across a book entitled The da Vinci Fraud: Why the Truth is Stranger than Fiction by Robert M. Price. The book purports to debunk the &amp;ldquo;many misleading claims found in Dan Brown&amp;rsquo;s Da Vinci Code&amp;rdquo; according to one reviewer. That statement and several others made by various reviewers suggest that somehow Brown was intending to provide accurate historical information regarding the Christian Church.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Wife Always Wanted to Marry a Pilot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/my-wife-always-wanted-to-marry-a-pilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/my-wife-always-wanted-to-marry-a-pilot/</guid>
      <description>My Wife Always Wanted to Marry a Pilot A Bit of Background I became interested in drones in the spring of 2021. My wife was preparing to retire from her teaching gig and considering a new career in real estate. After 15 years in our relatively small town in the mountains of North Georgia, we were planning a move to a little larger town with fewer challenging hills and more conveniences.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How We Encourage Cheating in Education</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/how-we-encourage-cheating-in-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/how-we-encourage-cheating-in-education/</guid>
      <description>How We Encourage Cheating in Education I was watching a news report this morning about students using ChatGPT that asked whether this was considered cheating. That got me to thinking about how we encourage cheating in education..&#xA;Think about it: The purpose for education is to provide the student with the foundational knowledge they need to be successful in work and life. We all want to be successful, so cheating to get there doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to me to be a very profitable endeavor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Think Crypto is Stupid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/why-i-think-crypto-is-stupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/why-i-think-crypto-is-stupid/</guid>
      <description>Why I Think Crypto is Stupid I recently read an article on Wired about Faruk Ozer, The CEO of Turkey&amp;rsquo;s biggest Cryptocurrency business. That article outlines how tens of thousands of Turkish people were victims of Ozer&amp;rsquo;s theft of their crypto wallets and all of their assets. The thing that stood out to me is how easy it was for him to simply download their accounts onto a thumb drive and be off with their money.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Thoughts on Competency Based Education</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/my-thoughts-on-competency-based-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/my-thoughts-on-competency-based-education/</guid>
      <description>My Thoughts on Competency Based Education Competency based education has gathered quite a lot of steam over the last few years. Many universities now assert that they are competency based and promote this as somehow better than traditional education. In general, it seems that competency based education is a way of expediting the educational process whereby the student can move forward more quickly so long as the student can demonstrate competence in a subject.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Don&#39;t Trust Gmail. Here&#39;s Why</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/i-dont-trust-gmail-heres-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/i-dont-trust-gmail-heres-why/</guid>
      <description>I Don&amp;rsquo;t Trust Gmail. Here&amp;rsquo;s Why. I have had an email address with Gmail for probably 20 years. I mean my email address is my name @ Gmail. No numbers, no weird abbreviations, no strange punctuations, just my firstnamelastname @gmail.com How long has it been since that was possible?&#xA;Three or four years ago I began receiving emails to my address that were clearly intended for another person with my same name.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Review - A Curious Mind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/book-review-a-curious-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/book-review-a-curious-mind/</guid>
      <description>A Curious Mind I am, and have always been, a curious person so when I saw this book at the book store I had no choice but to select it.&#xA;Curiosity is a driving force that pushes us to learn more, understand more, and to find or create new things. Curiosity is also the foundation for creativity, which is the premise for Brian Grazer&amp;rsquo;s book, &amp;ldquo;A Curious Mind&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;If the name sound familiar, but you can&amp;rsquo;t quite nail down his name, Brian is the producer of many hit movies, including Splash, Apollo 13, Friday Night Lights, and A Beautiful Life among many others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Noise by Daniel Kahneman</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/noise/</guid>
      <description>Noise By Daniel Kahnemnan Overview We often like to think that decision-makers use sound, rational judgment when making decisions. Using examples from the courtroom, Human Resources, insurance adjusters, and others, Kahneman and team show that, in fact, our judgments are strongly, and unconsciously, affected by a multitude of seemingly irrelevant factors such as the weather, how hunger the decision-maker is, and even whether the local sports team won their game over the prior weekend.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Almanack of Naval Ravikant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/almanack-naval-ravikant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/almanack-naval-ravikant/</guid>
      <description>I had never heard of Naval Ravikant until the book popped up in the search results for personal finance books on Amazon. Or wealth, I don&amp;rsquo;t really remember what that search term was!&#xA;In reality, this book is not about personal finance. Instead, it is a collection of thoughts by Naval Ravikant, a venture capitalist, founder or co-founder of several successful websites including the consumer reviews website Epinions.com, Angelist.com, producthunt.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Richest Man in Babylon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/richest-man-in-babylon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/richest-man-in-babylon/</guid>
      <description>George S. Clason&amp;rsquo;s The Richest Man in Babylon This book is not really a single book but a collection of short pamphlets that Mr. Clason, a businessman in the early 1900&amp;rsquo;s, wrote on the topic of financial success. Using parables set in ancient Babylonia, the pamphlets provide, generally, seven keys for becoming wealthy.&#xA;Although I quickly acknowledge that repetition of concepts aids in internalizing those ideas, I don&amp;rsquo;t usually care for books that include a lot of repetitive materialBecause the book is a collection of pamphlets, the same seven concepts, with the occasional additional idea thrown in, are repeated multiple times throughout the book using different characters and settings to convey the seven principles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Technology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/my-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/my-technology/</guid>
      <description>My Technology A common discussion in any of the technology forums is which platform is better. Some argue that Windows is best, others that Mac is and others, still, argue that Linux beats them all. What is my take? Well&amp;hellip; it depends.&#xA;###I am Operating System Agnostic&#xA;Truly, I am. I have all three operating systems in use in my home as I write this.&#xA;I started my technology back in 1984 or 1985 with a Commodore 128.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Returning to Basics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/returning-to-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/returning-to-basics/</guid>
      <description>Returning to Basics The title of this blog is iamcuri.us. That title was chosen to reflect the many and sundry interests that I have and the drive I have to explore new ideas and to learn new things. While I think some of my posts here have reflected that, others seems to skew in specific directions that seem to narrow the focus on the blog. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m wrong. Maybe the posts that outline my tinkering in websites and self-hosting do reflect my questioning and exploring and learning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My 2020 Reading List</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/my-2020-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/my-2020-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>My 2020 Reading List I set as a goal in 2020 the ambitious aim to complete 50 books over 52 weeks. I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite get there, but I did manage to complete 26. In addition, I read parts of four others and read probably a 100 or more journal and long-form magazine articles from a variety of sources. The four that I did not complete simply failed to sustain my interest.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Working from Home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/tips-for-working-from-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/tips-for-working-from-home/</guid>
      <description>Tips for Working from Home In response to the coronavirus, many employers have shifted as many workers as possible to teleworking. That is, working from home. This can be a real challenge if you&amp;rsquo;ve not had experience with working from home. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked from home for the last seven years, so I think I have some pretty reasonable suggestions to help you be successful while working from home and to help you ensure you have an appopriate balance between work and not-work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doing the Same Thing And ...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/doing-the-same-thing-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/doing-the-same-thing-and/</guid>
      <description>Doing the Same Thing And &amp;hellip; You&amp;rsquo;ve heard the saying &amp;ldquo;the definition insanity is doing the same thing over and over again and expecting a different result.&amp;rdquo; And I think you&amp;rsquo;ll agree that this &amp;lsquo;definition&amp;rsquo; is commonly true. But, what about those times when you do the same thing each and every time and get a different result? That, my friends, is the definition of randomness. And, it&amp;rsquo;s far more common than you think.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of an Academic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/he-evolution-of-an-academic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/he-evolution-of-an-academic/</guid>
      <description>The Evolution of an Academic Had someone told me on the day of my high school graduation in 1977 that I would one day be an academic, in possession of a doctoral degree and teaching at the university level, I&amp;rsquo;d have warned them that whatever they were smoking was muddling their brain. Yet, here I am, forty years later, in possession of not one, but two master&amp;rsquo;s degrees, and a doctorate, teaching at a university.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ONE THING</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/the-one-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/the-one-thing/</guid>
      <description>The ONE THING I love to read and love to learn, so it is no suprise that one of my favorite pastimes is to wander through bookstores. I love perusing the titles, skimming a few pages of those that interest me and maybe marking a few to add to my reading list. It&amp;rsquo;s a habit I developed probably thirty years ago.&#xA;One of the subject areas I generally skim is the business management section.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Wrong With Asking for a &#34;Highly Satisfied&#34; Rating</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/whats-wrong-with-asking-for-a-highly-satisfied-rating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/whats-wrong-with-asking-for-a-highly-satisfied-rating/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s Wrong with Asking for a &amp;ldquo;Highly Satisified&amp;rdquo; Rating? Virtually all businesses today are concerned about how the public perceives them. They recognize &amp;ndash; and rightfully so, in my opinion &amp;ndash; that customers who have a positive experience, who receive great service, or receive quality, tasty foods are more likely to be repeat customers. They also know that customers who have a poor experience are just as unlikely to return. Thus, measuring the customer experience by asking the customer to complete a survey of their experience is an important means for getting information on how well the company is doing in meeting the customers&amp;rsquo; needs and expectations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updates on Technology Projects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/updates-to-technology-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/updates-to-technology-projects/</guid>
      <description>Updates to Technology Projects I&amp;rsquo;ve had several technology projects running for a while now and thought it was time for an update.&#xA;Nextcloud, OnlyOffice, and the Like Back in February I set up a Nextcloud server and incorporated OnlyOffice. The concepts are pretty cool, but I have abandoned both of those projects. In all honesty, having completed my dissertation, I write so little that requires a word processor that I&amp;rsquo;ve not yet found a need for OnlyOffice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Science Fiction and the Polymath</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/science-fiction-and-the-polymath/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/science-fiction-and-the-polymath/</guid>
      <description>Science Fiction and the Polymath Throughout my junior high years I was a huge science fiction fan. One of my favorite authors of the time was Isaac Asimov. I was quite surprised to learn that Asimov not only wrote science fiction but had also penned books, short stories, and essays that ranged from religion (Guide to the Bible), chemistry (he was educated as a biochemist), engineering, and the list goes on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Me? A Manager? Not So Much</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/me-a-manager-not-so-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/me-a-manager-not-so-much/</guid>
      <description>Me? A Manager? Not so Much For the past year or so my manager has been after me to move into a management role. I managed to avoid doing so until fairly recently, using my work on my doctorate as an excuse for not really having the time to take on all the work of learning the role, learning the courses I would manage and so forth. Recently, however, I was approached again and, having all-but completed my degree, really didn&amp;rsquo;t have a good reason for</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Curiosity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/the-power-of-curiosity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/the-power-of-curiosity/</guid>
      <description>The Power of Curiosity I have always been a curious person. I&amp;rsquo;m the kid that took toys apart to see how they worked (and was sometimes able to put them back together again, too!) I was the kid that enjoyed reading the WorldBook Encyclopedia because, well, just because. Learning about different stuff fascinated me. Even as a very small child I was curious. My mother used to tell the story of the time when I was maybe 3 or 4 years old and came in crying because my eyes were filled with sand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nextcloud, OnlyOffice and the Like </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/nextcloud-onlyoffice-and-the-like/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/nextcloud-onlyoffice-and-the-like/</guid>
      <description>Nextcloud, OnlyOffice, and the Like Every once in a while I get this notion that I need to move my data off of sites like Dropbox, OneDrive, and so forth. When I do, I start playing around with self-hosted services such as NextCloud, OwnCloud, and so forth. I&amp;rsquo;m currently in one of those cycles and have been playing around a good bit with Nextcloud.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve even coupled it with OnlyOffice so that I can edit documents in the</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connecting the MacBook to the Edgerouter VPN</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/connecting-the-macbook-to-the-edgerouter-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/connecting-the-macbook-to-the-edgerouter-vpn/</guid>
      <description>Connecting the MacBook to the Edgerouter VPN Today I fixed a problem that has vexed me for some time. Reading through the search pages, it seems it has vexed quite a few others, as well. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share my solution to this problem so that others might benefit.&#xA;What&amp;rsquo;s the problem? I&amp;rsquo;ve setup a VPN server on my Ubiquiti Edgerouter-X. The VPN works great with my Windows clients, but I&amp;rsquo;ve not been able to get my MacBook or iPhone to connect.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Progress ... Slowly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/making-progress-slowly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/making-progress-slowly/</guid>
      <description>Making Progress &amp;hellip; Slowly There has been a lot going on the last few months. I have been struggling to get my dissertation done. The biggest obstacle has been locating participants for a qualitative study. I finally got responses to my recruiting efforts and have been able to interview 7 people. That&amp;rsquo;s not a great response, but is better than nothing (which is what I had in the past!)&#xA;and allows me to move forward.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving to a Self-Hosted Bookmarking Service</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/moving-to-a-self-hosted-bookmarking-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/moving-to-a-self-hosted-bookmarking-service/</guid>
      <description>Moving to a Self-Hosted Bookmarking Service There&amp;rsquo;s a hint that bookmarks are going away. Services like Delicious that used to provide great web-based book marking services have closed down. In their place are the likes of Instapaper and Pinboard and the like that break stuff into different types. Instapaper to store sites that you want to read later, Pinterest for images you like, and so forth. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t work well for me, though.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Education Relevant?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/is-education-relevant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/is-education-relevant/</guid>
      <description>Is Education Relevant One of the questions with which I have wrestled for a while now is the question of what it means to be ‘educated’. The problem, of course, is that there is no one definition and that, I think, creates much of the problem in evaluating educational programs. The state of Georgia recently put on the ballot a bill that would create an “Opportunity School District”. In an effort to address “failing” schools, the state proposed taking them over and doing whatever is necessary to ‘improve’ outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Learning the Challenges of Jekyll</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/learning-the-challenges-of-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/learning-the-challenges-of-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Learning the Challenges of Jekyll So a few days ago I decided to use Jekyll to generate a static website to host all &amp;ndash; well, most &amp;ndash; of my writing. Jekyll, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, is a different beast from most applications used for these purposes. I&amp;rsquo;ve found several themes that I really liked, but they all had some sort of quirks that made them less easy to use. I&amp;rsquo;m finding, though, that &amp;ldquo;easy to use&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Jekyll&amp;rdquo; probably don&amp;rsquo;t belong in the same sentence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Getting Started with Ham Radio</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/getting-started-with-ham-radio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/getting-started-with-ham-radio/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started with Ham Radio One of the goals on my bucket list has been getting my Ham radio license. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember, really, when it first landed on my list. I was a teen and it most likely was the result of some movie I saw or book I read that extolled the use and excitement of reaching out to the world through radio. The desire wasn&amp;rsquo;t helped, I&amp;rsquo;m sure, by having an uncle that got into it after he retired.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weewx on the Raspberry PI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/weewx-on-the-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/weewx-on-the-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>Weewx on the Raspberry Pi I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved gadgets. When the first Raspberry Pis came out a few years ago, I was pretty confident that eventually, I&amp;rsquo;d get one. About three years ago I decided I wanted to build a media server and the RPI seemed the perfect tool for the job. While it works, it didn&amp;rsquo;t do all that I had hoped. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t the device&amp;rsquo;s fault; the software just didn&amp;rsquo;t quite match up with my particular use case.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life Long Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/life-long-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/life-long-learning/</guid>
      <description>Life Long Learning One of the &amp;lsquo;goals&amp;rsquo; of the nursing department is that we develop &amp;rsquo;life long learners&amp;rsquo;. What this means, I suppose is up for some debate but I think, generally, that what is meant is that we prepare our students to learn how to identify their professional learning needs and help them develop the skills needed to meet those on-going needs. After all, health care is an ever-evolving field and constant learning is required.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changes in my Weather Station</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/changes-in-my-weather-station/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/changes-in-my-weather-station/</guid>
      <description>Changes in my Weather Station For the past 8 years I&amp;rsquo;ve managed a personal weather station consisting of a Davis Vantagse Pro and a Windows computer running the excellent Weather Display software. Last December I decided that the inexpensive computer I was running the scripts on may well be coming to its end-of-life and went looking for alternatives. Another goal of this move was to lower my cost of operations. The Jetway computer I was running didn&amp;rsquo;t use a lot of power, perhaps 25 W, but if I could do better, I would.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogging with Jekyll</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/blogging-with-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/blogging-with-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Blogging with Jekyll Over the past nearly 10 years I&amp;rsquo;ve tried numerous times to maintain a blog. I enjoy writing and figured it would be a good way not only to practice the skill, but to share my thoughts with others. I don&amp;rsquo;t really care whether anyone reads my work, to be honest; I just want to write. The problem is that, while I don&amp;rsquo;t care so much if I&amp;rsquo;m read, I do want to be able to keep my files and refer back to them from time to time &amp;ndash; something of a journal (which is what the blog was originally conceived to be).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing your Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/designing-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/designing-your-life/</guid>
      <description>Designing Your Life I &amp;lsquo;attended&amp;rsquo; a presentation by Story Musgrave, the astronaut, on &amp;ldquo;Designing your life&amp;rdquo; or some such similar topic. While I wasn&amp;rsquo;t overly impressed with his general rambling presentation style, I was very impressed with the message that threaded throughout his story. I took several keys away from the presentation.&#xA;The value of curiosity The first takeaway was the importance of curiosity in achieving an effective life. From high school drop out, he went on to earn a BS in math and statistics, MBA in operations analysis and computer programming, BA in chemistry, MD, and MS in physiology and biophysics within an 8 year period.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Thoughts on Philosophy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/some-thoughts-on-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/some-thoughts-on-philosophy/</guid>
      <description>Some Thoughts on Philosophy So, I&amp;rsquo;ll begin this treatise with a question: What is philosophy? And perhaps another, just to follow on that, why is philosophy important?&#xA;To take things in order, my simple answer to the question of what is philosophy is to say that it is, generally, the creed by which one lives one&amp;rsquo;s life. I think the dominance of big names in the field &amp;ndash; Nietzsche, Hume, Watts Marx, and so many others &amp;ndash; and the deep, convoluted and difficult writings that these big names have produced have left most people with the impression that philosophy requires deep, almost mystical thought on very esoteric subjects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Social Filters Impact an Educated Response</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/how-social-filters-impact-an-educated-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/how-social-filters-impact-an-educated-response/</guid>
      <description>How Social Filters Impact an Educated Response One of the hallmarks of the well-educated person is, I think, the ability and willingness to explore all sides of an issue before making a decision. Unfortunately, it seems that few people, even those who are, in fact, well-educated, truly take the time to explore an issue before taking a stance on it. And, to a large extent, I get it. It’s hard to do.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The First Thing Every College Should Do For Its Students</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/the-first-thing-every-college-should-do-for-its-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/the-first-thing-every-college-should-do-for-its-students/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-first-thing-every-college-should-do-for-its-students&#34;&gt;The First Thing Every College Should Do For Its Students&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For some time now I’ve argued that colleges and universities have dropped the ball on one of the most important preparatory steps in attending college: Defining what a college education is all about.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Students often go to college without a clear conception of what they’re supposed to be getting from the experience.  They go because college has become the “thing you do” after high school.  Like their secondary education, they never really stop to think about why they’re going, or what the benefits are. More importantly, many students see college as simply an extension of their secondary education. That is, learning without an express purpose other than “I’ll need to know this someday.” &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> No, In Fact I Don&#39;t Like Social Media</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/no-in-fact-i-dont-like-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/no-in-fact-i-dont-like-social-media/</guid>
      <description>#No, In Fact I Don&amp;rsquo;t Like Social Media&#xA;Well, the title really says it all: I don’t like social media. The reasons, though, need some explanation.&#xA;I believe that social interaction and the sharing of ideas is an important part of life and, particularly, of learning. Engaging in thoughtful, thought-provoking conversations allows us to to explore more fully our own thinking, to consider the thoughts of others, and find in the mix a fuller, more well-developed sense of the world around us.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fault of Not Reading</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/the-fault-of-not-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/the-fault-of-not-reading/</guid>
      <description>The Fault of Not Reading I love to read. That’s a good thing, since I do quite a lot of it. After four years of forced reading as I progressed, first through my Masters degree and then the first three years of my doctorate, you’d think that I’d be tired of reading. Surprisingly, not only have I not grown tired of it, but I actually derive great pleasure from it. Still.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Long Time Coming</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/a-long-time-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/a-long-time-coming/</guid>
      <description>A Long Time Coming It’s been quite a while since I posted anything here. I’ve been quite busy working through the remainder of my didactics, writing (and passing) my comprehensive exams, and beginning work on my prospectus. But, I’m back trying to regain some semblance of order in my life that includes sharing some of my ideas, thoughts, and observations on nursing, education, and a various sundry other things. How Did I Get Here?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of a Degree</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/the-meaning-of-a-degree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/the-meaning-of-a-degree/</guid>
      <description>The Meaning of a Degree The reasons why they may choose to do this are myriad. For some students, the BSN has long been a personal goal. For others, though, the decision isn’t internally motivated. Rather, they’re faced with either obtaining their BSN, or finding other employment. Now, for anyone outside of nursing, that latter reason might seem a bit harsh. But for those of us in the profession, it makes sense – at least to a degree.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Time Flies!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/how-time-flies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/how-time-flies/</guid>
      <description>How Time Flies Okay, granted not the most original title, but the fact is I really didn’t realize it had been nearly four months since my last post. If you read that one, though, you might be inclined to forgive me — I’ve been a bit busy. But, today those crazy hours are behind me and only a single paper remains between me and the end of the term.&#xA;There has been so much that has captured my interest this term that I’ve simply not been able to write about.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technology For Its Own Sake</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/technology-for-its-own-sake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/technology-for-its-own-sake/</guid>
      <description>Technology For It&amp;rsquo;s Own Sake About eight years ago I spent a couple of years teaching high school. Being a nurse, and coming into the experience with no real educational background it was quite an interesting, and eye-opening experience. Needless to say, I probably learned more than my students did. One of the things that left me scratching my head was the approach the school system took toward education. Tons of money was spent on technology and teachers were required to have at least one “technology lesson” each week.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is it for Education or Business?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/is-it-for-education-or-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/is-it-for-education-or-business/</guid>
      <description>Is it for Education or Business? In the early 1990’s as I was preparing to wrap up my MBA I was informed by my advisor that I still needed to take a basic statistics course. Now, that would seem a reasonable expectation were it not for the fact that I had already completed two advanced statistics courses. Being a bit obstinate, I asked why it was necessary for me to take a course designed to prepare me for courses that I had already taken and passed (quite well, I might add.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Education &#34;All That&#34;?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/is-education-all-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/is-education-all-that/</guid>
      <description>Is Education &amp;ldquo;All That&amp;rdquo; I had a wonderful opportunity to talk with a woman(we’ll call her Jane) who has accomplished several things that I have only dreamed of. She has developed a new approach to an old and vexing problem many nurses face, she contributed to the development of a new medical device, she has been published in peer-reviewed journals, and has spoken around the world before thousands of people to introduce other professionals to both her new technique and to the medical device.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The State of the MOOC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/the-state-of-the-mooc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/the-state-of-the-mooc/</guid>
      <description>The State of the MOOC Two recent articles about Massive Open Online Courses (MOOC) got my attention this week.&#xA;Fail? The first article brings to the fore the reality that only about 7% of those who start a MOOC course complete it. This is, of course, a major concern for educators, given that completion rates are the major metric for colleges. It is completely understandable that many would see that number and conclude that MOOCs are failing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So, What&#39;s This Site All About?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/so-whats-this-site-all-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/so-whats-this-site-all-about/</guid>
      <description>So, What&amp;rsquo;s This Site All About? Hello, and welcome to my little corner of the web … yes, I know that’s a bit cliché but … well, what can I say?&#xA;Anyway, I am a doctoral student in Education (Nursing education to be precise) and have decided to use a blogging platform as a means for storing ideas and thoughts related to topics that might be useful as I move toward my dissertation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt; ALMANACK OF NAVAL RAVIKANT tags: - 📚Book - review title: ALMANACK OF NAVAL RAVIKANT author: - Eric Jorgenson publisher: Harper Business publish: 2021 total: 0 isbn: 9354893899 9789354893896 cover: http://books.google.com/books/content?id=0jxbzwEACAAJ&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;img=1&amp;amp;zoom=1&amp;amp;source=gbs_api status: read created: - 2024-03-09 13:20:49 updated: 2024-03-09 13:20:49CopyALMANACK OF NAVAL RAVIKANT&#xA;[]&#xA;I had never heard of Naval Ravikant until the book popped up in the search results for personal finance books on Amazon. Or wealth, I don&#39;t really remember what that search term was!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/posts/tags/</guid>
      <description>Tags </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/about/</guid>
      <description>Who am I? That is the quintessential Existential question, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? Who am I?&#xA;I read somewhere years ago that we here in the US tend to answer that question by saying what career we&amp;rsquo;re engaged in: I am a nurse. I am an engineer. I am a salesman. And so on. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t really tell anyone who you are, it simply tells them how you make your living. What about those of us who are retired?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/projects/</guid>
      <description>In this section I will be sharing the projects I&amp;rsquo;m working on and the things that I have learned along the way.&#xA;As you can see, though, I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet started building this section &amp;hellip; hang tight&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve got projects in the works, I&amp;rsquo;m just not ready to write them up yet.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
