<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ham Radio on Kevin&#39;s Corner of the Web</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ham-radio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ham Radio on Kevin&#39;s Corner of the Web</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ham-radio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title> Getting Started with Ham Radio</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/getting-started-with-ham-radio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/getting-started-with-ham-radio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;getting-started-with-ham-radio&#34;&gt;Getting Started with Ham Radio&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the goals on my bucket list has been getting my Ham radio license.  I
don&amp;rsquo;t remember, really, when it first landed on my list.  I was a teen and it
most likely was the result of some movie I saw or book I read that extolled the
use and excitement of reaching out to the world through radio. The desire wasn&amp;rsquo;t
helped, I&amp;rsquo;m sure, by having an uncle that got into it after he retired.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;getting-started-with-ham-radio&#34;&gt;Getting Started with Ham Radio&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the goals on my bucket list has been getting my Ham radio license.  I
don&amp;rsquo;t remember, really, when it first landed on my list.  I was a teen and it
most likely was the result of some movie I saw or book I read that extolled the
use and excitement of reaching out to the world through radio. The desire wasn&amp;rsquo;t
helped, I&amp;rsquo;m sure, by having an uncle that got into it after he retired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Times have changed, of course, and where once amateur radio was the only  means
for
contacting the world beyond my community, the internet has made huge inroads in
that domain.  In fact, one does have to ask why get a license? As I began to
ponder that question I began to realize that it is less for the excitement and
mystique of reaching out to others far away and more about simple
accomplishment.  Earning a license requires that I gain the necessary knowledge.&lt;br&gt;
After all, if it was only about communicating with others, I could do that with
the
internet or family radios (FRS) or, if I &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to have a license, a General
Mobile Radio Service license.  No knowledge required.  But it&amp;rsquo;s about learning
the basics of electronics, of radio waves, and the rules that govern their use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about lately is the range of knowledge that
we all carry around that we don&amp;rsquo;t really recognize or appreciate.  As it turns
out, as I started to study for the exam I began to realize how much knowledge I
already had in this domain.  I already understand the basics of electronic
circuits, for example, In fact, I took a couple of practice tests and the only
real areas I failed were those related to the rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m excited to get started on this bucket list item.  I may never actually do
much with the license, but going through that process is important for me to
meet a bucket list goal and to have the option to use amateur radio when, and
if, I choose to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And options are always good.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
