<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General on Kevin&#39;s Corner of the Web</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General on Kevin&#39;s Corner of the Web</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Am I on &#34;The Spectrum&#34;?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/am-i-on-the-spectrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/am-i-on-the-spectrum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past ten years I have worked from home.  Although I interacted regularly with students and other faculty, those interactions generally took place by email (my preferred method) or, when interactivity was required, by phone, Teams, or Zoom. Actual face-to-face interaction was very limited.  I liked it that way for, as odd as it may seem, I don&amp;rsquo;t actually like dealing with people directly.  I say that&amp;rsquo;s odd because I have spent my entire career in a field that required not only face-to-face interaction but, as a nurse,  often that interaction  required intimate contact with others. And, while I did need to interact on a one-to-one level in the hospital, teaching allowed me to interact with students on a more generic level. Speaking to a class or conducting on on-line lesson is easier and less stressful for me than meeting one on one with an individual.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;For the past ten years I have worked from home.  Although I interacted regularly with students and other faculty, those interactions generally took place by email (my preferred method) or, when interactivity was required, by phone, Teams, or Zoom. Actual face-to-face interaction was very limited.  I liked it that way for, as odd as it may seem, I don&amp;rsquo;t actually like dealing with people directly.  I say that&amp;rsquo;s odd because I have spent my entire career in a field that required not only face-to-face interaction but, as a nurse,  often that interaction  required intimate contact with others. And, while I did need to interact on a one-to-one level in the hospital, teaching allowed me to interact with students on a more generic level. Speaking to a class or conducting on on-line lesson is easier and less stressful for me than meeting one on one with an individual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;stress-stress-and-more-stress&#34;&gt;Stress, Stress, and More Stress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dealing with others face-to-face has always been a struggle for me.  I hate parties and other gatherings where I&amp;rsquo;m required to &amp;lsquo;socialize&amp;rsquo; and make small talk.  I never learned how!  I struggled to make sense of the social cues that others seems to intuitively understand.  I never felt that I fit in.  Any kind of social situation generated significant stress for me and so I tried to avoid it them whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have dealt with high stress levels since my early twenties (and perhaps before, I just don&amp;rsquo;t remember).  Near constant headaches and Gastroesophageal Reflux disease (GERD) or acid indigestion, have plagued me since at least age 20.  Depression negatively influenced much of my life.  Since I began working from home where I have very limited interaction with others, however, both of those issues, and others related to stress, have abated.  Headaches are rare and while I still have GERD (thanks to a hiatal hernia), I am no longer keeping TUMS in business.  Clearly my social anxiety was at the heart of my stress issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;and-a-bit-of-adhd-didnt-help&#34;&gt;And, a Bit of ADHD Didn&amp;rsquo;t Help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve known for some time that I have &amp;lsquo;controlled&amp;rsquo; ADHD.  What I mean by controlled is that over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve learned some coping strategies to help me manage some of the issues around ADHD.  I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, for example, how to focus for short periods of time on some task and, at the same time, how not to hyperfocus on tasks.  What do I mean by hyperfocus?  Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve been known to spend 16 - 18 hours a day working on a project, forgetting to eat, ignoring family, and so on because I was so focused in on what I was doing. But while I sometimes experience hyperfocus, I also have issues finishing projects that I start.  One of the key characteristics of an ADHD person is to become highly excited by a project then dig in, taking a project to, say, 80% complete, then losing interest.  That&amp;rsquo;s me.  It&amp;rsquo;s why I have at least two partial master&amp;rsquo;s degrees.  I got to a certain point and simply lost interest, distracted by some other new, shiny topic that captured my attention.  I have an FCC license as an amateur radio operator and spent a couple of thousand dollars on radios, though I don&amp;rsquo;t actually get on the radio (in fact, I don&amp;rsquo;t currently have any radios  set up for use.)  I hold an FAA certificate as a drone pilot, and own a drone though I seldom fly. I have photography and video equipment that sits idle because I became highly interested in those fields only to let them fall to the wayside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ah-growing-up-adhd-before-adhd-was-a-thing&#34;&gt;Ah, Growing Up ADHD Before ADHD was a Thing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up in the 60&amp;rsquo;s and 70&amp;rsquo;s the concept of ADHD was not really well recognized.  I was a behavior problem in class.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t finish (or sometimes start) assignments. I forgot things.  I was easily distracted and occasionally disruptive in class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some testing (who knows what kind since there was no testing for ADHD at the time), my high distractibility was attributed to boredom.  It was thought that I tended to grasp things quickly so that I became bored in the classroom.  Apparently they thought I was smart even though I was, and am, pretty average. But I also didn&amp;rsquo;t do well on the playground.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t make friends easily. I was a poor, mildly uncoordinated athlete, so I was always one of the last ones picked for teams. I was different, though exactly how, I can&amp;rsquo;t say (it&amp;rsquo;s been more than 50 years, you know!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now lest you think that I am self-diagnosing (I&amp;rsquo;ll get to that shortly) I was actually professionally tested in the late 90&amp;rsquo;s, while in my mid-thirties, and officially diagnosed with ADHD, though I had  developed compensatory skills which lessened its impact on me. I think there was some hesitance in assigning that diagnosis, given the masking behaviors I had developed. Looking back, though, I think part of that hesitancy may have been that adult ADHD wasn&amp;rsquo;t well recognized. I was tested in 1997, just three years after ADHD was added to the DSM-III as a legitimate diagnosis for adults&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;enter-the-spectrum&#34;&gt;Enter the Spectrum&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In more recent years I have come to realize that, in addition to ADHD,  I may be somewhere on the Autistic spectrum.  Why do I say that?  Well, let&amp;rsquo;s go back to that comment about hating social events.  The primary reason I hate social events is that I could never figure out how to interact with others, to make small talk.  Maintaining a conversation&amp;rsquo;s flow has always been a challenge. I struggled to read the social clues that others provide.  I was known for saying things that, to me, were reasonable but were, to others,  apparently insensitive or rude.  It wasn&amp;rsquo;t intentional; I just didn&amp;rsquo;t recognize the problem.  Years of practice has led to some improvement in that area, but given the option to attend a social event or not, I&amp;rsquo;ll choose &amp;ldquo;not&amp;rdquo; every time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole social avoidance thing was a conundrum for my ex-wife.  You see, I was working as a nurse and always interacted well with my patients.  My wife was confused because I could be quite outgoing with my patients, in contrast to other social scenarios. She wanted to go to parties and visit with people and all the other social things people do.  I generally refrained from going with her.  The reason, as I explained to her one time, is because the work environment is a stage.  I know the script, I know the bounds of the stage, I know the limits of the storyline.  I don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about small talk, per se, because the situation defined the conversation. But, when I&amp;rsquo;m in an uncontrolled social situation, I don&amp;rsquo;t understand the rules.  I don&amp;rsquo;t know the limits and don&amp;rsquo;t have a script to follow.  I said this, by the way, in the presence of a counselor who clearly did not recognize the signs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of wives and other relationships, I often failed to discern the needs and wants of others.  Well, that&amp;rsquo;s not exactly true. I could &lt;em&gt;sometimes&lt;/em&gt; discern their needs and wants, but not often.  As a consequence,  I tended to act on my own interests, without really being aware of others&amp;rsquo; interests. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily self-absorbed, though I think I came across that way, nor was I necessarily insensitive or uncaring.  I just honestly didn&amp;rsquo;t understand what others needed.  To that end, gift giving was a challenge because I could never determine what my wife  or kids might want.  The choices I made, though well intentioned, were seldom met with much appreciation.  I actually warned my current wife that she would need to be specific in what she would like because it wasn&amp;rsquo;t in my wheelhouse to &amp;lsquo;devine&amp;rsquo; these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another common trait of autism is sudden, intense bouts of anger. What many call meltdowns.  Well, that was me as a child and even today I struggle to deal with frustration without over reacting or becoming angry and even, at times, violent, though that violence is not aimed at people. My desk has taken quite a beating over the years, however. Anger is sometimes associated with the frustration of trying to manage multiple tasks.  That earlier evaluation noted exactly that type of behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I dug into the topic, I learned &amp;lsquo;stimming&amp;rsquo; is a common behavior and can take many forms.  For me, this seems to be constant leg movements as well as picking at my skin, particularly my scalp.  This is actually a behavior that I had not associated with anything other than mindless responses to itching.  The problem being, of course, that I didn&amp;rsquo;t always itch!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then let&amp;rsquo;s talk about impulse control. Although I am much better now, having developed some masking behaviors, I still have issues at times with impulse control.  What I mean is jumping into the middle of conversations, interrupting others, and so on while talking with others.  Doing things out of sequence or before they should be done because I&amp;rsquo;m impatient and want to get going.  Acting before thinking in some cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-first-inkling-that-something-wasnt-right&#34;&gt;My First Inkling that Something Wasn&amp;rsquo;t Right&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the issues I&amp;rsquo;ve related are seen in hindsight.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t recognize them at the time, nor did anyone else, apparently.  It would be many, many years later before I really began to put the pieces together. And, though I didn&amp;rsquo;t know it at the time, perhaps the first hint that something was amiss was when, as a teenager I began working in a grocery store.  One day one of the guys I worked with asked my why I never looked him in the eye.  He noted that I always looked &lt;em&gt;between&lt;/em&gt; his eyes as he pointed to his glabella (skin just above the nose where the eyebrows meet).  It was a behavior that I had not known I was doing.  Yet, the inability to look others in the eye is a common trait of ASD, though I didn&amp;rsquo;t know it at the time. Having him point it out to me, of course, made me conscious of it and I made a concerted effort to make eye contact. I still struggle with it sometimes, particularly with people I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given what I know (I haven&amp;rsquo;t divulged &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; my secrets!) about myself and about autism, I suspect that I&amp;rsquo;m somewhere on the spectrum.  In fact, I recently took several online screening tests all of which suggested I seek professional help.  Now, I admit that having done some reading on the topic I have a general sense of what answers lead to that outcome and this may bias those tests.  Still, looking at my history and combining that with those assessments gives me a fairly good idea that my suspicion is correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, am I self-diagnosing?  Yes. Do I believe I am autistic? Probably. Am I going to get tested so that I have an official diagnosis?  No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting an actual diagnosis, particularly as an older adult is both expensive and challenging.  I&amp;rsquo;ve had 60+ years of experience in developing compensatory mechanisms and masking behaviors for dealing with the challenges I face. As a healthcare provider and educator, I&amp;rsquo;ve also learned what the expected responses are, so, there&amp;rsquo;s some question as to how accurate any diagnostic testing would be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-next-steps&#34;&gt;My Next Steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More to the point, what would be the benefit?  Will a diagnosis change how I do things?  Will it lead to some magical improvements?  The answer to those questions is &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo;.  There&amp;rsquo;s no magic bullet to treat the issues.  It comes down to making a concerted effort to face those challenges and put myself in uncomfortable situations in order to develop those skills that are lacking.  Or, alternately, to embrace my difference and live my life in a way that is consistent with my needs and preferences so that I don&amp;rsquo;t feel anxious and stressed.  I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen, for the most part, this second path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, why have I written this?  Well, mostly to explore my own thinking (which is the motivation for much of my writing) and to perhaps stimulate others to take a close look at themselves and their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.columbiapsychiatry.org/news/effort-underway-develop-first-u-s-guidelines-adhd-adults&#34;&gt;https://www.columbiapsychiatry.org/news/effort-underway-develop-first-u-s-guidelines-adhd-adults&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Right Tool for the Job</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-01-using-the-right-tool-for-the-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-01-using-the-right-tool-for-the-job/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;using-the-right-tool-for-the-job&#34;&gt;Using the Right Tool for the Job&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the late 1980&amp;rsquo;s, when I first began working with computers, there were a fairly wide variety of devices and OSes from which to choose.  TRS-80, Commodore (I had the C-128), MS-Dos based PCs, Apple, Amiga, and so on.  The challenge was to determine which device worked best for your intended use.  DOS based PCs were best for office type work, Apple was the choice if you were doing multimedia, Amiga for gaming, etc.  While you &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; do anything on most of those devices, each had particular strengths and weaknesses.  The question you faced in making a purchase was, &amp;ldquo;which device is best for what I want to do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;using-the-right-tool-for-the-job&#34;&gt;Using the Right Tool for the Job&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the late 1980&amp;rsquo;s, when I first began working with computers, there were a fairly wide variety of devices and OSes from which to choose.  TRS-80, Commodore (I had the C-128), MS-Dos based PCs, Apple, Amiga, and so on.  The challenge was to determine which device worked best for your intended use.  DOS based PCs were best for office type work, Apple was the choice if you were doing multimedia, Amiga for gaming, etc.  While you &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; do anything on most of those devices, each had particular strengths and weaknesses.  The question you faced in making a purchase was, &amp;ldquo;which device is best for what I want to do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure there were folks who asked why a particular device didn&amp;rsquo;t do &amp;ldquo;such-and-so&amp;rdquo; but, for the most part, it was understood that different platforms had different options. Despite having been adopted by businesses early on (Thanks, IBM) the MS-DOS PC didn&amp;rsquo;t have a spreadsheet program.  The first spreadsheet, VisiCalc, was introduced on the Apple, so if a business wanted to leverage that application, they invested in an Apple machine, they didn&amp;rsquo;t carp about VisiCalc not being available on the PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today the industry has pretty well consolidated in a way that blurs the lines between the various devices and their OSes.  Many of the manufacturers of computers have evaporated and their OSes have disappeared.  What remains are really three major  players (Windows, Mac OS, and Linux) and one minor player (BSD), along with a few &amp;ldquo;also rans&amp;rdquo; (Haiku, BeOS, etc). These are centered around two primary hardware platforms &amp;ndash; Apple, and everything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work primarily with Mac OS, though I also have numerous Linux and even BSD machines.  Linux and BSD are used for what they&amp;rsquo;re best suited for &amp;ndash; servers. My Mac OS devices are my daily drivers and what I use for web browsing, email, writing, tracking finances, etc. The Mac is also what I do video and photo editing on. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say that I don&amp;rsquo;t do Linux (or BSD) desktop &amp;ndash; I do.  I just don&amp;rsquo;t currently use those desktops regularly. And the reason is rather mundane: the M2 Mac Mini is what sits on my desktop and my Intel Macbook Air (2020 model) is what lives in the living room for quick browsing when I&amp;rsquo;m not at my desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do own a Windows 10 device, though it generally sits on a shelf, waiting to be turned on for those rare occasions when I have no other option because the software I need is only available on Windows (PlayOn TV, for example).   Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss my reasons for avoiding Windows at some later date. Or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I noted in an earlier post I have begun exploring FreeBSD.  Anytime you&amp;rsquo;re learning a new system, program, service, etc. you tend to peruse the forums and message boards for hints, tips, and answers to specific issues you encounter.  One of the topics that seems to come up frequently, not only on the BSD boards, but Linux, as well, is why a particular OS doesn&amp;rsquo;t support a particular device (wireless, printer, whatever) or piece of software.  There are folks that seem to think that Adobe ought to be available on Linux. Or Microsoft Office.  Or whatever specific piece of software they want.  And it&amp;rsquo;s a whine that I don&amp;rsquo;t understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the complaints I&amp;rsquo;ve read about FreeBSD is that it lacks certain &amp;ldquo;vital&amp;rdquo; pieces of software.  Of course what is &amp;ldquo;vital&amp;rdquo; to you may not be vital to me, so that whole complaint is a bit subjective. But, from what I&amp;rsquo;ve read there are some 28,000 programs available for FreeBSD.  Surely there&amp;rsquo;s a program in that bunch that will meet your needs.  Now, I admit that my needs are not that big, but I have had no problem locating and installing every application I need to do my daily work in either the packages or ports for FreeBSD. Scanning the ports lists, I am absolutely astonished at the wide range of applications that are available, including quite a few that I would consider rather arcane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen the same complaint levied against various Linux distributions, along with complaints of difficulty in installing them.  These complaints generally come, it seems to me, from folks that are trying to move from Windows to Linux and expecting the exact same experience.  Reminds me of those House Hunter International folks that move from the US to Lithuania for the &amp;ldquo;experience&amp;rdquo; then complain that housing in Vilnius (the capital of Lithuania) is not the same as in the US.  The kitchen is smaller, the rooms are smaller, there is no oven, there&amp;rsquo;s no expansive yard, etc.  When you move to a different country, you should expect significant differences in how the people in your new home live and what conveniences are available.  That&amp;rsquo;s the experience you came to have. When you move to a different OS you should expect differences in how the systems work and what software is available.  If there were no differences then there would be no reason to move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that kind of brings me back to my topic. If you&amp;rsquo;re wanting to get work done, you choose the best tool for the job.  You might be able to drive a nail in with a screwdriver, but it won&amp;rsquo;t be easy and it won&amp;rsquo;t be pretty.  You might be able to get your work done in Linux, but if your work relies on some specific software which is not available in Linux, then Linux is not the best tool for the job.  Stick with Windows.  Don&amp;rsquo;t whine that the Windows-only application &amp;ldquo;W&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is not available in Linux.  Stick with Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if you&amp;rsquo;re curious about Linux and want to see what applications are available or what Linux (or BSD) applications might be acceptable alternatives to Windows applications, by all means install and explore Linux (or BSD). Take your time. Explore widely and deeply.  You might just find that there is an alternative that is as good as, and perhaps better than, the Windows version.  Then you can jump out of Windows and into something more interesting, more challenging, and more fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was gonna us &amp;ldquo;X&amp;rdquo; but since that&amp;rsquo;s now the new name of Twitter, the argument didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confusing Fiction with Fact</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/confusing-fiction-with-fact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/confusing-fiction-with-fact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;confusing-fiction-with-fact&#34;&gt;Confusing Fiction with Fact&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I swear some people can&amp;rsquo;t keep track of reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While browsing Amazon for something to read in the vein of philosophy I ran across a book entitled &lt;em&gt;The da Vinci Fraud: Why the Truth is Stranger than Fiction&lt;/em&gt; by Robert M. Price.  The book purports to debunk the &amp;ldquo;many misleading claims found in Dan Brown&amp;rsquo;s Da Vinci Code&amp;rdquo; according to one reviewer.  That statement and several others made by various &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;reviewers suggest that somehow Brown was intending to provide accurate historical information regarding the Christian Church.  Funny, having read &lt;em&gt;The Da Vinci Code&lt;/em&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t recall Brown ever claiming that the book was historically accurate.  For someone to take the time to write a book to refute claims that were never made seems, well, stupid. Apparently, Mr. Price (or I should say Doctor Price, given his PhD) has difficulty comprehending that fiction is by definition not fact.  Fiction writers often base their works on some variation of an idea or concept and follow the &amp;ldquo;what if&amp;rdquo; process. That is, &amp;ldquo;what if&amp;rdquo; there really is an Opus Dei &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; with sinister underpinnings?  &amp;ldquo;What if&amp;rdquo; Jesus and Mary Magdalene really did have a child together? and so on.  Fiction writers take some fact and embroider it with the lace needed to paint an enticing picture that tells an entertaining story.  Few set out to present history (or any other topic) factually.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;confusing-fiction-with-fact&#34;&gt;Confusing Fiction with Fact&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I swear some people can&amp;rsquo;t keep track of reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While browsing Amazon for something to read in the vein of philosophy I ran across a book entitled &lt;em&gt;The da Vinci Fraud: Why the Truth is Stranger than Fiction&lt;/em&gt; by Robert M. Price.  The book purports to debunk the &amp;ldquo;many misleading claims found in Dan Brown&amp;rsquo;s Da Vinci Code&amp;rdquo; according to one reviewer.  That statement and several others made by various &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;reviewers suggest that somehow Brown was intending to provide accurate historical information regarding the Christian Church.  Funny, having read &lt;em&gt;The Da Vinci Code&lt;/em&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t recall Brown ever claiming that the book was historically accurate.  For someone to take the time to write a book to refute claims that were never made seems, well, stupid. Apparently, Mr. Price (or I should say Doctor Price, given his PhD) has difficulty comprehending that fiction is by definition not fact.  Fiction writers often base their works on some variation of an idea or concept and follow the &amp;ldquo;what if&amp;rdquo; process. That is, &amp;ldquo;what if&amp;rdquo; there really is an Opus Dei &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; with sinister underpinnings?  &amp;ldquo;What if&amp;rdquo; Jesus and Mary Magdalene really did have a child together? and so on.  Fiction writers take some fact and embroider it with the lace needed to paint an enticing picture that tells an entertaining story.  Few set out to present history (or any other topic) factually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love James Michener&amp;rsquo;s work. He has generated dozens of books that provide insight into the history of various regions (Alaska, Hawaii, the Caribbean, Spain, Poland, and on and on) but I would be fool to believe that his works are 100% historically accurate.  And, again, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that Michener ever set out for accuracy.  Having read almost all of his books, including his autobiography, I suspect that he simply found the process of researching and learning about these different regions interesting and consequently used that research to provide a foundation for his stories. His histories are painted in broad brush strokes that do give the flavor of that region&amp;rsquo;s history but are likely not completely accurate.  Does the lack of absolute historical accuracy diminish his work?  Not in my view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every writer writes through a particular lens and it&amp;rsquo;s especially important, I think, to remember that history is researched, interpreted, and written through the specific lens of that writer. Dr. Price may claim to present facts to refute Brown&amp;rsquo;s storyline (I can&amp;rsquo;t say for certain that he does since I&amp;rsquo;ve not read the book) but the reader must remember that Price&amp;rsquo;s account was interpreted and written through his own lens and may, therefore, be just as historically inaccurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m left scratching my head on why someone with a PhD would even consider Brown&amp;rsquo;s stories to be intended to be historically accurate.  They are simply works of fiction with some references to reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opus Dei is an organization officially recognized by the Catholic Church.  Brown&amp;rsquo;s depiction of the organization as somehow sinister is based, from what I can understand, on controversies surrounding the organization and its cult-like activities (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opus_Dei&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;)&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Wife Always Wanted to Marry a Pilot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-wife-always-wanted-to-marry-a-pilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-wife-always-wanted-to-marry-a-pilot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-wife-always-wanted-to-marry-a-pilot&#34;&gt;My Wife Always Wanted to Marry a Pilot&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-bit-of-background&#34;&gt;A Bit of Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I became interested in drones in the spring of 2021.  My wife was preparing to retire from her teaching gig and considering a new career in real estate.  After 15 years in our relatively small town in the mountains of North Georgia, we were planning a move to a little larger town with fewer challenging hills and more conveniences. We were building a new home in our soon-to-be new town.  This was, I thought, a great time &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;to explore my interest in drones.  After all, I could document the progress of our new home and, if she did go into real estate, I would be positioned to do some of her photography.  Win!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-wife-always-wanted-to-marry-a-pilot&#34;&gt;My Wife Always Wanted to Marry a Pilot&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-bit-of-background&#34;&gt;A Bit of Background&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I became interested in drones in the spring of 2021.  My wife was preparing to retire from her teaching gig and considering a new career in real estate.  After 15 years in our relatively small town in the mountains of North Georgia, we were planning a move to a little larger town with fewer challenging hills and more conveniences. We were building a new home in our soon-to-be new town.  This was, I thought, a great time &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;to explore my interest in drones.  After all, I could document the progress of our new home and, if she did go into real estate, I would be positioned to do some of her photography.  Win!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, while you can fly your drone recreationally without needing a license, if you do anything that has the potential for profit, the FAA requires that you hold a license as a professional drone pilot. The fancy pants way of describing this is that you must hold an Airman certificate for small unmanned aircraft systems, more colloquially this is known as being Part 107 certified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you were pursuing a private pilot license to fly a manned aircraft (for example, a Piper Cub) you would have to go through some fairly rigorous ground school training, learn a ton about weather, radio lingo, how to navigate between airports (and around an airport) and so on. After completing ground school you have to spend time actually flying an aircraft under the direct tutelage of a qualified instructor before being allowed to solo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In comparison to the manned aircraft certificate, the process for obtaining your unmanned certificate (Part 107) is a bit easier.  You only need to take certain topics from the ground school and pass a knowledge test.  No actual flight time required.  The requirements for the test are laid out for you in the &lt;em&gt;Remote Pilot &amp;ndash; Small Unmanned Aircraft Systems Study Guide (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;opi=89978449&amp;amp;url=https://www.faa.gov/sites/faa.gov/files/regulations_policies/handbooks_manuals/aviation/remote_pilot_study_guide.pdf&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwiwuJ33u-eFAxWErIQIHU7lBIUQFnoECAYQAQ&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw3MXKA-tW2dc0bYz-JcA9Qh&#34;&gt;FAA-G-8082-22&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt; provided by the FAA.  This study guide is fairly comprehensible, but sometimes simply reading the content isn&amp;rsquo;t enough.  I like to see and hear what I&amp;rsquo;m learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to make life a bit easier (and easier to understand) I opted to take a paid course to prepare me for the exam.  The cost of theses programs vary considerably and, so far as I know, unlike private pilot training, the FAA does not certify programs that prepare you for the exam. I chose one that seemed reasonable in cost and had good reviews: Pilot Institute. And started studying in earnest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually went through the entire training in a few weeks and was ready to take the test. During the interim, however, my wife decided that she didn&amp;rsquo;t want to pursue real estate as a second career and with that motivation gone, I decided not to continue my pursuit of the license.  After all, why pay for testing for a license that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t likely ever use?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-renewed-motivation&#34;&gt;A Renewed Motivation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a couple of years.  As I prepared for my own retirement, I began looking at my next chapter. I&amp;rsquo;ve always enjoyed writing and thought that I might get serious about blogging regularly.  To add to that, I was fascinated by videography and realized that I could actually make videos that included drone shots.  Motivation for obtaining my license was renewed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that renewed motivation I again studied in earnest. In fact, I went through the material in about a week or 10 days. I found the information fun and interesting.  There are several areas that I want to dig into a bit more deeply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-do-you-need-a-license&#34;&gt;Why do you need a license?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, it seems like the need for a license is just a &amp;lsquo;control&amp;rsquo; thing.  The reality is that the FAA is concerned about safety &amp;ndash; for you and the general public.  The license ensures that you are flying in a safe manner and understand what is needed to protect yourself and those around you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;so-what-is-in-the-exam&#34;&gt;So, what is in the exam?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most obvious, and most applicable, is information on the actual regulations that govern the use of sUAS (small Unmanned Aircraft Systems).  Other information I thought was pretty interesting, but much less useful.  For example, in general you&amp;rsquo;re not permitted to fly your UAS at an airport, yet the exam includes questions about the signage on runways and taxiways.  Similarly, do I really need to know how to enter a landing pattern for an airport?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, to be fair, &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; radio controlled aircraft are considered drones or UASs.  This would include all radio controlled fixed wing model aircraft, so there is some potential applicability for this information.  But to require that knowledge on a licensing exam seems a bit over the top.  The more I studied and considered the exam, the more I began to think that perhaps the FAA felt they needed some type of licensing but didn&amp;rsquo;t really have anything to test on, so they included material that was only tangentially relevant to most drone pilots. And, to be honest, I did find the information interesting and piqued my interest to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-whats-on-the-test&#34;&gt;So, What&amp;rsquo;s on the Test?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I alluded to some of the general concepts above. More specifically, the test covers five areas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regulations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Airspace and Requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weather&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loading and Performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of those areas are broken down into submodules so that the overall test covers a dozen topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applicable regulations relating to small unmanned aircraft system rating privileges, limitations, and flight operation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Airspace classification and operating requirements, and flight restrictions affecting small unmanned aircraft operation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aviation weather sources and effects of weather on small unmanned aircraft performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small unmanned aircraft loading and performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emergency procedures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crew resource management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Radio communication procedures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determining the performance of small unmanned aircraft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Physiological effects of drugs and alcohol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aeronautical decision-making and judgment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Airport operations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintenance and pre-flight inspection procedures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;taking-the-exam&#34;&gt;Taking the Exam&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve studied and feel prepared to take the exam, you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create an account on the FAA&amp;rsquo;s Integrated Airman Certification and Rating Application (IACRA) website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve created your account, you&amp;rsquo;re assigned an FAA Tracking Number (FTN). This number stays with you throughout your aviation career and allows the FAA to keep all of your records together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With your FTN in hand, you then go to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://faa.psiexams.com/faa/login&#34;&gt;Testing Center Website&lt;/a&gt; where you create yet another account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve created that account you simply look for testing centers that are near you. One of the challenges I ran into is that the information on testing sites is a bit confusing at first.  I found several testing sites near me that I would have preferred but couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out how to register.  What I discovered is that those sites, while official testing sites, either had no availability or were simply not accepting reservations.  Scrolling a bit further down the page I finally found some (relatively) nearby sites that had availability.  My closest one was about an hour away.  Chose a time and date and I was set.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived about 30 minutes before my exam. One other person was there waiting to take the exam, as well.  I strongly encourage you to arrive early if for no other reason than to gather your wits about yourself before testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The testing site was quite nice and the people were great.  They check you in, verify your identity and explain the process to you.  You do have to give up anything that&amp;rsquo;s in your pockets (wallet, phone, keys, etc) to ensure that you&amp;rsquo;re not cheating.  They also have cameras and a proctor watching, though I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel intimidated by any of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;re assigned a computer and test code, you go through a brief training program on the computer and, when you&amp;rsquo;re ready, you click start and away you go!  You&amp;rsquo;re given two hours to complete the exam. I took about an hour and that included double-checking every answer.  Most of the answers I knew right off &amp;ndash; my training was quite effective.  There were a few answers that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure about and one that I had absolutely no clue. The other guy that was there started about 5 minutes or so before me and was still there when I left.  I have no clue how he did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One odd thing about the testing software: Once you complete all of the questions it returns you to the first question. I assume that is to allow you to review your answers before submitting.  It wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly clear, though, how to exit that cycle and actually submit the exam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve completed the exam and clicked submit you&amp;rsquo;re taken to a survey.  Once the survey is completed the software closes and you&amp;rsquo;re directed back to the proctor&amp;rsquo;s office for your score.  I made a 92!  The score report does provide feedback on the areas you missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, you&amp;rsquo;re not done yet!  With your score in hand, you go back to the IACRA website to submit your application for a license. You need your Exam ID number that is assigned when you complete the test in order to apply for your license. This ties your score to you in the IACRA system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all goes well, within a few days you&amp;rsquo;ll receive an email that includes your temporary airman certificate that indicates that you&amp;rsquo;re a remote pilot of small unmanned aircraft systems!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet received my permanent certificate, but it should be coming in a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;do-you-need-to-renew-your-license&#34;&gt;Do You Need to Renew your License?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, every two years you&amp;rsquo;ll need to renew your license.  Once upon a time (before 2021) you needed to re-test in order to renew your license.  The rule has changed and now you simply need to take an online refresher course (provided by the FAA). You&amp;rsquo;ll then receive a certificate showing the completion of the course and you&amp;rsquo;re good for another 24 calendar months.  One note, though, just as you&amp;rsquo;ll need to have you Part 107 license on you when you fly, you will also need to keep a copy of the certificate of completion on you to demonstrate compliance with the regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, now my wife can claim to be the wife of a pilot!  (that was her idea, not mine.)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Think Crypto is Stupid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-i-think-crypto-is-stupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-i-think-crypto-is-stupid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-i-think-crypto-is-stupid&#34;&gt;Why I Think Crypto is Stupid&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently read an article on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/story/faruk-ozer-turkey-crypto-fraud/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about Faruk  Ozer, The CEO of Turkey&amp;rsquo;s biggest Cryptocurrency business.  That article outlines how tens of thousands of Turkish people were victims of Ozer&amp;rsquo;s theft of their crypto wallets and all of their assets.  The thing that stood out to me is how easy it was for him to simply download their accounts onto a thumb drive and be off with their money.   In the wake of the crypto crimes of Sam Bankman-Fried (FTX) and Changpeng&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; Zhao (Binance) I fail to understand why anyone would trust their financial assets and future to something so easily stolen.  Unlike banks, there is no FDIC insurance. Unlike stocks and bonds there is no physical document to show ownership. (Yes, I realize that most transactions exist in the &amp;rsquo;ether&amp;rsquo; but using a reputable trading house provides a level of safety that they are unlikely to steal your money.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-i-think-crypto-is-stupid&#34;&gt;Why I Think Crypto is Stupid&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently read an article on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/story/faruk-ozer-turkey-crypto-fraud/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about Faruk  Ozer, The CEO of Turkey&amp;rsquo;s biggest Cryptocurrency business.  That article outlines how tens of thousands of Turkish people were victims of Ozer&amp;rsquo;s theft of their crypto wallets and all of their assets.  The thing that stood out to me is how easy it was for him to simply download their accounts onto a thumb drive and be off with their money.   In the wake of the crypto crimes of Sam Bankman-Fried (FTX) and Changpeng&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; Zhao (Binance) I fail to understand why anyone would trust their financial assets and future to something so easily stolen.  Unlike banks, there is no FDIC insurance. Unlike stocks and bonds there is no physical document to show ownership. (Yes, I realize that most transactions exist in the &amp;rsquo;ether&amp;rsquo; but using a reputable trading house provides a level of safety that they are unlikely to steal your money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although many of us may not fully understand stocks, bonds, mutual funds, and the like, they have been around a very long time and there are plenty of resources available to help you wrap your head around those concepts.  Do you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; understand cryptocurrency?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my rules in personal finance is to never invest in anything that you do not understand.  If you don&amp;rsquo;t understand cryptocurrency and how it works, don&amp;rsquo;t invest in it. Period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stocks and bonds are rooted, ultimately, in a physical business with physical and financial assets.  That is, there is intrinsic value in the stock or bond. There are regulations through the Securities and Exchange Commission that govern how these stocks and bonds are traded.  On what is cryptocurrency based? From what I can tell, it rooted in the belief that it has value.  And it&amp;rsquo;s nothing more than belief.  There is no physical &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; that underlies the value of crypto. And there are no protections or, so far as I am aware, any regulations around them. It is the wild west of of stupidity, in my view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, there are a lot of folks that will point out that the US dollar is similarly unmoored from anything physical. And that is absolutely true. However, it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; backed by the government and is the official currency of the government. And, while the government has its problems, the US dollar is accepted as valid currency here and in many areas abroad. Cryptocurrency lacks any such backing.  In effect, so far as I understand it, cryptocurrency has value only because we believe it has value.  So, too, did Beanie Babies, pet rocks, Cabbage Patch Kids, and a host of other &amp;ldquo;collectibles&amp;rdquo; until we no longer believed they had value, then their &amp;ldquo;value&amp;rdquo; evaporated.   There is one major difference between these &amp;ldquo;collectibles&amp;rdquo; and cryptocurrency: Even if you don&amp;rsquo;t believe the items have any real value, they are still physical assets and at some point in the future they may again have value. (Think about old toys that are now considered antiques which has enhanced their value.) Cryptocurrency, on the other hand, is not a physical &amp;rsquo;thing&amp;rsquo; consequently there will be no future for it. Once it disappears it is simply gone, like a puddle of water in the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another rule of personal finance management is to never risk more than you can afford to lose.  Many people (too many!) put large sums of money into crypto when they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t.  Many people believe that crypto can make them a great deal of money quickly.  But, as the old saying goes, if it sounds too good to be true, it probably is.  It is likely that cryptocurrency is making a lot of money for some people, but they&amp;rsquo;re likely doing it at the expense of others.  You don&amp;rsquo;t want to be that &amp;ldquo;other&amp;rdquo;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Don&#39;t Trust Gmail. Here&#39;s Why</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-dont-trust-gmail-heres-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-dont-trust-gmail-heres-why/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-dont-trust-gmail-heres-why&#34;&gt;I Don&amp;rsquo;t Trust Gmail. Here&amp;rsquo;s Why.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have had an email address with Gmail for probably 20 years.  I mean my email address is my name @ Gmail. No numbers, no weird abbreviations, no strange punctuations, just my firstnamelastname @gmail.com How long has it been since that was possible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three or four years ago I began receiving emails to my address that were clearly intended for another pers&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;on with my same name.  Their email was literally my email address!  At first I thought it was just an glitch in the system. Later I thought perhaps they had simply mis-typed their name (maybe left out a letter or something) or had made up a name so that they did not get spam emails.  However, many of those emails were for legitimate purposes &amp;ndash; receipts from Tractor Supply or from their cell phone provider.  What gives?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-dont-trust-gmail-heres-why&#34;&gt;I Don&amp;rsquo;t Trust Gmail. Here&amp;rsquo;s Why.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have had an email address with Gmail for probably 20 years.  I mean my email address is my name @ Gmail. No numbers, no weird abbreviations, no strange punctuations, just my firstnamelastname @gmail.com How long has it been since that was possible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three or four years ago I began receiving emails to my address that were clearly intended for another pers&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;on with my same name.  Their email was literally my email address!  At first I thought it was just an glitch in the system. Later I thought perhaps they had simply mis-typed their name (maybe left out a letter or something) or had made up a name so that they did not get spam emails.  However, many of those emails were for legitimate purposes &amp;ndash; receipts from Tractor Supply or from their cell phone provider.  What gives?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I know that there are at least a dozen folks out there here in the US and in South Africa and Australia that share my name.  But Gmail should not allow anyone else to create an account with the same user name.  Yet, clearly, when I look at the emails intended for those other Kevins it is very clear that they are using the same email address.  How is that possible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It occurred to me, then, that if I am receiving their emails, they are likely seeing some of mine.  Not a good plan!  I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to figure out how to contact Gmail to see what&amp;rsquo;s going on and how this could be happening but so far I haven&amp;rsquo;t been successful.  And, frankly, with so many other email accounts available to me (outlook, yahoo, icloud, etc) I don&amp;rsquo;t really need the Gmail account anymore.  I keep it simply because I&amp;rsquo;ve had it so long and there are still a (very) few folks that only have that address for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I don&amp;rsquo;t use Gmail for anything embarrassing or nefarious but, still, the idea that others may be receiving emails intended for me is, to say the least unsettling. So, since I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to track down why I am receiving emails intended for others and how it is possible for others to create accounts using my same username (there are at least two!) I don&amp;rsquo;t feel that I can trust Gmail. For that reason I no longer use it for anything other than as an address to use when I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to receive emails to my primary service (I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about that in another post).  That&amp;rsquo;s sad, because Gmail used to be a good service.  But, I guess when you get too big for your britches you lose control of a lot of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing the Same Thing And ...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/doing-the-same-thing-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/doing-the-same-thing-and/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;doing-the-same-thing-and-&#34;&gt;Doing the Same Thing And &amp;hellip;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve heard the saying &amp;ldquo;the definition insanity is doing the same thing over and over again and expecting a different result.&amp;rdquo; And I think you&amp;rsquo;ll agree that this &amp;lsquo;definition&amp;rsquo; is commonly true.  But, what about those times when you do the same thing each and every time and &lt;em&gt;get&lt;/em&gt; a different result?  That, my friends, is the definition of randomness. And, it&amp;rsquo;s far more common than you think.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;doing-the-same-thing-and-&#34;&gt;Doing the Same Thing And &amp;hellip;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve heard the saying &amp;ldquo;the definition insanity is doing the same thing over and over again and expecting a different result.&amp;rdquo; And I think you&amp;rsquo;ll agree that this &amp;lsquo;definition&amp;rsquo; is commonly true.  But, what about those times when you do the same thing each and every time and &lt;em&gt;get&lt;/em&gt; a different result?  That, my friends, is the definition of randomness. And, it&amp;rsquo;s far more common than you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Physicist Leonard Mlodinow, in his book &lt;em&gt;The Drunkard&amp;rsquo;s Walk: How Randomness Rules Our Lives&lt;/em&gt;, Psychologist &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Dan Ariely, in &lt;em&gt;Predictably Irrational: The Hidden Forces That Shape Our Decisions&lt;/em&gt;, Psychologist Daniel Kahneman, in &lt;em&gt;Thinking, Fast and Slow&lt;/em&gt;, and a variety of others whose names I don&amp;rsquo;t now recall, have all pointed to how often randomness injects itself into our lives without our ever realizing its influence. Not only is randomness more common than we realize, we actively reject the notion that something that occurs is simply a random event.  Rather, as Kahneman points out, we often create stories to &amp;ldquo;explain&amp;rdquo; what happens.  It seems we can&amp;rsquo;t simply accept that most of the events in our lives are simply random events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*** Randomness, an Example ***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take, for example, the manager that monitors sales in his store. He installed a contraption that counts the number of visitors to his store and uses that as a basis for determining the effectiveness of his sales staff.  Over the past few months he noted that sales tended to hang around 85% of visits.  That is, for every 100 visitors 85% of them became customers by purchasing something.  About four months ago, sales jumped by nearly 7% to 92%. The manager was ecstatic and praised his staff for their hard work.  They all kind of looked at each other because they really hadn&amp;rsquo;t done anything differently. If asked, they would be unable to explain why the sales suddenly increased.  But the manager never asked; he was just happy to see the increase.  To the benefit of the sales staff, the manager assumed that the increase was the result of the employees&amp;rsquo; hard work.  That was his story to explain the increase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following month, though, sales were down a bit.  Still higher than the average of 85%, but not at that same nice 92%. It was closer to 87%.  He began to wonder what happened but didn&amp;rsquo;t really say anything.  In the most recent month sales dropped again to 86% of visitors.  Now he is concerned that the staff are resting on their laurels and aren&amp;rsquo;t working as hard to make sales and so he begins to suggest that they need to step it up. After all, if they can do 92% once, they shoud be able to maintain that.  Now, his story to explain the drop in sales is that the staff aren&amp;rsquo;t working hard enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That manager does not understand how sales work. More specifically he doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand the concept of randomness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sales staff did nothing different in order to achieve that nice 92%. It simply happened.  The steady drop back to 85% is simply what statisticians call &lt;em&gt;regression to the mean&lt;/em&gt;.  Over time random events tend to return to the average.  There is variation in every process. This is most easily seen when a process, such as sales (yes, sales is a process), varies from its normal levels, particularly if the variation is sudden, unexpected, and unexplainable. If there is some clear explanation &amp;ndash; for example, a storm motivates more people to purchase generators than are normally purchased &amp;ndash; then the process itself is not random, though, of course, the cause of the variation (the storm) is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those involved in operations management know that variation is to be expected.  For example, let&amp;rsquo;s suppose you manufacture chocolate chip cookies.  At each step of the process, there is some variation.  So, there might be slight differences in the quantities of ingredients added to each batch of dough, the amount of dough dispensed onto the conveyor that takes the cookies through the oven, and even the &amp;ldquo;doneness&amp;rdquo; of the cookies.  And, of course, not every cookie will have the same number of chocolate chips.  But, in general, all of those variations will be within an acceptable range. That acceptable range is defined by &lt;em&gt;control limits&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; upper and lower limits within which the process is allowed to vary. The idea is that even if all of the variations skewed to one extreme, the product would still meet quality control standards and every cookie will have some tasty chocolate chips in it. Only when the control limits are exceeded are corrective actions taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, even though we follow the recipe for chocolate chip cookies every time, there is still a randomness to both the process and the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this might be fairly easy to see in the cookies example, it&amp;rsquo;s often less clear in other situations. Suppose you&amp;rsquo;re shopping in the mall and you become aware that you&amp;rsquo;ve seen the same man several times, in several different stores. That you cross paths several times while in the shopping center is largely a matter of chance &amp;ndash; randomness &amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, as Kahneman points out, we don&amp;rsquo;t like to accept the simple but true explanation that the variation was simple a random event. We&amp;rsquo;re uncomfortable with that.  Instead, we create a story to explain the event.  When sales are up, the story is that the staff worked harder and deserves reward. When sales are down, the story is that the staff didn&amp;rsquo;t work as hard and should be reprimanded and coaxed into working harder to re-establish those high sales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*** Making Stories ***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The books I mentioned earlier all tell the same story: people are uncomfortable accepting that outcomes are most often random and, consequently, create stories that explain the results.  Think about the stock market. Despite what many would claim, the stock market is essentially a random process.  There are a great many factors that may influence the price of a stock on a given day, but over time the stock price is going to fluctuate fairly widely, regardless of whatever else is happening.  We know this is true simply by watching the price of a single stock. Watch the hour to hour changes in stock prices.  Watch the day-to-day and week-to-week changes.  How many of hte changes in the price of that stock can be difinitively linked to some action on the part of management? Not many, if any at all.  Why? Because the changes are random.  Over time stock prices tend to rise. But on a short-term basis there is a great deal of variablity in their prices.  All of that variability is the result of the randomness of the market. And nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*** The Effect of Small Samples ***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, one of my colleagues was out of work for a bit.  On his return, he was assigned about 1/10th of the students he might normally have during the month.  When the data for the month were analyzed there was much ado about his having achieved a 100% pass rate (the team rate is about 85%).  He received much praise and acknowledgement for his hard work.  Did he deserve it?  Probably not. His situation describes the effect of small numbers &amp;ndash; the smaller the number in a sample, the more more extreme the results tend to be.  For him, the small number of students assigned to him resulted in a significant increase in his pass rate.  It is just as likely that his pass rate could have been 50%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that last bit confused you, consider this: If you are teaching a class of 500 students, the effect of one student&amp;rsquo;s score on the average score for the class is 0.002 (0.2%). So, the average score for the class is going to be the sum of the individual students&amp;rsquo; scores. However, if you&amp;rsquo;re class only has 100 students in it, then the effect of one student on the overall class score is 0.01(1%) &amp;ndash; five times the impact on the overall average than the student who is one of 500.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let&amp;rsquo;s reduce that even more.  Let&amp;rsquo;s say your class only has 20 students. Each student has a 0.05  point (5%) impact on the overall score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s look at how the change in a single students score from in score from 80% to 90% impacts the overall class average:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;Score/Students&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;20 Students&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;100 Students&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;500 Students&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;80%&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;avg: 75&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;avg: 75&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;avg: 75&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;90%&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;avg 75.5&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;avg: 75.1&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;avg 75.02&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this table it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see how the number of students affects the impact that one student&amp;rsquo;s grade has on the class average. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re talking about the number of customers, the number of students, the number of cats, or the number of hotdogs as the subject of the statistical analysis, the simple fact is that the fewer subjects you include in your statistics the greater the individual&amp;rsquo;s impact will be on the final result.  This means, of course, that with fewer subjects, you are more likely to see extreme results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is what managers tend to overlook. Rather than considering the effect of smaller numbers on the results, they celebrate (or punish) the employee&amp;rsquo;s &amp;rsquo;effectiveness&amp;rsquo;, even if the employee did nothing to bring about that outcome. The manager creates a story to explain the employee&amp;rsquo;s performance even when there is no basis for the story.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ONE THING</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-one-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-one-thing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-one-thing&#34;&gt;The ONE THING&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love to read and love to learn, so it is no suprise that one of my favorite pastimes is to wander through bookstores. I love perusing the titles, skimming a few pages of those that interest me and maybe marking a few to add to my reading list. It&amp;rsquo;s a habit I developed probably thirty years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the subject areas I generally skim is the business management section. Learning about management styles and techniques is interesting and informative.  Last fall, however, as  I was skimming titles, I had an epihany.  As I skimmed the titles I became aware of just how many titles purported to embue the reader &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;with &amp;ldquo;the one thing&amp;rdquo; that they could do to be the best leader, the best manager, to build the most successful company, and &amp;hellip; well, you get the idea. As I looked further, I found books of similar types in other subject areas.  It seems that everyone one is looking for the ONE THING that gives them an advantagse. The problem was that in skimming the books it quickly became apparent that the &amp;ldquo;one thing&amp;rdquo; differed from book to book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-one-thing&#34;&gt;The ONE THING&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love to read and love to learn, so it is no suprise that one of my favorite pastimes is to wander through bookstores. I love perusing the titles, skimming a few pages of those that interest me and maybe marking a few to add to my reading list. It&amp;rsquo;s a habit I developed probably thirty years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the subject areas I generally skim is the business management section. Learning about management styles and techniques is interesting and informative.  Last fall, however, as  I was skimming titles, I had an epihany.  As I skimmed the titles I became aware of just how many titles purported to embue the reader &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;with &amp;ldquo;the one thing&amp;rdquo; that they could do to be the best leader, the best manager, to build the most successful company, and &amp;hellip; well, you get the idea. As I looked further, I found books of similar types in other subject areas.  It seems that everyone one is looking for the ONE THING that gives them an advantagse. The problem was that in skimming the books it quickly became apparent that the &amp;ldquo;one thing&amp;rdquo; differed from book to book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-could-that-be&#34;&gt;How Could That Be?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I pondered this situation, a couple of explanations came to mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first explanation is that there are many road to the same outcome.  That is, despite the author&amp;rsquo;s assertion that his or her approach was the &amp;ldquo;one best way&amp;rdquo;, perhaps there were other, equally effective ways of acheiving first-rate outcomes. The author simply chose a title that he or she hoped would sell more books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second explanation is that maybe the &amp;ldquo;one best way&amp;rdquo; worked for this manager, in this organization.  Whether or not it would work for a different manager, with a different management style, in a different organizational environment is questionable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A third explanation (yes, I know that &amp;ldquo;a couple&amp;rdquo; means two), and the one that I most agree with, is that all those books are just a bunch of hooey.  There is no one best way that applies to everyone.  The titles, and, indeed the premise on which they are based, are aimed at selling books and nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This last gains some support from psychologist Daniel Kahneman who notes that humans love stories and abhor the unexplained.  So we look for stories to explain why a particular business appears to be successful while another fails.  We look for stories to explain why one person is hugely successful while another, even with similar talents and abilities, fails miserably.  And, it seems, that&amp;rsquo;s what most (if not all) of these books are: stories to explain success or failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;theyre-just-stories&#34;&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re Just Stories&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three problems with these stories.  First, the stories are always rendered in hindsight.  It is much easier to explain success or failure after the fact. Whether or not the success or failure was predicted (or could have been) beforehand is a different story. this suggests that &amp;ldquo;the one thing&amp;rdquo; is not so much a truism as it is an interpretation designed to explain the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, the stories almost invariably omit the factors that don&amp;rsquo;t fit the narrative. That is, a story that explains why TheCompany was so successful omits the myriad blunders and failed attempts that occurred along the way.  Or, if the story is about a person, the story may omit the obvious strokes of luck that occurred as part of that success story. If Bill Gates was 10 years older, or 10 years younger than he is, no one would have heard of him.  His luck was in being at the right place at the right time with the right skillset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third problem is that rarely is an event the result of some single factor. There is no ONE THING.  We humans are a lazy bunch.  We want things presented to us in simple, easily digested bites.  We don&amp;rsquo;t want to hear that the success of one company was based on the interaction of dozens of factors while that of another was based on the interactions of dozens of &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; factors.  The two companies might share some of those factors, but not all of them, yet they were both successful.  And we certainly don&amp;rsquo;t want to hear that changes to any one of those factors might well have doomed the company rather than ensuring its success. That&amp;rsquo;s way too complicated and we don&amp;rsquo;t like complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;so-whats-my-point&#34;&gt;So, What&amp;rsquo;s My Point?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I have two points to make, really. The first is that the world is a complicated place that cannot be easily boiled down to simple rules.  That means that success can come from many factors, or the interaction of many factors, but rarely can be attributed to a single all-encompassing idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second point is that reading these books is interesting, thought-provoking, and even inspirational. But they don&amp;rsquo;t explain anything.  They are simply interesting stories that reflect one person&amp;rsquo;s interpretation of the facts, after the fact, that they invented to explain success or failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read them with a large dose of salt.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Wrong With Asking for a &#34;Highly Satisfied&#34; Rating</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/whats-wrong-with-asking-for-a-highly-satisfied-rating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/whats-wrong-with-asking-for-a-highly-satisfied-rating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;whats-wrong-with-asking-for-a-highly-satisified-rating&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Wrong with Asking for a &amp;ldquo;Highly Satisified&amp;rdquo; Rating?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtually all businesses today are concerned about how the public perceives them.  They recognize &amp;ndash; and rightfully so, in my opinion &amp;ndash; that customers who have a positive experience, who receive great service, or receive quality, tasty foods are more likely to be repeat customers.  They also know that customers who have a poor experience are just as unlikely to return.  Thus, measuring the customer experience by asking the customer to complete a survey of their experience is an important means for getting information on how&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; well the company is doing in meeting the customers&amp;rsquo; needs and expectations.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure all managers understand the value of the survey and the need for accurate feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;whats-wrong-with-asking-for-a-highly-satisified-rating&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Wrong with Asking for a &amp;ldquo;Highly Satisified&amp;rdquo; Rating?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtually all businesses today are concerned about how the public perceives them.  They recognize &amp;ndash; and rightfully so, in my opinion &amp;ndash; that customers who have a positive experience, who receive great service, or receive quality, tasty foods are more likely to be repeat customers.  They also know that customers who have a poor experience are just as unlikely to return.  Thus, measuring the customer experience by asking the customer to complete a survey of their experience is an important means for getting information on how&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; well the company is doing in meeting the customers&amp;rsquo; needs and expectations.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure all managers understand the value of the survey and the need for accurate feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-surveys-are-important&#34;&gt;Why Surveys Are Important&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a competitive marketplace reputation is important.  Reputation is the amalgam of the customer experience. Everything from the taste, temperature, and presentation of the food, to the friendliness of staff, the speed with which the food is delivered, and even the cleanliness of the environment, all play a role in reputation.  In retail businesses such as Wal-Mart or Target, the quality of the food may not be of value, but the abilty to easily navigate the aisles, or to locate a desired product, would be.  The simple fact is that your company may provide the best food in town, but if the service sucks, your reputation will sink you quickly. And, once the reputation is established it&amp;rsquo;s really hard to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customer surveys can provide management with insight into what the customer values and to how well the business is meeting that expectation.  If you want to improve, you pay attention to the feedback customers provide.  But that feedback needs to be accurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-ask&#34;&gt;The &amp;lsquo;Ask&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was immediately struck by the inanity of that message.  I doubt whether McDonalds corporate authorized that message. After all, they are spending money to collect and analyze the data from the survey, and providing incentives for completing it &amp;ndash; regardless of what ratings are applied. To ask for a specific rating invalidates the survey, wasting all the money they&amp;rsquo;ve invested in the process.  That wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make sense from a corporate perspective.  Businesses want and need valid customer feedback, as I said earlier.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming that McDonald&amp;rsquo;s corporate didn&amp;rsquo;t authorize the message, I am left with a couple of other possible explanations and to some degree they may be interrelated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, the management of this particular store does not understand the value of customer feedback.  It could be that the manager either never received or did not pay attention to the training on the value and utility of accurate customer feedback.  Alternately, they may simply have received bad training from the git go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second, it could be that the manager fully understands the value of feedback but also knows that some issues, such as service quality are the result of in-store cultures and, as a result, realizes the challenges faced with changing that culture.  It&amp;rsquo;s easier to ask customers to provide false feedback than to address the issues that could organically lead to improved customer experiences in the store.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A third option is that the management in that store simply doesn&amp;rsquo;t care.  They would rather bribe customers to get high ratings than to actually do the work of improving their service and quality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;undermining-their-own-intentions&#34;&gt;Undermining Their Own Intentions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fourth possibility is that corporate messaging may lead to misunderstanding the goals of the survey, or actually change the purpose of the survey unintentionally.  In my experience, it is pretty common for businesses to say one thing but then take steps that undermine their words.  Because businesses often don&amp;rsquo;t fully think through their actions, they fail to recognize and adjust for the potential unintentional consequences of their actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s assume, for example, that McDonalds is sincere in their desire to improve the quality of food and service in their stores. They initiate the customer feedback system to gain insights into the customer experience and expectations.  Along with this effort, they implement a rewards system that rewards stores for high ratings.  Sounds good, right?  Providing incentives to earn highly satisfied ratings might help improve the experience. Or, it could simply lead to managers asking customers to give high ratings, bribing them to do so. The unintentional effect of providing incentives to managers for their high ratings leads to the managers gaming the system to ensure they get those incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only does the customer experience not improve, but the company no longer has a valid way to determine what that customer experience is.  The data are tainted.  In my view, the results of surveys should not be tied either to incentives or punishment (the other direction some businesses tend to go).  Rather, the surveys should be presented to management for what they are &amp;ndash; opportunities to improve the success of the business through its focus on the customer experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-did-i-do-with-that-survey&#34;&gt;What Did I do With That Survey?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually completed the survey with the specific goal of expressing my displeasure at the &amp;ldquo;bribe&amp;rdquo; that was offered.  Interestingly, even though I did not provide &amp;ldquo;Highly Satisfied&amp;rdquo; responses to my survey, I was given a code for that free item.  So, it appears that a &amp;ldquo;highly satisfied&amp;rdquo; rating was not required for the incentive, but you don&amp;rsquo;t find that out until you&amp;rsquo;ve provided the high ratings.  It seems the company was simply providing an incentive to customers to provide feedback.  The manager decided to leverage that incentive to ensure high ratings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That manager needs retraining &amp;ndash; and not just on on the value of customer feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science Fiction and the Polymath</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/science-fiction-and-the-polymath/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/science-fiction-and-the-polymath/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;science-fiction-and-the-polymath&#34;&gt;Science Fiction and the Polymath&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout my junior high years I was a huge science fiction fan.  One of my favorite authors of the time was  Isaac Asimov.  I was quite surprised to learn that Asimov not only wrote science fiction but had also penned books, short stories, and essays that ranged from religion (Guide to the Bible), chemistry (he was educated as a biochemist), engineering, and the list goes on.  This realization intially confused me.  How &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;could a science fiction writer be so bold as to write on so many different topics? How could he know enough in each of those fields to qualify himself to write books on them?  It would be many years before I encountered the term &amp;ldquo;polymath&amp;rdquo;, but surely Asimov earned the title.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;science-fiction-and-the-polymath&#34;&gt;Science Fiction and the Polymath&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout my junior high years I was a huge science fiction fan.  One of my favorite authors of the time was  Isaac Asimov.  I was quite surprised to learn that Asimov not only wrote science fiction but had also penned books, short stories, and essays that ranged from religion (Guide to the Bible), chemistry (he was educated as a biochemist), engineering, and the list goes on.  This realization intially confused me.  How &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;could a science fiction writer be so bold as to write on so many different topics? How could he know enough in each of those fields to qualify himself to write books on them?  It would be many years before I encountered the term &amp;ldquo;polymath&amp;rdquo;, but surely Asimov earned the title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to a few weeks ago.  I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really given Asimov &amp;ndash; or science fiction &amp;ndash; a whole lot of thought in many years.  I would still occasionally read a sci-fi story or watch a few sci-fi films or TV shows, but for the the most part, I had set aside my interest.  Too many other demands on my time. Then I ran across &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.technologyreview.com/s/531911/isaac-asimov-asks-how-do-people-get-new-ideas/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; article in which Asimov explores how people get new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the points he makes in that article is that new ideas are born by combining old ideas in new ways.  That is, seeing connections between old ideas that others seem to have missed. Implicit in his explanation is that in order for one to create new ideas, one must first be conversant in a range of old ideas.  Logically, the more &amp;lsquo;old&amp;rsquo; knowledge you have, the more likely you are to develop some new idea. After all, the more knowledge you have, the greater are the opportunities for connections to be made between two or more of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That realization also underscores the need for a broad education.  Today the tendency, even at the university level, is to focus on knowledge and skills that translate into a career path. Now, there are a number of issues with that which I won&amp;rsquo;t go into here, but one problem with this perspective of education is highlighted by Asimov&amp;rsquo;s observation.  The more knowledge you have on a broad range of subjects, the more likely you are to make a connection that leads to new ideas and new knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a youngster, it made little sense to me that a writer of science fiction should spend his time in all of these disparate areas.  As an adult and an educator, it makes perfect sense.  Science fiction is a nearly perfect vehicle for exploring and questioning the range of human experience.  By creating &amp;rsquo;new worlds&amp;rsquo; and new civilizations, the sci-fi writer gives him or herself the license to explore ideas.  She is not bound to the current cultural norms; she can create her own.  To do that, though, the writer must first have an understanding of cultures and how they develop.  To develop new worlds, the writer must first develop an appreciation for how those worlds might be different.  To create and convincingly describe new technologies, the writer has to have at least a foundational understanding of the physics, chemistry, and/or engineering involved in those technologies.  To create new languages (as JRR Tolkien did) the writer must have an understanding of languages and linguistics. In short, the science fiction writer must be well-versed in a wide range of knowledge domains. That is, the writer most likely is a polymath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what is a polymath? &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/polymath&#34;&gt; Merriam-Webster&lt;/a&gt; defines a polymath as someone who knows a lot about a lot of different things; someone of encyclopedic knowledge.  From other readings, those whom we consider to be polymaths are highly curious and are constantly exploring new areas of knowledge. They want the knowledge for the sake of knowing, and without any particular purpose.  But I think it&amp;rsquo;s more than that.  I think that a true polymath not only knows a lot about many different things, but is also able to combine that knowledge in the creation of new knowledge. And this is what science fiction writers often do.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me? A Manager? Not So Much</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/me-a-manager-not-so-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/me-a-manager-not-so-much/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;me-a-manager-not-so-much&#34;&gt;Me? A Manager? Not so Much&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past year or so my manager has
been after me to move into a management role.  I managed to avoid doing so until
fairly recently, using my work on my doctorate as an excuse for not really
having the time to take on all the work of learning the role, learning the
courses I would manage and so forth.  Recently, however, I was approached again
and, having all-but completed my degree, really didn&amp;rsquo;t have a good reason for&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;me-a-manager-not-so-much&#34;&gt;Me? A Manager? Not so Much&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past year or so my manager has
been after me to move into a management role.  I managed to avoid doing so until
fairly recently, using my work on my doctorate as an excuse for not really
having the time to take on all the work of learning the role, learning the
courses I would manage and so forth.  Recently, however, I was approached again
and, having all-but completed my degree, really didn&amp;rsquo;t have a good reason for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t get the job.  Exactly why, though, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure. I do know that they had
multiple applicants and no one was chosen.  That&amp;rsquo;s fine.  That experience,
though, got me to really thinking about whether I really wanted to continue to
pursue a management position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-answer-is-no&#34;&gt;The Answer is &amp;ldquo;No&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s pretty common, I think, for people to expect that as you gain experience in
a field that you&amp;rsquo;ll want to move up within that field.  For most people, that
means moving into management.  And, if that&amp;rsquo;s truly where you want to be, that&amp;rsquo;s
a good plan.  But, when people begin to expect you to move up and you don&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ndash;
particularly by choice &amp;ndash; they begin to wonder why not.  Why, they ask, aren&amp;rsquo;t
you interested in growing?  Or, why don&amp;rsquo;t you want to improve yourself?  Some
organizations even set the expectation that you either express a desire to move
&amp;lsquo;up the ladder&amp;rsquo; or move on.  They (wrongfully) equate a lack of desire to &amp;lsquo;move
up&amp;rsquo; with a lack of motivation to do good work.  They are very short-sighted.
Ignorant, even.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the thing in my own case.  I began pursuit of my doctorate not because I
wanted to
become a manager but because I wanted to teach.  It really doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to
get a degree that fully qualifies me to teach and then abandon teaching for
management.  Perhaps as importantly, management is simply not me. I&amp;rsquo;ve done
management.  I have a degree in management.  I&amp;rsquo;m not a good manager. My manager
disagrees and that&amp;rsquo;s okay.  The problem is that he is evaluating my life through
his lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also the simple fact that leadership and management are often seen as
being the same thing. They
are not.  I am a good leader.  I have good ideas, I see ways that things can be
done differently and more effectively, and I am good a communicating those
thoughts.  I look at things through a different lens, which allows me to present
alternative ways of seeing and approaching things.  And, because I am both good
at expressing those thoughts and pretty much unafraid to bring up questions,
others listen to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, just because I am a good leader doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I&amp;rsquo;ll be a good manager.  The
requisite skills are different.  Perhaps more importantly, the constraints on
the two roles are different.  As a manager I am constrained to present the
organization&amp;rsquo;s perspective in a positive light, at least to those under my
management.  As a simple employee, I&amp;rsquo;m free to voice my frustrations and
disagreements with the &amp;lsquo;company view&amp;rsquo;. That can be dangerous, but is less likely
to garner significant backlash than if I did so as a manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;academics-and-management&#34;&gt;Academics and Management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t speak for anyone other than myself, so that heading is a bit misleading.&lt;br&gt;
But, it seems to me that academics go into education for one of three reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, they genuinely enjoy teaching. They enjoy the interaction with
students.
They love to see that &amp;ldquo;ah ha!&amp;rdquo; look in the students&amp;rsquo; faces when the students
connect the
dots and a concept crystallizes for them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second, they are curious (I&amp;rsquo;ll write
more about that later) and academia allows them to satisfy that curiosity and
to share the fruits of their curiosity with others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Third, I know at least
some people who come into education more as an avoidance of or escape from some
unpleasant work experience than for any particular desire to educate.  This
third group may also include people who can simply no longer function in the
workplace due to age or infirmity.  Nurses, for example, may come into teaching
more because they can no longer physically do the work of nursing. There&amp;rsquo;s
nothing wrong with that, though they may not be the most effective educators.  I
do disagree with the old saw that &amp;ldquo;Them what can, do; Them what can&amp;rsquo;t, teach.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s true.  In my experience, teaching is simply an expression
of what drives the individual.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of these reasons points to the need for a position in management.  It&amp;rsquo;s not
about power or authority. It&amp;rsquo;s about sharing with others and exploring one&amp;rsquo;s own
interests. It&amp;rsquo;s not about growing into more &amp;lsquo;responsible&amp;rsquo; positions (whatever
that means), it&amp;rsquo;s about growing in understanding and insight and
accomplishments. I don&amp;rsquo;t see the ability to manage others or to implement the
plans and goals of others as necessarily being growth. Nor do I see stifling my
own perspectives, interests, and curiosity in order to meet some vague corporate
conception of what I should be as a desirable thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, I&amp;rsquo;ve given it thought and I will not be pursuing management anytime in
the foreseeable future.  I want to grow, but as a person and as an intellectual,
not as a minion to those with more titular &amp;lsquo;power&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Curiosity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-power-of-curiosity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-power-of-curiosity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-power-of-curiosity&#34;&gt;The Power of Curiosity&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always been a curious person. I&amp;rsquo;m the kid that took toys apart to see how they worked (and was sometimes able to put them back together again, too!) I was the kid that enjoyed reading the &lt;em&gt;WorldBook Encyclopedia&lt;/em&gt; because, well, just because. Learning about different stuff fascinated me.  Even as a very small child I was curious.  My mother used to tell the story of the time when I was maybe 3 or 4 years old and came in crying because my eyes were filled with sand.  I had apparently held a toy over my head and looked up&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; as the sand fell out because I wanted to see what it looked like from that angle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-power-of-curiosity&#34;&gt;The Power of Curiosity&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always been a curious person. I&amp;rsquo;m the kid that took toys apart to see how they worked (and was sometimes able to put them back together again, too!) I was the kid that enjoyed reading the &lt;em&gt;WorldBook Encyclopedia&lt;/em&gt; because, well, just because. Learning about different stuff fascinated me.  Even as a very small child I was curious.  My mother used to tell the story of the time when I was maybe 3 or 4 years old and came in crying because my eyes were filled with sand.  I had apparently held a toy over my head and looked up&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; as the sand fell out because I wanted to see what it looked like from that angle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that curiosity persists within me today. My wife becomes exasperated with me because I tend to bounce around to different ideas, interests, and activities.  Today I&amp;rsquo;m learning a new programming language, tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;m studying Spanish, then next day I&amp;rsquo;m reading some philosophical treatise.  Or business. Or economics. Or &amp;hellip; Or &amp;hellip; Or. Did I say I like to learn stuff?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most recently I&amp;rsquo;ve read two books that have at least provided some consolation that perhaps my natural inclination toward epistemic meandering is neither uncommon nor bad for me.  Mario Livio, an astrophysicist and author of several books on mathematics and physics, wrote the book &lt;em&gt;Why? What Makes Us Curious.&lt;/em&gt; In it Livio shares with the reader how many well-known figures such as Leonardo Da Vinci, Richard Feynman, and a host of others had wide ranging interests and who often became fascinated by some topic only to drop it once their curiosity had been sated, or the specific question they sought to answer had been answered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ian Leslie, an author and journalist, took a similar approach to curiosity in his book, &lt;em&gt;Curious: The Desire to Know and Why Your Future Depends on It.&lt;/em&gt; Now, having read the book I think the title is a bit hyperbolic, but he does make a number of valid points regarding the importance of curiosity in learning and how what is learned leads to ever more curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, both of these books surface a set of ideas that I&amp;rsquo;ve had floating around in my mind for a number of years. The idea that we should focus on one thing is exactly the wrong approach. In the book &lt;em&gt;Freakonomics&lt;/em&gt;, author and economist Steven Levitt told the story of how, when he was being considered for a faculty position, some of those on the committee questioned his program of research.  Typically, an program of research is focused on a single topic area.  This was not the case for Levitt. That is, in his research he was not developing a body of knowledge within a limited field of study but was, instead, researching and writing more broadly. He argued that everything is, in some way, connected and that he, therefore, was well within his rights to explore them.  Bottom line: he as curious and he acted on that curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;curiosity-leads-to-new-discoveries&#34;&gt;Curiosity Leads to New Discoveries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Levitt did was to take an immense curiosity, accumulate knowledge of broad fields and find connections between them.  Levitt exemplified the concepts that both Livio and Leslie described.  Curiosity prompts us to question and to explore.  Those actions, in turn, add to our knowledge base. Our brain, then, takes that information and begins to build connections. In this way new knowledge is created and new understandings are achieved.  Without that broad knowledge base, it is nearly impossible to see connections that lead to know understandings and insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Businesses want to exploit new ideas but create environments that, ultimately, work against that very desire.  Many employers either actively, or out of ignorance, create environments that stifle &amp;ndash; and sometimes actively discourage &amp;ndash; the very thing they claim the want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll write more about that in my next post.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> No, In Fact I Don&#39;t Like Social Media</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/no-in-fact-i-dont-like-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/no-in-fact-i-dont-like-social-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#No, In Fact I Don&amp;rsquo;t Like Social Media&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, the title really says it all: I dont like social media. The reasons, though, need some explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that social interaction and the sharing of ideas is an important part of life and, particularly, of learning. Engaging in thoughtful, thought-provoking conversations allows us to to explore more fully our own thinking, to consider the thoughts of others, and find in the mix a fuller, more well-developed sense of the world around us. For many years  perhaps hundreds  sitting with friends and debating the issues of the day was a common means of passing the time. Conversations no doubt got heated at times, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;and Im sure more than few feelings got hurt. But, at the end of the day, they remained friends and may have developed a deeper appreciation for the knowledge and thoughts each held. And this, I think, is what the vision of social media started out to be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;#No, In Fact I Don&amp;rsquo;t Like Social Media&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, the title really says it all: I dont like social media. The reasons, though, need some explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that social interaction and the sharing of ideas is an important part of life and, particularly, of learning. Engaging in thoughtful, thought-provoking conversations allows us to to explore more fully our own thinking, to consider the thoughts of others, and find in the mix a fuller, more well-developed sense of the world around us. For many years  perhaps hundreds  sitting with friends and debating the issues of the day was a common means of passing the time. Conversations no doubt got heated at times, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;and Im sure more than few feelings got hurt. But, at the end of the day, they remained friends and may have developed a deeper appreciation for the knowledge and thoughts each held. And this, I think, is what the vision of social media started out to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it hasnt really worked out that way. At least not in my view. To be effective, such interaction needs to be local, personal and immediate. The image of a group of old men sitting around the potbelly stove in the general store on a cold, rainy day debating the issues of the day says a lot. They are friends who live and work in the same area and may well have grown up there. They may share many experiences. They may work in the same or closely allied fields. Theres history there that helps to put context to what is said. Joe knows that Sam is going to argue with him just for the sake of argument, regardless of what Sam might really believe. That shared existence and history provides a lens for understanding each other and the interactions between them. This doesnt exist in the world of social media. There is no shared history, no back story to the interactions between participants. There are only the words on the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those guys sitting around that stove also know that they are part of the social fabric of the community and, as such, arent likely to attack each other. The same cant be said for on-line social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media is everywhere. You cant watch TV without seeing the scroller run across the bottom of the screen showing you what others are saying on Twitter about the show. Watch the local news and youll be asked to tell us what you think But, is this even necessary? Does what you think about a new story alter its value? Does the short, often emotional responses hastily written on these kinds of boards add value to the story? Not in my view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is almost an expectation that you participate in Facebook, Instragram, Pinterest, and the host of similar sites. If youre not, people look at you as if youve some kind of pox. The very notion that I am expected to participate is unacceptable to me because the act of participating is seen as granting permission to attack me, to disparage my thoughts simply because they differ from yours. There is no respect for the thoughts of others and, perhaps most distressing is the simple reality that much of what passes as social interaction is little more than the constant parroting of ideas that are not original to the writer and which have not been truly considered for their veracity by the writer. In other words, social media is not social at all, in my view; its just a forum for ill-informed bullies to continue their bullying without fear of reprisal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I avoid social media as much as I can. And that is why I dont permit comments here. While I enjoy engaging in honest, thoughtful conversations, I find that such conversations just dont exist on line. If you dont like what I write, dont read it. That is your choice. And it is my choice not to give others a forum for lambasting me for thinking about things differently than they do.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
