<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General Thoughts on Kevin&#39;s Corner of the Web</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/general-thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General Thoughts on Kevin&#39;s Corner of the Web</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/general-thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Returning to Basics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/returning-to-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/returning-to-basics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;returning-to-basics&#34;&gt;Returning to Basics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title of this blog is iamcuri.us.  That title was chosen to reflect the many and sundry interests that I have and the drive I have to explore new ideas and to learn new things.  While I think some of my posts here have reflected that, others seems to skew in specific directions that seem to narrow the focus on the blog.  Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m wrong.  Maybe the posts that outline my tinkering in websites and self-hosting do reflect my questioning and exploring and learning. Still, I think that it&amp;rsquo;s time I pushed into some new areas a&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;nd revisit in more detail some old areas, too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;returning-to-basics&#34;&gt;Returning to Basics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title of this blog is iamcuri.us.  That title was chosen to reflect the many and sundry interests that I have and the drive I have to explore new ideas and to learn new things.  While I think some of my posts here have reflected that, others seems to skew in specific directions that seem to narrow the focus on the blog.  Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m wrong.  Maybe the posts that outline my tinkering in websites and self-hosting do reflect my questioning and exploring and learning. Still, I think that it&amp;rsquo;s time I pushed into some new areas a&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;nd revisit in more detail some old areas, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;philosopy&#34;&gt;Philosopy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first real introduction to philosophy was through my doctoral program.  In fact, the introduction to the topic was a bit abrupt and jarring.  The very first class in my doctoral program was in the philosophy of science course. To say it was bewildering was an understatement.  The lectures were interesting, though I can&amp;rsquo;t say that I understood a great deal of them.  The readings, likewise, were challenging. Still, I persisted and managed to do fairly well in the course, even while feeling I had no idea what it was all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a couple of years and I became interested in the concepts of critical thinking.  Now, thinking is a core aspect of philosophy so if I was to gain any understanding of critical thinking I realized I would need to get a better handle on philosophy.  In fits and starts I&amp;rsquo;ve been adding to my understanding by reading, somewhat haphazardly, the writings of various philosophers, notably the ancient ones such as Plato, Aristotle, and the like but also some more recent ones such as Kuhn, Popper, and Watts.  But my approach was disjointed and I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like I was building the proper foundation.  What I needed was a structured approach to learning more about philosophy.  But, where to start? What are the best first readings?  How do I layer my learning so that I build on prior learning without jumping into the deep end of the pool and feeling totally lost?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;ve found a way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;physics&#34;&gt;Physics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve expanded my reading on a variety of topics over the last several years, one topic that keeps coming up in various ways is that of physics.  I know nothing of physics, though I do find the articles I&amp;rsquo;ve read on topics related to physics interesting and I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself wanting to know more.  As with philosophy, though, the question was where to begin.  Physics is a huge and confusing field.  Would a &amp;ldquo;dummies&amp;rdquo; book benefit me?  I didn&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, while reading &lt;em&gt;The Structure of Science&lt;/em&gt; by Thomas Kuhn.  Kuhn was a physicist by training who stumbled into the history of science and later into the philosphy of science. That transition actually made sense to me.  But, in reading that essay I was struck by the broad range of topics in which Kuhn seemed to be conversant. Ponder this, of course, I realized that his background in the history of science required him to understand the basics of the broad range of concepts that constitute &amp;ldquo;science&amp;rdquo;. I also realized that his background in physics seemed to provide him a particularly sound starting point for mastering these other topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve set my cap to learning a bit more about physics (In fact, I did this about four years ago but never acted on it.)  How to begin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-path-forward&#34;&gt;A Path Forward&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While searching for some hints on how to begin teaching myself physics, quite by accident I ran across an article by Susan Fleming entitled, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.susanjfowler.com/blog/2016/8/26/from-the-fledgling-physicist-archives-if-susan-can-learn-physics-so-can-you%22&#34;&gt;If Susan Can Learn Physics, So Can You&lt;/a&gt;.  This blog post laid out, step-by-step, a course of study that reflected a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in physics.  Now, I really don&amp;rsquo;t care to get &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; deep into it (or maybe I do), but at least she gave me a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, as they say on TV, &amp;ldquo;But Wait!  There&amp;rsquo;s More!&amp;rdquo;  Ms. Fleming is now Mrs. Rigetti and she has changed her website, but provided follow up post for a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in philosopy entitled, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.susanrigetti.com/philosophy&#34;&gt;So You Want to Learn Philosopy &amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;.  She was the answer to my dreams!  How did it come to be that she was able to do this?  I briefly read her bio and it seems she was a philosphy major who, with no prior experience in physics and little mathematical background, was cajoled by college advisor to take physics as an elective.  I&amp;rsquo;ll let you follow the two links to her sites to get the lowdown on her path to two majors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-road-map&#34;&gt;The Road Map&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, now I have two paths to follow.  How to proceed.  My plan, perhaps foolish as it might be, is to begin with philosophy. I intend to follow, as closely as possible the curriculum she has laid out for that domain.  I figure two years to get through it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, because I&amp;rsquo;m really a glutton for punishment, I&amp;rsquo;ll tackle the physics curriculum.  That&amp;rsquo;s at least another two years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let&amp;rsquo;s be honest about something: I have no intentions of ever using the knowledge gained for anything other than self edification.  I do not aspire to by a &amp;lsquo;Philosopher&amp;rsquo; (though I suspect most everyone becomes one at some point in time) and I certainly do not expect to make a career or even get a job in physics.  But, having the knowledge, being able to understand just a little better some of the topics that seem so esoteric to me, at the moment seems worth the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of an Academic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/he-evolution-of-an-academic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/he-evolution-of-an-academic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-evolution-of-an-academic&#34;&gt;The Evolution of an Academic&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had someone told me on the day of my high school graduation in 1977 that I would one day be an academic, in possession of a doctoral degree and teaching at the university level, I&amp;rsquo;d have warned them that whatever&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; they were smoking was muddling their brain. Yet, here I am, forty years later, in possession of not one, but two master&amp;rsquo;s degrees, and a doctorate, teaching at a university.  How did that happen?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-evolution-of-an-academic&#34;&gt;The Evolution of an Academic&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had someone told me on the day of my high school graduation in 1977 that I would one day be an academic, in possession of a doctoral degree and teaching at the university level, I&amp;rsquo;d have warned them that whatever&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; they were smoking was muddling their brain. Yet, here I am, forty years later, in possession of not one, but two master&amp;rsquo;s degrees, and a doctorate, teaching at a university.  How did that happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-wasnt-planned&#34;&gt;It Wasn&amp;rsquo;t Planned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never planned to go to college.  As a high school student, I hated school.  It wasn&amp;rsquo;t so much that I disliked learning. Rather, it was that I disliked the structure and rigidity of the scholastic environment.  I was, and am, curious (hence the title of this blog). I loved learning about things that caught my interest.  As a teen I became interested in solar power and, to this day, I can tell you that the proper angle for a solar panel is latitude plus or minus 15 degrees, depending on the season. I learned that tidbit of information somewhere around age 17 and it has never left me. And, I&amp;rsquo;ve always read on a variety of topics.  Even as a elementary school student I was interested in topics such as psychology and anthropology, pondering on why cultures were different, for example, and read on those topics&amp;ndash; at least as well as a fifth grader could!  But I hated the imposed structure of learning that schooling provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time I was graduating from high school I was done. No more school for me!  So, I went to work.  Now, it&amp;rsquo;s important to recognize that in the mid-1970&amp;rsquo;s a college education was nice to have but wasn&amp;rsquo;t necessary for most jobs.  Someone could easily get a wide variety of jobs that paid a decent wage, allowing a relatively good middle-class living, without having attended college.  But things were changing.  After a year of working, I realized that the really well-paying jobs required an associate degree.  So, off to the community college I went. I had no idea what I wanted to do. So, like so many others, I chose a business admin major.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After blundering through a few business courses, however, I realized that the topic didn&amp;rsquo;t hold much interest to me so I started digging around.  I learned about this intriguing career called a Physician&amp;rsquo;s Assistant (PA).  I shifted my focus a bit and found a job as an orderly in the local hospital to help me decide if healthcare was appealing to me. I talked to a couple of PAs who, to my dismay, presented a less than rosey picture of the future of the PA. They were wrong, by the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the PA picture was looking rather bleak, I also met and worked with a number of men who were nurses. When I had been working in a small local grocer, the owner&amp;rsquo;s wife was working on her degree in nursing and suggested that I consider that.  I thought she was nuts; nursing was for women.  But, having met and worked with several men in nursing, and having gotten their whole-hearted endorsements of the field as appropriate for men, I thought, &amp;ldquo;why not?&amp;rdquo;  I changed my major and off I went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to say here that in making that choice I found that my grades improved.  Having a clearly defined goal certainly helped me to focus my energies toward my studies.  I took, and passed with good grades, all of the biological studies the community college offered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having already earned the hours for an associates degree, it made little sense to spend another two years getting an AD in nursing, so I chose, instead, to pursue a BSN.  I applied to, and was accepted, into a BSN program.  I can&amp;rsquo;t say it was always a pleasant two years, but at least I had a focus and was successful in my studies.  And by 1983 I was a full-fledged licensed, RN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-next-stagse&#34;&gt;The Next Stagse&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing my degree and passing the licensing exam I went to work in a Coronary Care Unit.  I generally like the work and soon found that I wanted more.  In this case, I thought that I wanted to move into administration.  To that end, I began work on a Masters in Business Administration and by 1992, and two schools later, I had acheived that goal. I went to work as an administrator in home health.  And hated it.  It didn&amp;rsquo;t take me long to realize that my personality didn&amp;rsquo;t suit the world of management well.  Still, I persisted in working in healthcare, returning to my roots as an RN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the realization that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t great management material, there were still areas within management that intrigued me and I found myself drawn to reading and studying those topics. I had begun my studies in the mid-1980s &amp;ndash; just when computers were really beginning to show up in the workplace. They definitely piqued my curiosity and soon I was off playing with computers, learning how to program and how the darn things worked.  This fit into my general curiosity of all things technical.  I loved computers and exploring all the things you could do with them.  I still do, by the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the 1990s I returned to school again, first for a masters in nursing (with the notion of becoming a nurse practitioner) and later as a masters in information systems (to answer my interest in computers). Both of those pursuits were derailed by social and family issues that got in the way of my studies and prevented me from completing.  For the MSN, in particular, a fading interest in becoming an NP was also a factor.  It always saddened me that I never completed the MIS degree (even though I possess now much of the knowledge and skills that the degree would have provided me.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through out this time, I continued to read and study in a variety of topic areas.  I remained an avid reader of both fiction and non-fiction.  It was rare that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have some book at hand, and visits to bookstores were a weekly occurrence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;transition-to-teaching&#34;&gt;Transition to Teaching&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While working at a small hospital, I had the opportunity to take on the role of nurse educator for the facilty. I found not only that I enjoyed the work but that I apparently had a penchant for communicating concepts in a clear and concise manner.  I was a good teacher.  That experience, and the realization that it engendered, led me to explore the possiblity of teaching in an academic setting.  I applied for, and was accepted, as an instructor in an LPN program.  This I did for for nearly 10 years, with a two year interlude in which I taught health science in a high school (that experienced confirmed for me that secondary education was NOT a viable option for me!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed teaching LPN students.  As I continued in that role, I found that my perspective on teaching and learning about nursing was changing.  I also found that I was more introspective. I gave thought to how I taught. I sought out information on how to teach more effectively and efficiently.  My approaches evolved from the &amp;ldquo;sage on the stagse&amp;rdquo; approach that I had grown up with, to a more interactive approach.  And, I became more aware of the value of education beyond simple career training.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t just want to teach students how to do the job, I wanted to teach them how to think.  I had begun to realize that the more knowledge you have, the better able you are to make sense of your life, to make better and more informed decisions.  Limiting yourself to knowledge only within the work domain limits your ability to grow and find value as a person.  I came to realize that I wanted to teach at a higher level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To teach beyond the LPN level, however, requires a masters degree or higher.  So, back to school I went.  Nearing completion of my MSN, I decided that a doctorate would open more doors. Not only did it open more doors for me, the doctorate also opened my eyes and mind to new ways of thinking.  The experience profoundly affected my sense of self and how I view my world.  Through my doctoral work I began to realize just how limited my own worldview had been.  I began to read even more widely and more deeply on a range of subjects.  I began to think about how critical the skills of thinking and reading were to success not only in nursing, but in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common complaint of my students, most of whom are practicing RNs who are being forced back to school for their BSN by their employers, is that they don&amp;rsquo;t see how the BSN helps them to become a better nurse.  I can answer that now.  How can adding more knowledge, regardless of the type of knowledge, not help you be more effective in working with others?  How can knowledge not help you to see connections between ideas and experiences?  How can knowledge of disparate concepts not help you to develop your own ideas more fully?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here I am. A teacher &amp;ndash; an academic. Even, perhaps, a bit of a scholar. This is not where I expected life to take me, but here is where I have found a sense of fulfillment. Mihaly Csikcszentmihaly, in his book &lt;em&gt;Flow: The Psychology of Optimal Experience&lt;/em&gt; describes the sense of oneness one feels when things are as they should be in life.  I think, in becoming an academic, I have found my flow.  I have found my purpose in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boy, am I surprised!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ONE THING</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-one-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-one-thing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-one-thing&#34;&gt;The ONE THING&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love to read and love to learn, so it is no suprise that one of my favorite pastimes is to wander through bookstores. I love perusing the titles, skimming a few pages of those that interest me and maybe marking a few to add to my reading list. It&amp;rsquo;s a habit I developed probably thirty years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the subject areas I generally skim is the business management section. Learning about management styles and techniques is interesting and informative.  Last fall, however, as  I was skimming titles, I had an epihany.  As I skimmed the titles I became aware of just how many titles purported to embue the reader &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;with &amp;ldquo;the one thing&amp;rdquo; that they could do to be the best leader, the best manager, to build the most successful company, and &amp;hellip; well, you get the idea. As I looked further, I found books of similar types in other subject areas.  It seems that everyone one is looking for the ONE THING that gives them an advantagse. The problem was that in skimming the books it quickly became apparent that the &amp;ldquo;one thing&amp;rdquo; differed from book to book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-one-thing&#34;&gt;The ONE THING&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love to read and love to learn, so it is no suprise that one of my favorite pastimes is to wander through bookstores. I love perusing the titles, skimming a few pages of those that interest me and maybe marking a few to add to my reading list. It&amp;rsquo;s a habit I developed probably thirty years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the subject areas I generally skim is the business management section. Learning about management styles and techniques is interesting and informative.  Last fall, however, as  I was skimming titles, I had an epihany.  As I skimmed the titles I became aware of just how many titles purported to embue the reader &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;with &amp;ldquo;the one thing&amp;rdquo; that they could do to be the best leader, the best manager, to build the most successful company, and &amp;hellip; well, you get the idea. As I looked further, I found books of similar types in other subject areas.  It seems that everyone one is looking for the ONE THING that gives them an advantagse. The problem was that in skimming the books it quickly became apparent that the &amp;ldquo;one thing&amp;rdquo; differed from book to book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-could-that-be&#34;&gt;How Could That Be?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I pondered this situation, a couple of explanations came to mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first explanation is that there are many road to the same outcome.  That is, despite the author&amp;rsquo;s assertion that his or her approach was the &amp;ldquo;one best way&amp;rdquo;, perhaps there were other, equally effective ways of acheiving first-rate outcomes. The author simply chose a title that he or she hoped would sell more books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second explanation is that maybe the &amp;ldquo;one best way&amp;rdquo; worked for this manager, in this organization.  Whether or not it would work for a different manager, with a different management style, in a different organizational environment is questionable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A third explanation (yes, I know that &amp;ldquo;a couple&amp;rdquo; means two), and the one that I most agree with, is that all those books are just a bunch of hooey.  There is no one best way that applies to everyone.  The titles, and, indeed the premise on which they are based, are aimed at selling books and nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This last gains some support from psychologist Daniel Kahneman who notes that humans love stories and abhor the unexplained.  So we look for stories to explain why a particular business appears to be successful while another fails.  We look for stories to explain why one person is hugely successful while another, even with similar talents and abilities, fails miserably.  And, it seems, that&amp;rsquo;s what most (if not all) of these books are: stories to explain success or failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;theyre-just-stories&#34;&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re Just Stories&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three problems with these stories.  First, the stories are always rendered in hindsight.  It is much easier to explain success or failure after the fact. Whether or not the success or failure was predicted (or could have been) beforehand is a different story. this suggests that &amp;ldquo;the one thing&amp;rdquo; is not so much a truism as it is an interpretation designed to explain the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, the stories almost invariably omit the factors that don&amp;rsquo;t fit the narrative. That is, a story that explains why TheCompany was so successful omits the myriad blunders and failed attempts that occurred along the way.  Or, if the story is about a person, the story may omit the obvious strokes of luck that occurred as part of that success story. If Bill Gates was 10 years older, or 10 years younger than he is, no one would have heard of him.  His luck was in being at the right place at the right time with the right skillset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third problem is that rarely is an event the result of some single factor. There is no ONE THING.  We humans are a lazy bunch.  We want things presented to us in simple, easily digested bites.  We don&amp;rsquo;t want to hear that the success of one company was based on the interaction of dozens of factors while that of another was based on the interactions of dozens of &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; factors.  The two companies might share some of those factors, but not all of them, yet they were both successful.  And we certainly don&amp;rsquo;t want to hear that changes to any one of those factors might well have doomed the company rather than ensuring its success. That&amp;rsquo;s way too complicated and we don&amp;rsquo;t like complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;so-whats-my-point&#34;&gt;So, What&amp;rsquo;s My Point?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I have two points to make, really. The first is that the world is a complicated place that cannot be easily boiled down to simple rules.  That means that success can come from many factors, or the interaction of many factors, but rarely can be attributed to a single all-encompassing idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second point is that reading these books is interesting, thought-provoking, and even inspirational. But they don&amp;rsquo;t explain anything.  They are simply interesting stories that reflect one person&amp;rsquo;s interpretation of the facts, after the fact, that they invented to explain success or failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read them with a large dose of salt.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Wrong With Asking for a &#34;Highly Satisfied&#34; Rating</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/whats-wrong-with-asking-for-a-highly-satisfied-rating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/whats-wrong-with-asking-for-a-highly-satisfied-rating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;whats-wrong-with-asking-for-a-highly-satisified-rating&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Wrong with Asking for a &amp;ldquo;Highly Satisified&amp;rdquo; Rating?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtually all businesses today are concerned about how the public perceives them.  They recognize &amp;ndash; and rightfully so, in my opinion &amp;ndash; that customers who have a positive experience, who receive great service, or receive quality, tasty foods are more likely to be repeat customers.  They also know that customers who have a poor experience are just as unlikely to return.  Thus, measuring the customer experience by asking the customer to complete a survey of their experience is an important means for getting information on how&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; well the company is doing in meeting the customers&amp;rsquo; needs and expectations.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure all managers understand the value of the survey and the need for accurate feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;whats-wrong-with-asking-for-a-highly-satisified-rating&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Wrong with Asking for a &amp;ldquo;Highly Satisified&amp;rdquo; Rating?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtually all businesses today are concerned about how the public perceives them.  They recognize &amp;ndash; and rightfully so, in my opinion &amp;ndash; that customers who have a positive experience, who receive great service, or receive quality, tasty foods are more likely to be repeat customers.  They also know that customers who have a poor experience are just as unlikely to return.  Thus, measuring the customer experience by asking the customer to complete a survey of their experience is an important means for getting information on how&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; well the company is doing in meeting the customers&amp;rsquo; needs and expectations.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure all managers understand the value of the survey and the need for accurate feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-surveys-are-important&#34;&gt;Why Surveys Are Important&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a competitive marketplace reputation is important.  Reputation is the amalgam of the customer experience. Everything from the taste, temperature, and presentation of the food, to the friendliness of staff, the speed with which the food is delivered, and even the cleanliness of the environment, all play a role in reputation.  In retail businesses such as Wal-Mart or Target, the quality of the food may not be of value, but the abilty to easily navigate the aisles, or to locate a desired product, would be.  The simple fact is that your company may provide the best food in town, but if the service sucks, your reputation will sink you quickly. And, once the reputation is established it&amp;rsquo;s really hard to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customer surveys can provide management with insight into what the customer values and to how well the business is meeting that expectation.  If you want to improve, you pay attention to the feedback customers provide.  But that feedback needs to be accurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-ask&#34;&gt;The &amp;lsquo;Ask&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was immediately struck by the inanity of that message.  I doubt whether McDonalds corporate authorized that message. After all, they are spending money to collect and analyze the data from the survey, and providing incentives for completing it &amp;ndash; regardless of what ratings are applied. To ask for a specific rating invalidates the survey, wasting all the money they&amp;rsquo;ve invested in the process.  That wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make sense from a corporate perspective.  Businesses want and need valid customer feedback, as I said earlier.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming that McDonald&amp;rsquo;s corporate didn&amp;rsquo;t authorize the message, I am left with a couple of other possible explanations and to some degree they may be interrelated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, the management of this particular store does not understand the value of customer feedback.  It could be that the manager either never received or did not pay attention to the training on the value and utility of accurate customer feedback.  Alternately, they may simply have received bad training from the git go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second, it could be that the manager fully understands the value of feedback but also knows that some issues, such as service quality are the result of in-store cultures and, as a result, realizes the challenges faced with changing that culture.  It&amp;rsquo;s easier to ask customers to provide false feedback than to address the issues that could organically lead to improved customer experiences in the store.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A third option is that the management in that store simply doesn&amp;rsquo;t care.  They would rather bribe customers to get high ratings than to actually do the work of improving their service and quality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;undermining-their-own-intentions&#34;&gt;Undermining Their Own Intentions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fourth possibility is that corporate messaging may lead to misunderstanding the goals of the survey, or actually change the purpose of the survey unintentionally.  In my experience, it is pretty common for businesses to say one thing but then take steps that undermine their words.  Because businesses often don&amp;rsquo;t fully think through their actions, they fail to recognize and adjust for the potential unintentional consequences of their actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s assume, for example, that McDonalds is sincere in their desire to improve the quality of food and service in their stores. They initiate the customer feedback system to gain insights into the customer experience and expectations.  Along with this effort, they implement a rewards system that rewards stores for high ratings.  Sounds good, right?  Providing incentives to earn highly satisfied ratings might help improve the experience. Or, it could simply lead to managers asking customers to give high ratings, bribing them to do so. The unintentional effect of providing incentives to managers for their high ratings leads to the managers gaming the system to ensure they get those incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only does the customer experience not improve, but the company no longer has a valid way to determine what that customer experience is.  The data are tainted.  In my view, the results of surveys should not be tied either to incentives or punishment (the other direction some businesses tend to go).  Rather, the surveys should be presented to management for what they are &amp;ndash; opportunities to improve the success of the business through its focus on the customer experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-did-i-do-with-that-survey&#34;&gt;What Did I do With That Survey?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually completed the survey with the specific goal of expressing my displeasure at the &amp;ldquo;bribe&amp;rdquo; that was offered.  Interestingly, even though I did not provide &amp;ldquo;Highly Satisfied&amp;rdquo; responses to my survey, I was given a code for that free item.  So, it appears that a &amp;ldquo;highly satisfied&amp;rdquo; rating was not required for the incentive, but you don&amp;rsquo;t find that out until you&amp;rsquo;ve provided the high ratings.  It seems the company was simply providing an incentive to customers to provide feedback.  The manager decided to leverage that incentive to ensure high ratings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That manager needs retraining &amp;ndash; and not just on on the value of customer feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science Fiction and the Polymath</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/science-fiction-and-the-polymath/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/science-fiction-and-the-polymath/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;science-fiction-and-the-polymath&#34;&gt;Science Fiction and the Polymath&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout my junior high years I was a huge science fiction fan.  One of my favorite authors of the time was  Isaac Asimov.  I was quite surprised to learn that Asimov not only wrote science fiction but had also penned books, short stories, and essays that ranged from religion (Guide to the Bible), chemistry (he was educated as a biochemist), engineering, and the list goes on.  This realization intially confused me.  How &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;could a science fiction writer be so bold as to write on so many different topics? How could he know enough in each of those fields to qualify himself to write books on them?  It would be many years before I encountered the term &amp;ldquo;polymath&amp;rdquo;, but surely Asimov earned the title.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;science-fiction-and-the-polymath&#34;&gt;Science Fiction and the Polymath&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout my junior high years I was a huge science fiction fan.  One of my favorite authors of the time was  Isaac Asimov.  I was quite surprised to learn that Asimov not only wrote science fiction but had also penned books, short stories, and essays that ranged from religion (Guide to the Bible), chemistry (he was educated as a biochemist), engineering, and the list goes on.  This realization intially confused me.  How &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;could a science fiction writer be so bold as to write on so many different topics? How could he know enough in each of those fields to qualify himself to write books on them?  It would be many years before I encountered the term &amp;ldquo;polymath&amp;rdquo;, but surely Asimov earned the title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to a few weeks ago.  I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really given Asimov &amp;ndash; or science fiction &amp;ndash; a whole lot of thought in many years.  I would still occasionally read a sci-fi story or watch a few sci-fi films or TV shows, but for the the most part, I had set aside my interest.  Too many other demands on my time. Then I ran across &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.technologyreview.com/s/531911/isaac-asimov-asks-how-do-people-get-new-ideas/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; article in which Asimov explores how people get new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the points he makes in that article is that new ideas are born by combining old ideas in new ways.  That is, seeing connections between old ideas that others seem to have missed. Implicit in his explanation is that in order for one to create new ideas, one must first be conversant in a range of old ideas.  Logically, the more &amp;lsquo;old&amp;rsquo; knowledge you have, the more likely you are to develop some new idea. After all, the more knowledge you have, the greater are the opportunities for connections to be made between two or more of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That realization also underscores the need for a broad education.  Today the tendency, even at the university level, is to focus on knowledge and skills that translate into a career path. Now, there are a number of issues with that which I won&amp;rsquo;t go into here, but one problem with this perspective of education is highlighted by Asimov&amp;rsquo;s observation.  The more knowledge you have on a broad range of subjects, the more likely you are to make a connection that leads to new ideas and new knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a youngster, it made little sense to me that a writer of science fiction should spend his time in all of these disparate areas.  As an adult and an educator, it makes perfect sense.  Science fiction is a nearly perfect vehicle for exploring and questioning the range of human experience.  By creating &amp;rsquo;new worlds&amp;rsquo; and new civilizations, the sci-fi writer gives him or herself the license to explore ideas.  She is not bound to the current cultural norms; she can create her own.  To do that, though, the writer must first have an understanding of cultures and how they develop.  To develop new worlds, the writer must first develop an appreciation for how those worlds might be different.  To create and convincingly describe new technologies, the writer has to have at least a foundational understanding of the physics, chemistry, and/or engineering involved in those technologies.  To create new languages (as JRR Tolkien did) the writer must have an understanding of languages and linguistics. In short, the science fiction writer must be well-versed in a wide range of knowledge domains. That is, the writer most likely is a polymath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what is a polymath? &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/polymath&#34;&gt; Merriam-Webster&lt;/a&gt; defines a polymath as someone who knows a lot about a lot of different things; someone of encyclopedic knowledge.  From other readings, those whom we consider to be polymaths are highly curious and are constantly exploring new areas of knowledge. They want the knowledge for the sake of knowing, and without any particular purpose.  But I think it&amp;rsquo;s more than that.  I think that a true polymath not only knows a lot about many different things, but is also able to combine that knowledge in the creation of new knowledge. And this is what science fiction writers often do.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me? A Manager? Not So Much</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/me-a-manager-not-so-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/me-a-manager-not-so-much/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;me-a-manager-not-so-much&#34;&gt;Me? A Manager? Not so Much&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past year or so my manager has
been after me to move into a management role.  I managed to avoid doing so until
fairly recently, using my work on my doctorate as an excuse for not really
having the time to take on all the work of learning the role, learning the
courses I would manage and so forth.  Recently, however, I was approached again
and, having all-but completed my degree, really didn&amp;rsquo;t have a good reason for&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;me-a-manager-not-so-much&#34;&gt;Me? A Manager? Not so Much&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past year or so my manager has
been after me to move into a management role.  I managed to avoid doing so until
fairly recently, using my work on my doctorate as an excuse for not really
having the time to take on all the work of learning the role, learning the
courses I would manage and so forth.  Recently, however, I was approached again
and, having all-but completed my degree, really didn&amp;rsquo;t have a good reason for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t get the job.  Exactly why, though, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure. I do know that they had
multiple applicants and no one was chosen.  That&amp;rsquo;s fine.  That experience,
though, got me to really thinking about whether I really wanted to continue to
pursue a management position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-answer-is-no&#34;&gt;The Answer is &amp;ldquo;No&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s pretty common, I think, for people to expect that as you gain experience in
a field that you&amp;rsquo;ll want to move up within that field.  For most people, that
means moving into management.  And, if that&amp;rsquo;s truly where you want to be, that&amp;rsquo;s
a good plan.  But, when people begin to expect you to move up and you don&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ndash;
particularly by choice &amp;ndash; they begin to wonder why not.  Why, they ask, aren&amp;rsquo;t
you interested in growing?  Or, why don&amp;rsquo;t you want to improve yourself?  Some
organizations even set the expectation that you either express a desire to move
&amp;lsquo;up the ladder&amp;rsquo; or move on.  They (wrongfully) equate a lack of desire to &amp;lsquo;move
up&amp;rsquo; with a lack of motivation to do good work.  They are very short-sighted.
Ignorant, even.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the thing in my own case.  I began pursuit of my doctorate not because I
wanted to
become a manager but because I wanted to teach.  It really doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to
get a degree that fully qualifies me to teach and then abandon teaching for
management.  Perhaps as importantly, management is simply not me. I&amp;rsquo;ve done
management.  I have a degree in management.  I&amp;rsquo;m not a good manager. My manager
disagrees and that&amp;rsquo;s okay.  The problem is that he is evaluating my life through
his lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also the simple fact that leadership and management are often seen as
being the same thing. They
are not.  I am a good leader.  I have good ideas, I see ways that things can be
done differently and more effectively, and I am good a communicating those
thoughts.  I look at things through a different lens, which allows me to present
alternative ways of seeing and approaching things.  And, because I am both good
at expressing those thoughts and pretty much unafraid to bring up questions,
others listen to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, just because I am a good leader doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I&amp;rsquo;ll be a good manager.  The
requisite skills are different.  Perhaps more importantly, the constraints on
the two roles are different.  As a manager I am constrained to present the
organization&amp;rsquo;s perspective in a positive light, at least to those under my
management.  As a simple employee, I&amp;rsquo;m free to voice my frustrations and
disagreements with the &amp;lsquo;company view&amp;rsquo;. That can be dangerous, but is less likely
to garner significant backlash than if I did so as a manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;academics-and-management&#34;&gt;Academics and Management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t speak for anyone other than myself, so that heading is a bit misleading.&lt;br&gt;
But, it seems to me that academics go into education for one of three reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, they genuinely enjoy teaching. They enjoy the interaction with
students.
They love to see that &amp;ldquo;ah ha!&amp;rdquo; look in the students&amp;rsquo; faces when the students
connect the
dots and a concept crystallizes for them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second, they are curious (I&amp;rsquo;ll write
more about that later) and academia allows them to satisfy that curiosity and
to share the fruits of their curiosity with others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Third, I know at least
some people who come into education more as an avoidance of or escape from some
unpleasant work experience than for any particular desire to educate.  This
third group may also include people who can simply no longer function in the
workplace due to age or infirmity.  Nurses, for example, may come into teaching
more because they can no longer physically do the work of nursing. There&amp;rsquo;s
nothing wrong with that, though they may not be the most effective educators.  I
do disagree with the old saw that &amp;ldquo;Them what can, do; Them what can&amp;rsquo;t, teach.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s true.  In my experience, teaching is simply an expression
of what drives the individual.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of these reasons points to the need for a position in management.  It&amp;rsquo;s not
about power or authority. It&amp;rsquo;s about sharing with others and exploring one&amp;rsquo;s own
interests. It&amp;rsquo;s not about growing into more &amp;lsquo;responsible&amp;rsquo; positions (whatever
that means), it&amp;rsquo;s about growing in understanding and insight and
accomplishments. I don&amp;rsquo;t see the ability to manage others or to implement the
plans and goals of others as necessarily being growth. Nor do I see stifling my
own perspectives, interests, and curiosity in order to meet some vague corporate
conception of what I should be as a desirable thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, I&amp;rsquo;ve given it thought and I will not be pursuing management anytime in
the foreseeable future.  I want to grow, but as a person and as an intellectual,
not as a minion to those with more titular &amp;lsquo;power&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Curiosity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-power-of-curiosity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-power-of-curiosity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-power-of-curiosity&#34;&gt;The Power of Curiosity&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always been a curious person. I&amp;rsquo;m the kid that took toys apart to see how they worked (and was sometimes able to put them back together again, too!) I was the kid that enjoyed reading the &lt;em&gt;WorldBook Encyclopedia&lt;/em&gt; because, well, just because. Learning about different stuff fascinated me.  Even as a very small child I was curious.  My mother used to tell the story of the time when I was maybe 3 or 4 years old and came in crying because my eyes were filled with sand.  I had apparently held a toy over my head and looked up&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; as the sand fell out because I wanted to see what it looked like from that angle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-power-of-curiosity&#34;&gt;The Power of Curiosity&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always been a curious person. I&amp;rsquo;m the kid that took toys apart to see how they worked (and was sometimes able to put them back together again, too!) I was the kid that enjoyed reading the &lt;em&gt;WorldBook Encyclopedia&lt;/em&gt; because, well, just because. Learning about different stuff fascinated me.  Even as a very small child I was curious.  My mother used to tell the story of the time when I was maybe 3 or 4 years old and came in crying because my eyes were filled with sand.  I had apparently held a toy over my head and looked up&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; as the sand fell out because I wanted to see what it looked like from that angle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that curiosity persists within me today. My wife becomes exasperated with me because I tend to bounce around to different ideas, interests, and activities.  Today I&amp;rsquo;m learning a new programming language, tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;m studying Spanish, then next day I&amp;rsquo;m reading some philosophical treatise.  Or business. Or economics. Or &amp;hellip; Or &amp;hellip; Or. Did I say I like to learn stuff?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most recently I&amp;rsquo;ve read two books that have at least provided some consolation that perhaps my natural inclination toward epistemic meandering is neither uncommon nor bad for me.  Mario Livio, an astrophysicist and author of several books on mathematics and physics, wrote the book &lt;em&gt;Why? What Makes Us Curious.&lt;/em&gt; In it Livio shares with the reader how many well-known figures such as Leonardo Da Vinci, Richard Feynman, and a host of others had wide ranging interests and who often became fascinated by some topic only to drop it once their curiosity had been sated, or the specific question they sought to answer had been answered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ian Leslie, an author and journalist, took a similar approach to curiosity in his book, &lt;em&gt;Curious: The Desire to Know and Why Your Future Depends on It.&lt;/em&gt; Now, having read the book I think the title is a bit hyperbolic, but he does make a number of valid points regarding the importance of curiosity in learning and how what is learned leads to ever more curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, both of these books surface a set of ideas that I&amp;rsquo;ve had floating around in my mind for a number of years. The idea that we should focus on one thing is exactly the wrong approach. In the book &lt;em&gt;Freakonomics&lt;/em&gt;, author and economist Steven Levitt told the story of how, when he was being considered for a faculty position, some of those on the committee questioned his program of research.  Typically, an program of research is focused on a single topic area.  This was not the case for Levitt. That is, in his research he was not developing a body of knowledge within a limited field of study but was, instead, researching and writing more broadly. He argued that everything is, in some way, connected and that he, therefore, was well within his rights to explore them.  Bottom line: he as curious and he acted on that curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;curiosity-leads-to-new-discoveries&#34;&gt;Curiosity Leads to New Discoveries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Levitt did was to take an immense curiosity, accumulate knowledge of broad fields and find connections between them.  Levitt exemplified the concepts that both Livio and Leslie described.  Curiosity prompts us to question and to explore.  Those actions, in turn, add to our knowledge base. Our brain, then, takes that information and begins to build connections. In this way new knowledge is created and new understandings are achieved.  Without that broad knowledge base, it is nearly impossible to see connections that lead to know understandings and insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Businesses want to exploit new ideas but create environments that, ultimately, work against that very desire.  Many employers either actively, or out of ignorance, create environments that stifle &amp;ndash; and sometimes actively discourage &amp;ndash; the very thing they claim the want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll write more about that in my next post.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
