<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Weather on Kevin&#39;s Corner of the Web</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/weather/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Weather on Kevin&#39;s Corner of the Web</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/weather/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Weewx on the Raspberry PI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/weewx-on-the-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/weewx-on-the-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;weewx-on-the-raspberry-pi&#34;&gt;Weewx on the Raspberry Pi&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved gadgets.  When the first Raspberry Pis came out a few years ago, I was pretty confident that eventually, I&amp;rsquo;d get one.  About three years ago I decided I wanted to build a media server and the RPI seemed the perfect tool for the job.  While it works, it didn&amp;rsquo;t do all that I had hoped.  It wasn&amp;rsquo;t the device&amp;rsquo;s fault; the software just didn&amp;rsquo;t quite match up with my particular use case.  So, the device sat idle for a while.  5}&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;weewx-on-the-raspberry-pi&#34;&gt;Weewx on the Raspberry Pi&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved gadgets.  When the first Raspberry Pis came out a few years ago, I was pretty confident that eventually, I&amp;rsquo;d get one.  About three years ago I decided I wanted to build a media server and the RPI seemed the perfect tool for the job.  While it works, it didn&amp;rsquo;t do all that I had hoped.  It wasn&amp;rsquo;t the device&amp;rsquo;s fault; the software just didn&amp;rsquo;t quite match up with my particular use case.  So, the device sat idle for a while.  5}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, though, another use came along in the form of a VPN server for my internal network. For this I used the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;http://softether.org&#34;&gt;SoftEther VPN&lt;/a&gt; software.  If you have need for a VPN server to access your internal network, I strongly recommend this software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way, though, other uses for the little device began to emerge.  One
such use is to provide some of the weather data that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t provide via my
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meteobridge.com/wiki/index.php/Home&#34;&gt;Meteobridge&lt;/a&gt; device as I
outlined in &lt;a href=&#34;../changes-in-my-weather-station&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Meteobridge device could provide almost all of the data I needed to serve the weather website, it cannot generate NOAA-type files in order to feed some of the scripts I run on my website. So, I started looking for alternatives.   In keeping with my motivation for moving to the Meteobridge, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to have to run a Windows machine. Rather,  I wanted another small, low-power device.  the RPI came to mind.  After doing some digging around I discovered &lt;a href=&#34;http://weewx.com&#34;&gt;weewx&lt;/a&gt;, an opensource software that did exactly what I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In truth, the RPI running weewx can do everything that the Meteobridge can do
and a whole lot more.  Had I started a bit earlier, I might have chosen to use
only weewx rather than Meteobridge. I believe that the Meoteobridge license
comes up for renewall in a year or so.  I may chose to drop it in favor of
Weewx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one thing holdimg me back, though, will be the really nice imaging that
Meteobridge provides for webcams.  I do have a webcam that I include on my
website.  Having that really nice, clean banner across the bottom of the image
makes for a very nice looking presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll have to ponder that one a while!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes in my Weather Station</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/changes-in-my-weather-station/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/changes-in-my-weather-station/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;changes-in-my-weather-station&#34;&gt;Changes in my Weather Station&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past 8 years I&amp;rsquo;ve managed a personal weather station consisting of a
Davis Vantagse Pro and a Windows computer running the excellent Weather Display
software.  Last December I decided that the inexpensive computer I was running
the scripts on may well be coming to its end-of-life and went looking for
alternatives. Another goal of this move was to lower my cost of operations.  The
Jetway computer I was running didn&amp;rsquo;t use a lot of power, perhaps 25 W, but if I
could do better, I would. After all, at 25 watts, that&amp;rsquo;s about 219 kW or $26.25
annually.  With the growth of small computers such as the Raspberry Pi, I knew I
could do better. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;changes-in-my-weather-station&#34;&gt;Changes in my Weather Station&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past 8 years I&amp;rsquo;ve managed a personal weather station consisting of a
Davis Vantagse Pro and a Windows computer running the excellent Weather Display
software.  Last December I decided that the inexpensive computer I was running
the scripts on may well be coming to its end-of-life and went looking for
alternatives. Another goal of this move was to lower my cost of operations.  The
Jetway computer I was running didn&amp;rsquo;t use a lot of power, perhaps 25 W, but if I
could do better, I would. After all, at 25 watts, that&amp;rsquo;s about 219 kW or $26.25
annually.  With the growth of small computers such as the Raspberry Pi, I knew I
could do better. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some mucking around, I found Meteobridge.  Meteobridge is software that
gets flashed onto a TP-Link TL-3060Mr (and some other similar devices).  While
not nearly as full-featured as Weather Display,  the Meteobridge software works
well and sends the data to my website without problems.  Best of all, the total
price was about $100 and will use about 0.6 W, that&amp;rsquo;s about 5.256 kW or a
whopping 63 cents per year!  The whole shebang will pay for it self in about 3.5
years.  Sweet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the Meteobridge has a couple of caveats.  One is that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t store data,
so a separate device is needed for that (it does have the ability to save to a
mysql database hosted elsewhere). Nor does it generate the NOAA style reports
that are needed for some of the calculations and webpages that I generate (for
example, the freeze data &amp;ndash; first and last freeze dates for the year, number of
days below freezing, etc). Another caveat is that the updates are available only
for two years, then you have to buy an update license.  Having not had to do
that yet, I don&amp;rsquo;t know the cost.  Perhaps another caveat is that the product is
dependent on the Meteobridge server.  The OS is not actually stored on the
device but is downloaded each time the server reboots. Now, my server has run
for as many as 133 days without a hiccup, so that doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen often. But it
could.  This can be mitigated by including a USB stick on the device so that the
data are saved, together with a copy of software for those eventualities when
the MB server isn&amp;rsquo;t available. Good to know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, for now, I&amp;rsquo;m sticking with the Meteobridge.  Overall, I like it and have
found workarounds to the issues that have cropped up.  One of those is the
Raspberry Pi and weewx.  I&amp;rsquo;ll deal with that in another post.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
