<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>general on Kevin&#39;s corner of the web</title>
    <link>http://bashblog.local/categories/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in general on Kevin&#39;s corner of the web</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 - Kevin Sauls</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://bashblog.local/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Confusing Fiction with Fact</title>
      <link>http://bashblog.local/posts/confusing-fiction-with-fact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bashblog.local/posts/confusing-fiction-with-fact/</guid>
      <description>Confusing Fiction with Fact I swear some people can&amp;rsquo;t keep track of reality.
While browsing Amazon for something to read in the vein of philosophy I ran across a book entitled The da Vinci Fraud: Why the Truth is Stranger than Fiction by Robert M. Price. The book purports to debunk the &amp;ldquo;many misleading claims found in Dan Brown&amp;rsquo;s Da Vinci Code&amp;rdquo; according to one reviewer. That statement and several others made by various reviewers suggest that somehow Brown was intending to provide accurate historical information regarding the Christian Church.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Wife Always Wanted to Marry a Pilot</title>
      <link>http://bashblog.local/posts/my-wife-always-wanted-to-marry-a-pilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bashblog.local/posts/my-wife-always-wanted-to-marry-a-pilot/</guid>
      <description>A Bit of Background I became interested in drones in the spring of 2021. My wife was preparing to retire from her teaching gig and considering a new career in real estate. After 15 years in our relatively small town in the mountains of North Georgia, we were planning a move to a little larger town with fewer challenging hills and more conveniences. We were building a new home in our soon-to-be new town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Think Crypto is Stupid</title>
      <link>http://bashblog.local/posts/why-i-think-crypto-is-stupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bashblog.local/posts/why-i-think-crypto-is-stupid/</guid>
      <description>I recently read an article on Wired about Faruk Ozer, The CEO of Turkey&amp;rsquo;s biggest Cryptocurrency business. That article outlines how tens of thousands of Turkish people were victims of Ozer&amp;rsquo;s theft of their crypto wallets and all of their assets. The thing that stood out to me is how easy it was for him to simply download their accounts onto a thumb drive and be off with their money. In the wake of the crypto crimes of Sam Bankman-Fried (FTX) and ChangpengZhao (Binance) I fail to understand why anyone would trust their financial assets and future to something so easily stolen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Don&#39;t Trust Gmail. Here&#39;s Why</title>
      <link>http://bashblog.local/posts/i-dont-trust-gmail-heres-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bashblog.local/posts/i-dont-trust-gmail-heres-why/</guid>
      <description>I have had an email address with Gmail for probably 20 years. I mean my email address is my name @ Gmail. No numbers, no weird abbreviations, no strange punctuations, just my firstnamelastname @gmail.com How long has it been since that was possible?
Three or four years ago I began receiving emails to my address that were clearly intended for another person with my same name. Their email was literally my email address!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing the Same Thing And ...</title>
      <link>http://bashblog.local/posts/doing-the-same-thing-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bashblog.local/posts/doing-the-same-thing-and/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;ve heard the saying &amp;ldquo;the definition insanity is doing the same thing over and over again and expecting a different result.&amp;rdquo; And I think you&amp;rsquo;ll agree that this &amp;lsquo;definition&amp;rsquo; is commonly true. But, what about those times when you do the same thing each and every time and get a different result? That, my friends, is the definition of randomness. And, it&amp;rsquo;s far more common than you think.
Physicist Leonard Mlodinow, in his book The Drunkard&amp;rsquo;s Walk: How Randomness Rules Our Lives, Psychologist Dan Ariely, in Predictably Irrational: The Hidden Forces That Shape Our Decisions, Psychologist Daniel Kahneman, in Thinking, Fast and Slow, and a variety of others whose names I don&amp;rsquo;t now recall, have all pointed to how often randomness injects itself into our lives without our ever realizing its influence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ONE THING</title>
      <link>http://bashblog.local/posts/the-one-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bashblog.local/posts/the-one-thing/</guid>
      <description>I love to read and love to learn, so it is no suprise that one of my favorite pastimes is to wander through bookstores. I love perusing the titles, skimming a few pages of those that interest me and maybe marking a few to add to my reading list. It&amp;rsquo;s a habit I developed probably thirty years ago.
One of the subject areas I generally skim is the business management section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Wrong With Asking for a &#34;Highly Satisfied&#34; Rating</title>
      <link>http://bashblog.local/posts/whats-wrong-with-asking-for-a-highly-satisfied-rating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bashblog.local/posts/whats-wrong-with-asking-for-a-highly-satisfied-rating/</guid>
      <description>Virtually all businesses today are concerned about how the public perceives them. They recognize &amp;ndash; and rightfully so, in my opinion &amp;ndash; that customers who have a positive experience, who receive great service, or receive quality, tasty foods are more likely to be repeat customers. They also know that customers who have a poor experience are just as unlikely to return. Thus, measuring the customer experience by asking the customer to complete a survey of their experience is an important means for getting information on howwell the company is doing in meeting the customers&#39; needs and expectations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science Fiction and the Polymath</title>
      <link>http://bashblog.local/posts/science-fiction-and-the-polymath/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bashblog.local/posts/science-fiction-and-the-polymath/</guid>
      <description>Throughout my junior high years I was a huge science fiction fan. One of my favorite authors of the time was Isaac Asimov. I was quite surprised to learn that Asimov not only wrote science fiction but had also penned books, short stories, and essays that ranged from religion (Guide to the Bible), chemistry (he was educated as a biochemist), engineering, and the list goes on. This realization intially confused me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me? A Manager? Not So Much</title>
      <link>http://bashblog.local/posts/me-a-manager-not-so-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bashblog.local/posts/me-a-manager-not-so-much/</guid>
      <description>For the past year or so my manager has been after me to move into a management role. I managed to avoid doing so until fairly recently, using my work on my doctorate as an excuse for not really having the time to take on all the work of learning the role, learning the courses I would manage and so forth. Recently, however, I was approached again and, having all-but completed my degree, really didn&amp;rsquo;t have a good reason for</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Curiosity</title>
      <link>http://bashblog.local/posts/the-power-of-curiosity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bashblog.local/posts/the-power-of-curiosity/</guid>
      <description>I have always been a curious person. I&amp;rsquo;m the kid that took toys apart to see how they worked (and was sometimes able to put them back together again, too!) I was the kid that enjoyed reading the WorldBook Encyclopedia because, well, just because. Learning about different stuff fascinated me. Even as a very small child I was curious. My mother used to tell the story of the time when I was maybe 3 or 4 years old and came in crying because my eyes were filled with sand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> No, In Fact I Don&#39;t Like Social Media</title>
      <link>http://bashblog.local/posts/no-in-fact-i-dont-like-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bashblog.local/posts/no-in-fact-i-dont-like-social-media/</guid>
      <description>Well, the title really says it all: I don’t like social media. The reasons, though, need some explanation.
I believe that social interaction and the sharing of ideas is an important part of life and, particularly, of learning. Engaging in thoughtful, thought-provoking conversations allows us to to explore more fully our own thinking, to consider the thoughts of others, and find in the mix a fuller, more well-developed sense of the world around us.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
