<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Websites on Kevin&#39;s Corner of the Web</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/websites/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Websites on Kevin&#39;s Corner of the Web</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/websites/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Updates on Technology Projects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/updates-to-technology-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/updates-to-technology-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;updates-to-technology-projects&#34;&gt;Updates to Technology Projects&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had several technology projects running for a while now and thought it was time for an update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nextcloud-onlyoffice-and-the-like&#34;&gt;Nextcloud, OnlyOffice, and the Like&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in February I set up a Nextcloud server and incorporated OnlyOffice.  The concepts are pretty cool, but I have abandoned both of those projects.  In all honesty, having completed my dissertation, I write so little that requires a word processor that I&amp;rsquo;ve not yet found a need for OnlyOffice. And when I do need such &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;services, I have LibreOffice available on all of my computers.  MS Office is on its way out since I no longer need to power of a word processor for my writing and my licenses are beginning to expire. (I still have a couple of licenses that will be expiring soon.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;updates-to-technology-projects&#34;&gt;Updates to Technology Projects&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had several technology projects running for a while now and thought it was time for an update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nextcloud-onlyoffice-and-the-like&#34;&gt;Nextcloud, OnlyOffice, and the Like&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in February I set up a Nextcloud server and incorporated OnlyOffice.  The concepts are pretty cool, but I have abandoned both of those projects.  In all honesty, having completed my dissertation, I write so little that requires a word processor that I&amp;rsquo;ve not yet found a need for OnlyOffice. And when I do need such &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;services, I have LibreOffice available on all of my computers.  MS Office is on its way out since I no longer need to power of a word processor for my writing and my licenses are beginning to expire. (I still have a couple of licenses that will be expiring soon.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of document storage, I haven&amp;rsquo;t figured out what benefit Nextclod provides me over a simple document storage device such as my linux server.  I can access everything I need via the VPN.  This approach not only helps keep my data more secure by not opening it to the web, but just streamlines the whole process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;jekyll&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another project I started back in the fall was to use Jekyll for my website.  I am quite conversant in database design, management, etc and fully understand the benefits that a database e.g.  Mysql, postresql, etc can provide.  On the other hand, I also know how difficult it is to move your writing to another platform or to simply extract your work in a human-readable way.  The promise of Jekyll and other plaintext platforms is that you can write and store your writing in a human readable format that can easily be moved to different platforms, printed, or otherwise shared with ease. As you may infer from this site, however, I&amp;rsquo;ve moved to Grav, which is a bit more intuitive and easier to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several factors led to that decision.  Probably the most signficant is that creating a new post required too many steps.  Not only did I have to write and store the document in a specific location, I then had to run a script that would recompile the entire site, then upload the entire site to the webserver.  That doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to me. And, to accomplish this required that I either remember the various commands for compiling the site and uploading it, or remember where I put the script that would run the commands for me.  If it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I wrote a post, there was no guarantee that I&amp;rsquo;d remember these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grav provides an option to use the writing tools through the admin page of the website to write, or I can write off-line and simply upload the one file to the server.  No fuss, no muss, and the page is immediately live.  Grav may present a little bigger hit on the server itself as it processes the page, but probably no more so than would be seen if I was using a database driven site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did look at several alternatives, including YellowCMS, and Bludit.  I actually liked Bludit quite a lot and would have chosen it but for the fact that it lacked the ability to simply upload a page written offline.  It stores its page data in a JSON database file which would have required that I either write all my posts within the site, or manually update several JSON files in order to get everything set up correctly.  Not an appealing prospect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;self-hosted-bookmark-site&#34;&gt;Self-Hosted Bookmark Site&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three projects that are rocking along well are the self-hosted bookmark, the RSS reader, and the read-it-later sites that I created.  Both of these run on a Raspberry Pi and work very well. In fact, I use all three relatively routinely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;shaarli&#34;&gt;Shaarli&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After playing with several other scripts (Unmark, SemanticScuttle, and Shaarl, as well as a couple of others that I don&amp;rsquo;t now remember) I settled on Shaarli.  I can&amp;rsquo;t really say why, other than it seems to be the one that best meshed with how I work.  SemanticScuttle is still up and running and I do have bookmarks stored there, but I rarely send anything to it.  For this one, Shaarli wins the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;freshrss&#34;&gt;FreshRSS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I really wrote about an RSS reader earlier but I played with several over the course of several months.  I realize that RSS reader use may be on the decline but I like being able to quickly scan headlines of my favorite sites.  I have to manually mark the entries read and to manually refresh the page to update the headlines, but that&amp;rsquo;s okay.  I find FreshRSS useful and that&amp;rsquo;s what counts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;wallabag&#34;&gt;Wallabag&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was there ever a question that Wallabag would persist? Not for me.  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why I never really cottoned to Pocket.  It does the same thing as Wallabag, but for whatever reason I find Wallabag useful.  I try to keep my reading list there pruned so I don&amp;rsquo;t end up with hundreds of unread pages.  But being able to save not only the bookmark to a page, but also the content of that page is quite useful.  I also like that the advertising is stripped from the pages and they are made more readable and easier to print if  I want to keep a hard-copy of a particular article.  Pocket may have those capacities (I&amp;rsquo;m sure they do) but Wallabag is the service for me and it runs on my servers, keeping things simple and ensuring that they won&amp;rsquo;t suddenly disappear when the company goes under.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There you have it: updates to several of my technology projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nextcloud, OnlyOffice and the Like </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/nextcloud-onlyoffice-and-the-like/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/nextcloud-onlyoffice-and-the-like/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;nextcloud-onlyoffice-and-the-like&#34;&gt;Nextcloud, OnlyOffice, and the Like&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while I get this notion that I need to move my data off of sites
like Dropbox, OneDrive, and so forth. When I do, I start playing around with
self-hosted services such as NextCloud, OwnCloud, and so forth. I&amp;rsquo;m currently in
one of those cycles and have been playing around a good bit with Nextcloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve even coupled it with OnlyOffice so that I can edit documents in the&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;nextcloud-onlyoffice-and-the-like&#34;&gt;Nextcloud, OnlyOffice, and the Like&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while I get this notion that I need to move my data off of sites
like Dropbox, OneDrive, and so forth. When I do, I start playing around with
self-hosted services such as NextCloud, OwnCloud, and so forth. I&amp;rsquo;m currently in
one of those cycles and have been playing around a good bit with Nextcloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve even coupled it with OnlyOffice so that I can edit documents in the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s where I am right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-current-setup&#34;&gt;My Current Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me say upfront that I use OneDrive for most of my document storage. That
came about partly because I use a Microsoft Surface, as well as a Windows laptop
that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a large storage capacity.  Being able to write a document in
Word and send it straight to the cloud service, and then to have that document
available from any computer I work on (I have several) is a great convenience.&lt;br&gt;
Now, it&amp;rsquo;s important, here, to note that I actually have two OneDrive accounts:
The 5 GB free one and a 1 TB paid service through my Office365 account. I
actually use the paid account as my Exchange server more than for file storage,
but that option is available to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my documents, though, are saved to a Linux-based local network file
server. All of my computers are attached to that file server so that I can
access my files from that machine. The OneDrive folder that is synced to to
cloud service actually lives on that local server and is mapped to a drive on my
Windows laptop.  This ensures both that I have local access and have a backup of
those files I consider critical. (They&amp;rsquo;re also backed up locally to another
computer.)  Ensuring that those critical files are backed up off site is
important
and one of the arguments I have against self-hosted &amp;ldquo;cloud services&amp;rdquo;. What is
the point of &amp;ldquo;self-hosting&amp;rdquo; if you&amp;rsquo;re then going to back up those same files to
an online backup service?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the arguments that I frequently hear is that these services allow me to
access my files from anywhere. This is true.  And, if I&amp;rsquo;m not on my own computer
( a rare occurrence), this can be a very important, even critical, feature.  In
my case, though, I have all of my mobile devices set to access my local network
through a VPN. My Ubiquiti Edgerouter X made setting up that VPN almost trivial
and works flawlessly.  So, so long as I have one of my mobile devices, I can
access my internal network and all the files available there.  No need for a
webservice to provide that intermediate layer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;privacy-concerns&#34;&gt;Privacy Concerns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In most of the online discussions surrounding these types of self-hosted
services, the primary reason for moving from a &amp;ldquo;cloud host&amp;rdquo; to a self-hosted
solution is privacy.  After all, we don&amp;rsquo;t want those big, bad companies mining
our files for information.  As I considered this argument, though, I had to come
to the conclusion that it didn&amp;rsquo;t really matter to me.  First of all, there&amp;rsquo;s
really nothing in my files that I feel is so important that it needs to be
secured.  If I have such files (various bills and statements come to mind), I
don&amp;rsquo;t put them in my Dropbox or OneDrive folder.  They live in a local folder.
Most of what I store in the online services are downloaded PDF files or
documents that
I received through my educational experiences.  Those are already generally
publicly available. And, while they might provide some insight into what
interests me, they would hardly provide anything that could be considered
compromising.  So, privacy, at least for me, isn&amp;rsquo;t much of an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, having said that, I do have to concede one area that could become
problematic from the privacy perspective.  I write a lot.  Most of it is for
working out my own thoughts and ideas.  Some of it is part of various projects
that I&amp;rsquo;m working on (stories, or my dissertation, for example). Although not
sensitive in the sense of compromising my privacy, these writings do involve
some levels of
copyright.  Should my online account at one of these big providers be
compromised, my claim to copyright on these documents could be compromised.  The
likelihood of that occurring is minimal, but it is, nonetheless, a risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;security&#34;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security, to me, is part of, but separate from, privacy.  A secure service
protects my privacy, to be sure.  But what I&amp;rsquo;m referring to here is protecting
my work from loss.  If I have files that I truly do not want to lose, I want to
ensure that I&amp;rsquo;ve got them saved in multiple places so that I can be sure that I
don&amp;rsquo;t lose them.  As I mentioned earlier in this post, I have taken measures to
ensure that my important files are backed up to another computer in the event
that my server or hard drive crashes.  But, if my house burns down, I&amp;rsquo;m still
out of luck.  Except that I&amp;rsquo;ve also saved those files to my OneDrive account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue with saving them to an outside vendor, whether it be Dropbox, Box, or
OneDrive, is that those companies might, at any given moment, decide to simply
disappear from the face of the Earth, taking my important files with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternately, they may sell out to another company that doesn&amp;rsquo;t take the same
precautions, or that decides to hold my data hostagse.  Not an enticing scenario
and, hopefully, an unlikely one. But, taking that risk is &amp;hellip;, well, a risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;storage----the-defining-factor&#34;&gt;Storage &amp;ndash; The Defining Factor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the biggest draw for using a service like Nextcloud is available
storage. Unlike the online providers, all of which limit storage, storage for
your self-hosted Nextcloud account is limited only by the available storage on
the server in your home.  Need More? Add another drive, or upgrade to a larger
one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned earlier, my free OneDrive account is limited to
5 GB of storage.  Dropbox is currently limited to 2GB and will cost you $100 for
a 1TB option. Box offers 10 GB storage with their free plan and $120 a year for
a 100GB plan.  Oh, and all these have upload caps, so if you&amp;rsquo;re uploading big
files, you might be out of luck.  As I mentioned earlier, I have Office365
account that provides my Exchange services, as well as 1TB storage.  I&amp;rsquo;m
probably good there (I don&amp;rsquo;t remember if there are upload limits, though I&amp;rsquo;m
sure there are!) But, I&amp;rsquo;ve have that account for about 6 years, during which
time I&amp;rsquo;ve watched the provided services change and generally decline.  I would
not be surprised if, on my next renewal, the amount of available (paid) storage
diminishes. And, that is the risk with all of these services, particularly the
free services: At any time the provide can choose to lower their limits and
suddenly you&amp;rsquo;re locked out of your data, or required to pony up cash to keep the
account usable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, this is not really an issue for me. Part of the reason is because I do
have that
1TB of
paid-for storage, but more importantly because I have several TB of storage on
my local server, without upload limits, and have easy access through my VPN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-where-am-i-truly-at&#34;&gt;So, Where Am I Truly At?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For right now, I&amp;rsquo;m leaving the Nextcloud and OnlyOffice servers running.&lt;br&gt;
Whether I will use them is a question that only time will answer.  I&amp;rsquo;m intrigued
by the ability to do on-line editing much as Office Online and Google Docs can
do.  In fact, I don&amp;rsquo;t really see any differences between the various online
editing services based on my general use cases.  I&amp;rsquo;ll continue to play with them
to see whether they meet any specific need that I might have not yet identified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I wind down my dissertation work my needs for high-powered writing tools
diminishes, as does my need for document storage. In that light, Nextcloud may
provide all the services I need for daily work.  Time will tell that tale.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Learning the Challenges of Jekyll</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/learning-the-challenges-of-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/learning-the-challenges-of-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;learning-the-challenges-of-jekyll&#34;&gt;Learning the Challenges of Jekyll&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So a few days ago I decided to use Jekyll to generate a static website to host
all &amp;ndash; well, most &amp;ndash; of my writing.  Jekyll, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, is a different beast
from most applications used for these purposes.  I&amp;rsquo;ve found several themes that
I really liked, but they all had some sort of quirks that made them less easy to
use.  I&amp;rsquo;m finding, though, that &amp;ldquo;easy to use&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Jekyll&amp;rdquo; probably don&amp;rsquo;t belong
in the same sentence. Each of the themes I&amp;rsquo;ve looked at require slightly
different structures, use categories differently, and just generally appear
rather finicky.  I&amp;rsquo;m sure for people that have played with it for quite a while, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
these quirks are just part of the landscape. For people like me, who haven&amp;rsquo;t
really spent much time with the software, it&amp;rsquo;s a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;learning-the-challenges-of-jekyll&#34;&gt;Learning the Challenges of Jekyll&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So a few days ago I decided to use Jekyll to generate a static website to host
all &amp;ndash; well, most &amp;ndash; of my writing.  Jekyll, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, is a different beast
from most applications used for these purposes.  I&amp;rsquo;ve found several themes that
I really liked, but they all had some sort of quirks that made them less easy to
use.  I&amp;rsquo;m finding, though, that &amp;ldquo;easy to use&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Jekyll&amp;rdquo; probably don&amp;rsquo;t belong
in the same sentence. Each of the themes I&amp;rsquo;ve looked at require slightly
different structures, use categories differently, and just generally appear
rather finicky.  I&amp;rsquo;m sure for people that have played with it for quite a while, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
these quirks are just part of the landscape. For people like me, who haven&amp;rsquo;t
really spent much time with the software, it&amp;rsquo;s a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;making-links-work&#34;&gt;Making Links Work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges that I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered is making links work from the
dynamically created pages..  Say
for
example, I have a a post entitled, &amp;ldquo;Blogging with Jekyll&amp;rdquo;. When I generate the
site, Jekyll automatically creates a link to that post.  BUT, some of the themes
I played with didn&amp;rsquo;t generate the full link. They pointed me to the title, but
had not appended the &amp;lsquo;.html&amp;rsquo; to the page. The result? A blank page.  It took
some Googling around to find out that adding the &amp;lsquo;.html&amp;rsquo; to the end of the
&amp;lsquo;:title&amp;rsquo; part of the permalink fixed the problem.  Simple fix, once I finally
found it, but why was that ever a problem? Why wasn&amp;rsquo;t the &amp;lsquo;.html&amp;rsquo; added by the
theme creator?  Surely his or her copy of the script didn&amp;rsquo;t work without that
extension, either.  Not sure what I mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the _config.yml file I found:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-permalink:&#34; data-lang=&#34;permalink:&#34;&gt;
What is needed is 
 permalink:           /:title.html
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;x
Again, simple fix &amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;navigation-problems&#34;&gt;Navigation Problems.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, I wanted a theme that included navigation so that anyone reading the
site could move around within it.  One of the themes I really like didn&amp;rsquo;t have
navigation.  I probably could have added it but, frankly, didn&amp;rsquo;t want to take
the time to figure it out.  So, I settled for one that included navigation.&lt;br&gt;
Except that the navigation didn&amp;rsquo;t work correctly.  I&amp;rsquo;m not working from my
webserver root, so a baseurl is needed.  The navigation (home, back, and next
buttons) didn&amp;rsquo;t account for a non-root structure.  So, after a bit of plugging
about I finally found the template that contains thenavigation links (they&amp;rsquo;re
not
always in the same
place from one theme to another). Search about until I found the right variables
to include.  Now, I have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{% raw %}{{ site.baseurl }}\{{ page.previous.url }} {% endraw %}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works correctly.  I had to do this for the home button, as well as the
previous and next buttons.  And, I&amp;rsquo;m sure as I continue to work with the site,
I&amp;rsquo;ll find other things like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it stands right now, I&amp;rsquo;ll use this theme.  As I work more with the scripts,
I&amp;rsquo;m beginning to understand them a little better.  But I&amp;rsquo;d much rather spend my
time writing than trying to fix the platform that I&amp;rsquo;m using to host that
writing.  Yes, Wordpress or some such would have been easier, but, as I said in
&lt;a href=&#34;../blogging-with-jekyll&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; I
really
do think that a database driven website is overkill for my needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging with Jekyll</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blogging-with-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blogging-with-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;blogging-with-jekyll&#34;&gt;Blogging with Jekyll&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past nearly 10 years I&amp;rsquo;ve tried numerous times to maintain a
blog.  I enjoy writing and figured it would be a good way not only to practice
the skill, but to share my thoughts with others.  I don&amp;rsquo;t really care whether
anyone reads my work, to be honest; I just want to write. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that, while I don&amp;rsquo;t care so much if I&amp;rsquo;m read, I do want
to be able to keep my files and refer back to them from time to time &amp;ndash;
something
of a journal (which is what the blog was originally conceived to be). That means
that I need the writing in form that is easily saved and retrieved. Another
concern has been that I be able to write from essentially any computer, any
where.  I started, as most folks do, on Blogger, then moved to Wordpress, each
time abandoning my work and the platform, as I moved to another. That&amp;rsquo;s not what
I intended.  Making the process more difficult is that the writing is stored in
a database. This makes retrieval of the raw data difficult, particularly if
you&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten the password, or the database is corrupt, etc.  And, to be
honest, those platforms are simply more complex than my needs. What I needed was
a simple, easy to use platform that allowed me to maintain a file of my work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;blogging-with-jekyll&#34;&gt;Blogging with Jekyll&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past nearly 10 years I&amp;rsquo;ve tried numerous times to maintain a
blog.  I enjoy writing and figured it would be a good way not only to practice
the skill, but to share my thoughts with others.  I don&amp;rsquo;t really care whether
anyone reads my work, to be honest; I just want to write. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that, while I don&amp;rsquo;t care so much if I&amp;rsquo;m read, I do want
to be able to keep my files and refer back to them from time to time &amp;ndash;
something
of a journal (which is what the blog was originally conceived to be). That means
that I need the writing in form that is easily saved and retrieved. Another
concern has been that I be able to write from essentially any computer, any
where.  I started, as most folks do, on Blogger, then moved to Wordpress, each
time abandoning my work and the platform, as I moved to another. That&amp;rsquo;s not what
I intended.  Making the process more difficult is that the writing is stored in
a database. This makes retrieval of the raw data difficult, particularly if
you&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten the password, or the database is corrupt, etc.  And, to be
honest, those platforms are simply more complex than my needs. What I needed was
a simple, easy to use platform that allowed me to maintain a file of my work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flat-files&#34;&gt;Flat files&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year or so ago I became aware of flat-file blogging systems such as
Grav, HTMLy, Pico, and the like.  These were awesome!  They allowed me to write
my entries in plain text or Markup, upload the file to my server and, Viola!  I
had a blog.  These were awesome &amp;ndash; and still are. On the whole, these systems
meet my needs but, being the curious soul that I am, I wondered if there were
other ways.  Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be nice if my setup didn&amp;rsquo;t depend on which PHP version
I was running?  Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be nice if the system didn&amp;rsquo;t break every time
something changed on the back end?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;amazon-web-services&#34;&gt;Amazon Web Services&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I started playing around with Amazon Web
Service (AWS)
S3 storage.  One of the things you can do with S3 is serve static websites.&lt;br&gt;
Cool.  the kicker is, of course, that the site must be static.  Static websites
have some advantagses.  First, any webserver can serve html files, no special
resources or support files needed.  HTML is the reason webservers exist and was
the standard for early websites. Another advantagse is that a static site is not
subject to server-side scripting issues. This means that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter
whether you have the right version of PHP or PERL installed; the site will
simply work.  A third advantagse is that if you ever decide to move your site,
you simply copy the files to another server and you&amp;rsquo;re in business, no fiddling
needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test out the AWS webserver with S3 I started with the website
automatically created by Weewx, a linux based weather software to serve data
from my local personal weather station.  I uploaded the files and, lo and
behold, it worked like a charm!  There was just one problem: To keep the weather
information current, I needed to upload the files every 5 minutes.  This
identified one of the problems with static websites &amp;ndash; all files get uploaded
every time.  I was uploading somewhere around 85 files every 5 minutes.  In a 24
hour period that was about 24,500 files. Each file is a PUT, in AWS terminology,
so I was uploading a boatload of files every day.  S3 allows up to 2,000 puts
per day and charges $ 0.005 per 1000 files after that.  It would end up
costing
me 12 cents a day to maintain that site.  That&amp;rsquo;s not unreasonable &amp;ndash; less than
$4 a month. But not necessarily cheap either.  I can buy full support web servers
for about that price and not worry about upload, storage, DNS (AWS charges for
DNS services, too), or bandwidth costs. But, there are other uses that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t
cost as much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One such use is the blog. Now, Grav, Pico, and such, all require PHP,
which is not available in S3.  So, to do a blog on S3, I needed a static site
generator that would create the site locally, then upload them generated files
to the server.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.staticgen.com&#34;&gt;StaticGen&lt;/a&gt; is a great site that
lists dozens of static site generators, together with basic information about
them and their relative popularity.  Jekyll is, by far, the most popular. Also
pretty popular is Hugo.  I&amp;rsquo;ve played with and like both.  Unlike Jekyll, which is
written in Ruby, and interpreted language, Hugo is written in Go, which is
compiled.  This means, generally, Hugo should be faster for rendering larger
sites.  I can&amp;rsquo;t speak to their speed, given the small number of pages I&amp;rsquo;ve
created so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trying-them-out&#34;&gt;Trying Them Out&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just from early use, I generally like Hugo better.  I can&amp;rsquo;t put my
finger on why, though.  Initially, I found Jekyll a bit confusing to use.  While
the documentation is extensive, it is not terribly user friendly in my view.&lt;br&gt;
Even while I&amp;rsquo;m actually fairly conversant in computerese, I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel that the
documentation got to the point in providing a new user with the resources needed
to really get started.  That&amp;rsquo;s one place where, I think, Hugo was better.  So,
why did I end up using Jekyll?  Mostly because of themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried a dozen or so themes on Hugo.  Some worked; most didn&amp;rsquo;t.  I&amp;rsquo;m
sure it had much to do with user error, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend the time to
troubleshoot.  The themes I tried in Jekyll just worked.  So, I went with
Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-plan&#34;&gt;My Plan&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My plan is try Jekyll for a while and, if I do end up changing, it
shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be be that big of a deal.  I suspect, though I haven&amp;rsquo;t tested it, that
the files should be easily converted between the two; they both use Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
