<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book_reviews on Kevin&#39;s corner of the web</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book_reviews on Kevin&#39;s corner of the web</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 - Kevin Sauls</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Naked by Brian Hoffman</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/book-review-naked/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/book-review-naked/</guid>
      <description>Naked by Brian Hoffman Overview In the acknowledgements, author and scholar Brian Hoffman notes that the idea for this book grew out of his own early experiences in a clothing optional home/community. He noted that as he grew older he became increasingly aware that what was normal in his own life was not nearly so normal for most others, at least in the US. It was, he suggests, that dichotomy between his experiences and the broader social order that led him to explore the history and influences on nudist life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Review - A Curious Mind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/book-review-a-curious-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/book-review-a-curious-mind/</guid>
      <description>A Curious Mind I am, and have always been, a curious person so when I saw this book at the book store I had no choice but to select it.&#xA;Curiosity is a driving force that pushes us to learn more, understand more, and to find or create new things. Curiosity is also the foundation for creativity, which is the premise for Brian Grazer&amp;rsquo;s book, &amp;ldquo;A Curious Mind&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;If the name sound familiar, but you can&amp;rsquo;t quite nail down his name, Brian is the producer of many hit movies, including Splash, Apollo 13, Friday Night Lights, and A Beautiful Life among many others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Noise by Daniel Kahneman</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/noise/</guid>
      <description>Noise By Daniel Kahnemnan Overview We often like to think that decision-makers use sound, rational judgment when making decisions. Using examples from the courtroom, Human Resources, insurance adjusters, and others, Kahneman and team show that, in fact, our judgments are strongly, and unconsciously, affected by a multitude of seemingly irrelevant factors such as the weather, how hunger the decision-maker is, and even whether the local sports team won their game over the prior weekend.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Almanack of Naval Ravikant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/almanack-naval-ravikant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/almanack-naval-ravikant/</guid>
      <description>I had never heard of Naval Ravikant until the book popped up in the search results for personal finance books on Amazon. Or wealth, I don&amp;rsquo;t really remember what that search term was!&#xA;In reality, this book is not about personal finance. Instead, it is a collection of thoughts by Naval Ravikant, a venture capitalist, founder or co-founder of several successful websites including the consumer reviews website Epinions.com, Angelist.com, producthunt.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Richest Man in Babylon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/richest-man-in-babylon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/richest-man-in-babylon/</guid>
      <description>George S. Clason&amp;rsquo;s The Richest Man in Babylon This book is not really a single book but a collection of short pamphlets that Mr. Clason, a businessman in the early 1900&amp;rsquo;s, wrote on the topic of financial success. Using parables set in ancient Babylonia, the pamphlets provide, generally, seven keys for becoming wealthy.&#xA;Although I quickly acknowledge that repetition of concepts aids in internalizing those ideas, I don&amp;rsquo;t usually care for books that include a lot of repetitive materialBecause the book is a collection of pamphlets, the same seven concepts, with the occasional additional idea thrown in, are repeated multiple times throughout the book using different characters and settings to convey the seven principles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ksauls/hugo/book_reviews/almanack-of-naval-ravikant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt; ALMANACK OF NAVAL RAVIKANT tags: - 📚Book - review title: ALMANACK OF NAVAL RAVIKANT author: - Eric Jorgenson publisher: Harper Business publish: 2021 total: 0 isbn: 9354893899 9789354893896 cover: http://books.google.com/books/content?id=0jxbzwEACAAJ&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;img=1&amp;amp;zoom=1&amp;amp;source=gbs_api status: read created: - 2024-03-09 13:20:49 updated: 2024-03-09 13:20:49CopyALMANACK OF NAVAL RAVIKANT&#xA;[]&#xA;I had never heard of Naval Ravikant until the book popped up in the search results for personal finance books on Amazon. Or wealth, I don&#39;t really remember what that search term was!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
